/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374e520c817f0398fba9c0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-YouTube-channel-for-an-SSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Nanda Vanam, 10+ years as a youtuberAnswered 5 years agoWhich is the best YouTube channel for an SSC preparation? Nanda Vanam The best channel for SSC CGL in youtube is SSC CGL PREPARATION channel. all the syllabus for ssc cgl i.e General Intelligence & Reasoning : It would include questions of both verbal and non-verbal type. This component may include questions on analogies, similarities and differences, space visualization, spatial orientation, problem solving, analysis, judgement, decision making, visual memory, discrimination, observation, relationship concepts, arithmetical reasoning and figural classification, arithmetic number series, non-verbal series.Coding and decoding, statement conclusion, syllogistic reasoning etc. The topics are, Semantic Analogy, Symbolic/Number Analogy, Figural Analogy, Semantic Classification, Symbolic/Number Classification, Figural Classification, Semantic Series, Number Seri Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:14:26.133Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best YouTube channel for an SSC preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374e520c817f0398fba9c2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-books-for-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "It is difficult to label a test series as the “ best one “ as far as any competitive exam is concerned simply because each one has its own merits and demerits . Having enrolled myself in 3 test series during my preparation for SSC CGL 2017 , i would like to share my reviews . Since this was my first attempt so , i was also in a dilemma as to which test series to join. Hence , I enrolled for both Gradeup and Testbook for prelims and Ssctube for mains . I have noted down the pros and cons of the aforesaid test series : Gradeup : Pros : The user interface was compact and more or less similar to the original CGL examination .There were significant number of test takers . This helped in assessing my performance on a larger scale .The analysis of answers was good .The solutions had minimum number of Continue Reading It is difficult to label a test series as the “ best one “ as far as any competitive exam is concerned simply because each one has its own merits and demerits . Having enrolled myself in 3 test series during my preparation for SSC CGL 2017 , i would like to share my reviews . Since this was my first attempt so , i was also in a dilemma as to which test series to join. Hence , I enrolled for both Gradeup and Testbook for prelims and Ssctube for mains . I have noted down the pros and cons of the aforesaid test series : Gradeup : Pros : The user interface was compact and more or less similar to the original CGL examination .There were significant number of test takers . This helped in assessing my performance on a larger scale .The analysis of answers was good .The solutions had minimum number of Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:14:26.306Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best books for SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374e5a0c817f0398fba9c5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-start-learning-math-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "I'll try my best not to add just another answer in already existing “ocean” of answers here on quora. I'll try to be as practical as possible. I'll explain a four pillar strategy but before doing that, let me ask one thing. Do you think that maths is too tough for you or you are weak at it since school or you simply hate maths? If your answer is affirmative for any of the above questions then my dear friend, you have two options. Either switch to some other exam or inculcate a \"never give up\" attitude. Only you can help yourself in such case. Even if I end up explaining a perfect strategy here, it won't work until you bring your lazy ass on study table and start grinding. It's totally upto you if you want to just read this answer and forget about it (which you might have already done for many Continue Reading I'll try my best not to add just another answer in already existing “ocean” of answers here on quora. I'll try to be as practical as possible. I'll explain a four pillar strategy but before doing that, let me ask one thing. Do you think that maths is too tough for you or you are weak at it since school or you simply hate maths? If your answer is affirmative for any of the above questions then my dear friend, you have two options. Either switch to some other exam or inculcate a \"never give up\" attitude. Only you can help yourself in such case. Even if I end up explaining a perfect strategy here, it won't work until you bring your lazy ass on study table and start grinding. It's totally upto you if you want to just read this answer and forget about it (which you might have already done for many Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:14:34.575Z"),
    "question" : "How can I start learning math for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374e890c817f0398fbaa8e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Exam-in-3-months?-",
    "answer" : "Ishwar Jarewal Well, I have done this. So, I think i will be suitable to answer this question. My Score. Tier 1 = 171Tier 2 = Maths 171, English 183.25Tier 3 = 61Total = 586.25I started my preparation just after finishing my college i.e in June and prelims was in august. So, effectively i had 2.5–3 months, yes i would say i had made my plan in college itself ( Because, months of april and may, i spent in searching strategies, doing vocab in bits and pieces, and making a solid plan). Before coming home, I knew exactly what I need to do. Before telling my strategy it's always better to understand where i stood ( in terms of my knowledge about core subjects like English, maths etc. ). So, in terms of knowledge base, I would say, I had an Okayish maths (( that doesn't mean i knew tips and tricks etc., Tbh i cou Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:15:21.775Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for the SSC CGL Exam in 3 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374e9b0c817f0398fbaa98"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Before asking for strategy first ask a few questions with yourself:- Are you ready to make commitment with yourself that the strategy you follow, you will stick to it? Do you have courage and belief in yourself that you will easily crack it? Are you ready to keep yourself from distractions and work hard with consistency and perseverance? If yes, then follow this step wise. First go through all the posts which are under ssc cgl, check their work profile and all others things and target the post you want. Read the syllabus of each topic and go through some previous year papers to get aware with the examination pattern and type of questions asked. Sort out the best study material for each subject and start learning.the exam is conducted on 4 tiers but primarily you have to focus on tier 1 and tier 2 Continue Reading Before asking for strategy first ask a few questions with yourself:- Are you ready to make commitment with yourself that the strategy you follow, you will stick to it? Do you have courage and belief in yourself that you will easily crack it? Are you ready to keep yourself from distractions and work hard with consistency and perseverance? If yes, then follow this step wise. First go through all the posts which are under ssc cgl, check their work profile and all others things and target the post you want. Read the syllabus of each topic and go through some previous year papers to get aware with the examination pattern and type of questions asked. Sort out the best study material for each subject and start learning.the exam is conducted on 4 tiers but primarily you have to focus on tier 1 and tier 2 Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:15:39.584Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for the SSC CGL exam 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374eab0c817f0398fbab4a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-English-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Reading newspaper especially The Hindu will inadvertently help you to achieve your ends. Actually when we begin reading newspaper it is an arduous job to complete and comprehend. Thus almost everyone of us will decide to give up on reading. But as they say “IT TAKES ATLEAST 21 DAYs OF REGULAR & CONSISTENT EFFORT TO CONVERT AN ACTION INTO A HABIT AND ULTIMATELY INTO YOUR HOBBY” …Just try to convert it into a habit and after reading for these much days you will definitely see a difference in your approach of tackling reading comprehensions (RCs) Idioms & One word substitution Synonyms/ antonyms And if one is doing ones job with utmost sincerity (like googling unfamiliar words, trying to decode editorials i.e getting its central theme, noticing jargons and tricky idioms, tracking necessary phrasa Continue Reading Reading newspaper especially The Hindu will inadvertently help you to achieve your ends. Actually when we begin reading newspaper it is an arduous job to complete and comprehend. Thus almost everyone of us will decide to give up on reading. But as they say “IT TAKES ATLEAST 21 DAYs OF REGULAR & CONSISTENT EFFORT TO CONVERT AN ACTION INTO A HABIT AND ULTIMATELY INTO YOUR HOBBY” …Just try to convert it into a habit and after reading for these much days you will definitely see a difference in your approach of tackling reading comprehensions (RCs) Idioms & One word substitution Synonyms/ antonyms And if one is doing ones job with utmost sincerity (like googling unfamiliar words, trying to decode editorials i.e getting its central theme, noticing jargons and tricky idioms, tracking necessary phrasa Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:15:55.646Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare English for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374ebd0c817f0398fbab5a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-general-awareness-part?-",
    "answer" : "I started preparing for SSC-CGL 2017 in april'17. I was good with number so I had to spend lesser time with maths and reasoning. But I knew for me it's hard to score in GK and English, so I focused on maths and reasoning. Maths and reasoning :- I practiced lot of previous year paper (almost all papers from 2006–2016) and 25–30 mock test on top of it. Practicing helps a lot with maths and reasoning, you see all the possible types of questions and that widen your view of approach. In the real exam there was hardly anything new for me. At the end I scored 98 in maths and reasoning in tier 1. GK and English :- I knew that I am not good in English and GK so I spent my topics which can fetch me maximum marks. Like in GK I avoided current affairs and focused only on static GK, that too on import top Continue Reading I started preparing for SSC-CGL 2017 in april'17. I was good with number so I had to spend lesser time with maths and reasoning. But I knew for me it's hard to score in GK and English, so I focused on maths and reasoning. Maths and reasoning :- I practiced lot of previous year paper (almost all papers from 2006–2016) and 25–30 mock test on top of it. Practicing helps a lot with maths and reasoning, you see all the possible types of questions and that widen your view of approach. In the real exam there was hardly anything new for me. At the end I scored 98 in maths and reasoning in tier 1. GK and English :- I knew that I am not good in English and GK so I spent my topics which can fetch me maximum marks. Like in GK I avoided current affairs and focused only on static GK, that too on import top Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:16:13.485Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the SSC CGL general awareness part? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374ecf0c817f0398fbab60"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-life-like-after-clearing-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Ritesh Kumar Writing this anonymously because too many of my colleagues are here, on Quora. And we all follow each other. It's one of those stupid things. BACKGROUND ABOUT ME:- • I am currently 29 years old. • I cleared SSC CGL 2016 with a rank in top 150. General Category. • I got the post and the place of posting that I wanted. Examiner(Custom's inspector) in an “eastern” port of the country. Let's just say it's pretty “joyful” here 😉 • It's been almost 9 months since I am working as an Examiner. • I am a B.Tech graduate. But I was teaching in schools since my graduation. After a while I started preparing for CGL. My first attempt was in 2013. I failed. Also failed in 2014 & 2015. I have graduated in 2012. • Since 2012, I never studied seriously till 2015. Then something snapped & I went into hyperdrive. R Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:16:31.253Z"),
    "question" : "What is life like after clearing SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374ee00c817f0398fbab6e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-institute-for-SSC-CGL-preparation-in-New-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "No institute is best for CGL coaching as everybody has its own parameters to decide. And also for the reason that the suitability of a coaching institute differs from person to person. Some of the aspirants want great faculty only, some want good infrastructure as well, some other want good study material being provided etc etc. I personally feel that the general batches of brand names like Paramount, KD campus, Career launcher etc are useless fr a strong preparation for CGL. The reason fr the same is that there is no regularity and continuity in the course. They switch subjects in between without completing the on going topics or subjects. Second major reason is that the faculty for general batch in such brand coaching centres are told to cmplete the syllabus within a fix slot of time anyh Continue Reading No institute is best for CGL coaching as everybody has its own parameters to decide. And also for the reason that the suitability of a coaching institute differs from person to person. Some of the aspirants want great faculty only, some want good infrastructure as well, some other want good study material being provided etc etc. I personally feel that the general batches of brand names like Paramount, KD campus, Career launcher etc are useless fr a strong preparation for CGL. The reason fr the same is that there is no regularity and continuity in the course. They switch subjects in between without completing the on going topics or subjects. Second major reason is that the faculty for general batch in such brand coaching centres are told to cmplete the syllabus within a fix slot of time anyh Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:16:48.562Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching institute for SSC CGL preparation in New Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374ef30c817f0398fbac27"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "Testbook The SSC CHSL can be a tough nut to crack. The first step to crack the SSC CHSL is understanding and internalizing the following: The selection processExam pattern, syllabus, and marking scheme for each stage of the selection processKnowing the approximate category, sectional and overall cutoffs for each examImportant TopicsLet’s start with the selection process, exam pattern and marking scheme. It involves the following stages: Tier 1 - online objective test (100 MCQs | 200 Marks | 60 min) - 25 questions each from General intelligence, English Language, Quantitative Aptitude, and General Awareness.Note: There is negative marking. 0.5 marks will be deducted for every wrong answer.Tier 2 - Descriptive paper based test. (100 Marks including an essay and application/ letter writing)Tier 3 - skiContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:17:07.807Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for the SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f070c817f0398fbac2d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-get-the-first-rank-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "My Score. Tier 1 = 171Tier 2 = Maths 171, English 183.25Tier 3 = 61Total = 586.25I started my preparation just after finishing my college i.e in June and prelims was in august. So, effectively i had 2.5–3 months, yes i would say i had made my plan in college itself ( Because, months of april and may, i spent in searching strategies, doing vocab in bits and pieces, and making a solid plan). Before coming home, I knew exactly what I need to do. Before telling my strategy it's always better to understand where i stood ( in terms of my knowledge about core subjects like English, maths etc. ). So, in terms of knowledge base, I would say, I had an Okayish maths (( that doesn't mean i knew tips and tricks etc., Tbh i could have done an arithmetic question(needs to be done in 1 min. ) in 2–3 minutes Continue Reading My Score. Tier 1 = 171Tier 2 = Maths 171, English 183.25Tier 3 = 61Total = 586.25I started my preparation just after finishing my college i.e in June and prelims was in august. So, effectively i had 2.5–3 months, yes i would say i had made my plan in college itself ( Because, months of april and may, i spent in searching strategies, doing vocab in bits and pieces, and making a solid plan). Before coming home, I knew exactly what I need to do. Before telling my strategy it's always better to understand where i stood ( in terms of my knowledge about core subjects like English, maths etc. ). So, in terms of knowledge base, I would say, I had an Okayish maths (( that doesn't mean i knew tips and tricks etc., Tbh i could have done an arithmetic question(needs to be done in 1 min. ) in 2–3 minutes Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:17:27.471Z"),
    "question" : "How can I get the first rank in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f2b0c817f0398fbacf4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-clear-SSC-CGL-in-the-first-attempt?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I clear SSC CGL in the first attempt?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:18:03.655Z"),
    "question" : "How can I clear SSC CGL in the first attempt? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f3d0c817f0398fbacfc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-clear-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Gaurav Lekhi, 159.25 in SSC CGL 2016 Paper 2Answered 3 years ago · Author has 69 answers and 221.3K answer viewsHow do I clear SSC CGL? Gaurav Lekhi I appeared for SSC CGL 2016 and qualified Tier-1 and Tier-2. As of now I have appeared for Tier-3 (descriptive) exam. My Tier-1 score was 141.5/200 and Tier-2 score was 301.75/400. In my view, the single most important subject for CGL is English, since out of the total(700) 50% (50+200+100) marks are alloted to English. I would recommend you to keep the following points in mind. I won't recommend you to follow a strategy given by anyone since what worked for somebody, may not work for you, as his and your strengths may differ. Tier-1: As of 2016 Tier-1 will have 100 questions and 75 minutes. If you are going to start from scratch I believe that it will take you about 3 months to prepare for Tier-1, if you deidcate about 6 hours a day. During this phase you should understand that English and  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:18:21.988Z"),
    "question" : "How do I clear SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f660c817f0398fbadc0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-SSC-CGL-2019?-",
    "answer" : "Dhiraj Sharma My request section has been flooded with this question: “How do I prepare for CGL 2019?” Now-a-days I see many government jobs aspirants filling all kinds of application forms whichever gets notified. This clearly indicates that they have no idea about where they are heading to. This reminds me of a saying “Journey on two boats will not lead you anywhere, whereas consistent journey on one would definitely lead you the destination”. I strongly believe in these two quotes that have changed the way I perceive things: Success is a state of mind. If you want success, start thinking of yourself as a success.Control your mind, and see yourself control the things around you.Coming to the question: “How do I prepare for CGL 2019 exam?” Step 1: Follow Quote 1. Start believing in yourself and try to fig Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:19:02.670Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for SSC CGL 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f8c0c817f0398fbadcf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-good-apps-for-SSC-CGL-preprations?-",
    "answer" : "K.k Upadhayay SSC CGL (Staff Selection Commission Combined Graduate Exam) is a national level exam held each year for recruiting graduate candidates for various posts in central government’s ministries and departments. The exam is conducted by Staff Selection Commission (SSC) which works as an attached office of Department of Personnel and training, under government of India. Few changes were introduced in SSC CGL last year. As per the new exam pattern, the entire examination process has been shifted to online mode from the previous pen and paper mode and the number of questions and time allotted for Tier 1 exam has also been reduced to 60 minutes. Websites for SSC CGL Studying from online sources has its own benefits and advantages but at the same time it is quite confusing to pick up the best sources out Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:19:40.204Z"),
    "question" : "What are good apps for SSC CGL preprations? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374f9d0c817f0398fbae85"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-SSC-CGL-2018-be-conducted?-",
    "answer" : "Mukku Jodha I have explained in detail in My Original Post on Recognising the Opportunity in Exam Cancellation and Delays that why I think exam delays are an opportunity. Excerpts from my original post: Recognising the Opportunity in Exam Cancellation and Delays by Mukku Jodha on SSC-CGLE BABA I strongly believe students preparing for exams conducted by SSC should not involve in random crap like (I guess below questions are trending on top among students preparing for 2018 and 2019 CGLE ): When will exam be conducted?When will CET be introduced? If introduced, what will be the toughness level?Those who know it can never speak in open. These are highly confidential decision. Further, those who are answering, they do not have an iota of an idea. No one here knows the right answer. Everyone here can only pr Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:19:57.901Z"),
    "question" : "When will SSC CGL 2018 be conducted? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374fb10c817f0398fbae93"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-success-story-of-cracking-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Dhiraj Sharma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:20:17.849Z"),
    "question" : "What is your success story of cracking the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374fc50c817f0398fbae9b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-online-coaching-hub-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "As an SSC CGL aspirant myself i have researched numerous amount youtube coaching channels and other online classes such as testbook, unacademy etc. So i will be able to anwer your question. 1. For quantitative apititude just close your eyes and subscribe to “e1 coaching classes” and “ abhinay maths” these are the best online classes for quants. The explanation is brilliant and you will understand the concepts very well. For books you can refer rakesh yadav and abhinay 2. For reasoning you can practice from previous year papers. Its not much a issue because reasoning concepts are very easy to understand and just needs good practice. If you still want to learn it then search for “barkha agarwal reasoning” on youtube and you will get the whole playlist. She also teaches on unacademy so if you ha Continue Reading As an SSC CGL aspirant myself i have researched numerous amount youtube coaching channels and other online classes such as testbook, unacademy etc. So i will be able to anwer your question. 1. For quantitative apititude just close your eyes and subscribe to “e1 coaching classes” and “ abhinay maths” these are the best online classes for quants. The explanation is brilliant and you will understand the concepts very well. For books you can refer rakesh yadav and abhinay 2. For reasoning you can practice from previous year papers. Its not much a issue because reasoning concepts are very easy to understand and just needs good practice. If you still want to learn it then search for “barkha agarwal reasoning” on youtube and you will get the whole playlist. She also teaches on unacademy so if you ha Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:20:37.651Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best online coaching hub for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374fda0c817f0398fbaf53"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-points-to-keep-in-mind-while-preparing-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Saurabh Pathak Before starting preparation i would suggest you to prepare your mind for the exam. This exam is time consuming and you have to prepare yourself for atleast 2 attempts with full preparation. First go through the question paper of cgl 2019 tier1 and 2018 tier2. This will give you an idea what is important from exam point of view and what is not.Start by maths and english and side by side give 1- 1.5 hrs to gs daily.Complete the basics of maths first either by coatching or by class notes of Rakesh yadav. Then solve Rakesh yadav 7300 thoroughly.For english use Neetu singh because that is more ssc centric book. Complete that book thoroughly atleast 2 times.For reasoning just solve question papers of 2019 & 18. If you feel difficulty in any topic then refer book or lecture for that particular topContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:20:58.109Z"),
    "question" : "What are the points to keep in mind while preparing for the SSC CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60374ffb0c817f0398fbaf63"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-site-for-the-SSC-CGL-online-mock-test?-",
    "answer" : "Apart from all the great people here, who are instead of writing an answer, are marketing their websites, well I am one of those students who is actually preparing for SSC exam and have had familiarity with some test series. So let me present my unbiased views. Firstly those test series which one should AVOID at all cost: Wi-Fi STUDY: This is a new entrant in this test series market. I bought this one. The GK portion is wayward→ Has no relation watsoever with SSC. Some questions have wrong solutions. 2ndly their analysis is very crude. Wrong calculation of Percentile score.After the test, the analysis window takes forever to load. Trust me I have a lighting fast broadband connection, yet navigating their analysis page takes very very long time. Verdict: Avoid at all cost.Cracku.in: Very goodContinue Reading Apart from all the great people here, who are instead of writing an answer, are marketing their websites, well I am one of those students who is actually preparing for SSC exam and have had familiarity with some test series. So let me present my unbiased views. Firstly those test series which one should AVOID at all cost: Wi-Fi STUDY: This is a new entrant in this test series market. I bought this one. The GK portion is wayward→ Has no relation watsoever with SSC. Some questions have wrong solutions. 2ndly their analysis is very crude. Wrong calculation of Percentile score.After the test, the analysis window takes forever to load. Trust me I have a lighting fast broadband connection, yet navigating their analysis page takes very very long time. Verdict: Avoid at all cost.Cracku.in: Very goodContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:21:31.975Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best site for the SSC CGL online mock test? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037500e0c817f0398fbaf75"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-and-effective-way-for-preparing-the-SSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Swati Dwivedi Hello.. I am also a ssc aspirant. So i share my personal experience for the preparation. I hope my answer will help you. Today preparation for Competitive exam not an easy task but with our strong willpower we can fight and try to win the REVOLUTION. For the preparation you have to be well familier with syllabus. Start your preparation with firm determination without thinking about anything else. I suggest you some books and method for preparing for the exam. For maths Rakesh yadav and previous year are sufficient. First clear all the basic concept especially of Advance section. Complete one book two to three times well and clear all the doubts and concept. Then for english I use Nitu singh (vol.1st and vol.2nd), M.B., and mirror for common error. Generally we face problem in vocab section. Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:21:50.035Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best and effective way for preparing the SSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750250c817f0398fbb02c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-institute-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Sakshi Jain When it comes to preparing for SSC-CGL and other entrance exams, T.I.M.E. is a well established brand of its own. Having joined Time, RDC for the same reason, i can vouche for it. ‌The Director of Time RDC, Mr. Ritesh Jain, is himself one of the faculty members and is one of the best teachers I ever came across. His teaching without paper and pen methods are unparalleled. Apart from that, he is very approachable and dedicated towards his students. Being a leading career counselor, he has a vast knowledge base in the domain and provides guidance and counseling at every step, about the various entrance exams to fill and how to ace them. ‌The entrance exams are not only about being thourough with the concept but also solving the question in due time. The time study material and test series take Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:22:13.689Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best institute for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037503b0c817f0398fbb032"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-books-can-useful-for-SSC-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Nikhil Dudhawat Following is the book list which i would recommend for SSC CGL preparation SSC CGL Books – Tier I 2018 Exam SSC CGL Books for Reasoning: Lucent’s Reasoning bookVerbal and Nonverbal Reasoning by R S AggarwalAnalytical Reasoning by M K PandeySectional Tests for Reasoning on OliveboardSSC CGL Books for Quantitative Aptitude: Quantitative Aptitude for Competitive exams by R.S. AgarwalFast Track Objective Arithmetic by Rajesh VermaSSC Mathematics by Kiran PublicationSectional Tests for Quantitative Aptitude on OliveboardSSC CGL Books for General Awareness: NCERT 6th to 10th StdLucent’s GKManorama year book (current year 2017-18)Sectional Tests for General Awareness on OliveboardSSC CGL Books for English: Word Power Made Easy by Norman LewisObjective General English by SP Bhakshi (Arihant)Corrective EContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:22:35.484Z"),
    "question" : "What books can useful for SSC exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037504f0c817f0398fbb0ee"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-start-preparing-for-SSC-CGL-2018-as-I-have-almost-1-year-to-prepare?-",
    "answer" : "Abhishek Patil SSC CGL is one of the most sought-after Government exams. Every year, lakhs of candidates apply for the SSC CGL Examination and only a few get selected among them and land their dream jobs. One of the reasons for candidates not making it to the final merit list is lack of preparation or lack of preparation strategy. Therefore, in the following article, we are providing a comprehensive preparation strategy for the SSC CGL Tier-1 Examination: What to study? Before you start solving questions, it is important to know what to prepare. On a clean sheet, make a list of all the topics you need to prepare for SSC CGL Tier-1 Exam. Tier-1 includes 4 sections, i.e., Quantitative Aptitude, General Intelligence Reasoning, English Language and General Awareness. Make a timetable and stick to it. Divide all  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:22:55.499Z"),
    "question" : "How should I start preparing for SSC CGL 2018 as I have almost 1 year to prepare? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750650c817f0398fbb0ff"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-SSC-CGL-2018-exam-be-postponed?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Will the SSC CGL 2018 exam be postponed?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:23:17.885Z"),
    "question" : "Will the SSC CGL 2018 exam be postponed? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037507c0c817f0398fbb109"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-post-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Best post varies from person to person , let me decode it :- If you are a UPSC aspirant giving SSC CGL as a backup then best post :Assistant Section Officer in Central Secretariat Service : All time Delhi based job. High salary as well. Desk job.Auditor in CAG : Grade pay is 2400 but postings are in big (capital) cities with less work load.Divisional accountant in CAG : No hectic work schedule. You are your own boss.Tax assistant in CBDT : 2400 grade pay post but peaceful job with good promotion opportunities.If you want foreign postings :Assistant Section Officer in Ministry of External Affairs : The concept of “ 3 years India , 3 years Abroad “ has lured aspirants to this post .Cypher in Ministry of External Affairs : 3 Years India , 6 years Abroad . Hectic work Schedule.If you love traveContinue Reading Best post varies from person to person , let me decode it :- If you are a UPSC aspirant giving SSC CGL as a backup then best post :Assistant Section Officer in Central Secretariat Service : All time Delhi based job. High salary as well. Desk job.Auditor in CAG : Grade pay is 2400 but postings are in big (capital) cities with less work load.Divisional accountant in CAG : No hectic work schedule. You are your own boss.Tax assistant in CBDT : 2400 grade pay post but peaceful job with good promotion opportunities.If you want foreign postings :Assistant Section Officer in Ministry of External Affairs : The concept of “ 3 years India , 3 years Abroad “ has lured aspirants to this post .Cypher in Ministry of External Affairs : 3 Years India , 6 years Abroad . Hectic work Schedule.If you love traveContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:23:40.170Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best post in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750900c817f0398fbb1c5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-start-preparation-for-SSC-CGL-in-2020?-",
    "answer" : "You want to start your preparation for SSC CGL, my advice will be try to understand pattern of SSC CGL Exam or I say pattern of SSC Exams. Santosh Kumar Yadav's answer to What are the books /resources to be followed for Tier 1 of SSC CGL? You want to start your preparation - most important things for you have to understand that what actually SSC ask in SSC CGL when you go through previous years you will understand that most of the questions are same just values are different. TCS is conducting exams of SSC since 2019 and there is a fix pattern which TCS follow in each SSC Exams. They ask current affairs of last 3 months only.TCS gs is mostly unpredictable, (except 4–5 current affairs questions and 3–4 static gk questions), GS is only of 50 marks out of 700 so give time according to its value.RContinue Reading You want to start your preparation for SSC CGL, my advice will be try to understand pattern of SSC CGL Exam or I say pattern of SSC Exams. Santosh Kumar Yadav's answer to What are the books /resources to be followed for Tier 1 of SSC CGL? You want to start your preparation - most important things for you have to understand that what actually SSC ask in SSC CGL when you go through previous years you will understand that most of the questions are same just values are different. TCS is conducting exams of SSC since 2019 and there is a fix pattern which TCS follow in each SSC Exams. They ask current affairs of last 3 months only.TCS gs is mostly unpredictable, (except 4–5 current affairs questions and 3–4 static gk questions), GS is only of 50 marks out of 700 so give time according to its value.RContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:24:00.078Z"),
    "question" : "How do I start preparation for SSC CGL in 2020? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750b60c817f0398fbb1dc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-coaching-institutes-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-Hyderabad?-",
    "answer" : "What do you mean by the word ‘best’ ? Every one has his own interpretation for that word. What is yours? Is it Quality of the lectures ? Is it Number of ranks holders the institute give? Don't assume only quality leads to ranksOr other reasons like, this institute is near to my home. This institute charges less fee. My best friend is going to this institute. Test series in this institute. I stressed the first two because most of the aspirants gets confused between these two. Now we will go through reasons which are stressed. Quality: we find the lectures qualitative only if we understand them . if we are unable to grasp the things we will blame the lecturers. Let me give you an example, I am from Classmate academy, I found my lectures with high quality, I suggested my friends to join, but they wher Continue Reading What do you mean by the word ‘best’ ? Every one has his own interpretation for that word. What is yours? Is it Quality of the lectures ? Is it Number of ranks holders the institute give? Don't assume only quality leads to ranksOr other reasons like, this institute is near to my home. This institute charges less fee. My best friend is going to this institute. Test series in this institute. I stressed the first two because most of the aspirants gets confused between these two. Now we will go through reasons which are stressed. Quality: we find the lectures qualitative only if we understand them . if we are unable to grasp the things we will blame the lecturers. Let me give you an example, I am from Classmate academy, I found my lectures with high quality, I suggested my friends to join, but they wher Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:24:38.178Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best coaching institutes for the SSC CGL exam in Hyderabad? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750cb0c817f0398fbb294"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-expected-cut-off-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Shubhankar Kr, B.tech Civil Engineering, Not an IITian (2016)Updated 3 years agoWhat is expected cut off for SSC CGL 2017? Shubhankar Kr The cut off this year will be decidedly lower than 2016. 20% time has been reduced and the difficulty level of the paper has been increased while the no. of questions are still the same (100). Quants section this year has been tricky as compared to last year. There were hardly 5 questions in which pen and paper was required in 2016 cgl. While this year there are about 20 questions which requires pen and paper to be solved. Average students are finding it difficult to attempt even 20 questions this year. So automatically 6–8 marks will decrease this year in quants. English section pattern has changed this year. Now we didn't see comprehension this year in any shift. I feel comprehension was always the easiest part in ssc cgl. So 8–10 marks were almost guaranteed in comprehension. While this ye Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:24:59.638Z"),
    "question" : "What is expected cut off for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750e00c817f0398fbb2a2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-job-of-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "The SSC CGL is one of the most competitive exams you can find in India. It recruits eligible aspirants to various Group B (Gazetted & Non-Gazetted) and Group C Posts, all over India. These jobs offer lucrative salary and a reputed position in society. However, choosing the best job out of 20+ jobs by SSC CGL entirely depends on the personal liking and inclination of the aspirants. For those who want to settle in Delhi: You can opt for the post of Assistant Section Officer (ASO) in Central Secretariat Service (CSS)/Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) /AFHQ/ Railways, and also for Assistant Jobs in MinistriesThese jobs are mostly in-office and one can settle in Delhi permanently until retirementWith lucrative pay and promotions, you can opt for one, if you wish to settle in the National Capital Continue Reading The SSC CGL is one of the most competitive exams you can find in India. It recruits eligible aspirants to various Group B (Gazetted & Non-Gazetted) and Group C Posts, all over India. These jobs offer lucrative salary and a reputed position in society. However, choosing the best job out of 20+ jobs by SSC CGL entirely depends on the personal liking and inclination of the aspirants. For those who want to settle in Delhi: You can opt for the post of Assistant Section Officer (ASO) in Central Secretariat Service (CSS)/Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) /AFHQ/ Railways, and also for Assistant Jobs in MinistriesThese jobs are mostly in-office and one can settle in Delhi permanently until retirementWith lucrative pay and promotions, you can opt for one, if you wish to settle in the National Capital Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:25:20.474Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best job of SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603750f40c817f0398fbb2ae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-general-science-in-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "First watch crash course of each subject for an overview on YouTube or Unacademy (Pratiyogita Mantra made crash course on polity, economics, modern history etc) related to SSC.( Don't watch crash course of upsc or state psc) Cover Science first as it has three subjects so more questions come from this section, history in the last and rest subjects according to your interest. Then go through any one book like Lucent Gk, Black Book of General Awareness, Kiran GS previous years. etc. For current affairs(CA) go to any one application I preferred Adda 247 daily gk points (10–15) I revised them frequently ( Don't make notes of CA It will be time wasting). CA affairs of last 3–4 months are sufficient. Watch monthly top CA videos of Rahul Mishra, Varun Awasthi, Ravi Study iqgk( any one you like or oth Continue Reading First watch crash course of each subject for an overview on YouTube or Unacademy (Pratiyogita Mantra made crash course on polity, economics, modern history etc) related to SSC.( Don't watch crash course of upsc or state psc) Cover Science first as it has three subjects so more questions come from this section, history in the last and rest subjects according to your interest. Then go through any one book like Lucent Gk, Black Book of General Awareness, Kiran GS previous years. etc. For current affairs(CA) go to any one application I preferred Adda 247 daily gk points (10–15) I revised them frequently ( Don't make notes of CA It will be time wasting). CA affairs of last 3–4 months are sufficient. Watch monthly top CA videos of Rahul Mishra, Varun Awasthi, Ravi Study iqgk( any one you like or oth Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:25:40.063Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for general science in SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751190c817f0398fbb370"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-hours-of-daily-study-is-required-to-crack-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Ravi Kumar this question is quite common among ssc aspirants. many aspirants have listen that many successfull candidates have prepared within 6 months. this was true before cgl 2017. but after cgl 2017, whole scenario is changed. I am not disappointing anyone but i am telling truth.you should devote at least 8 to 10 months before cgl pre. if you are good in mathematics, your work will become easy but time may not be reduced. complete time table for everyday preparation.. 2 hrs class for maths (must for beginner) +2 hrs task of class + kiran /rakesh yadav previous 2 hrs. + 2 hrs. vocab.+ 2 hrs. grammar+ 1 hrs reading of the hindu (preferred)= 11 hrs daily in initial 3 to 4 months … many argue with me. why there is 2 hrs for vocab .it can be done in half hours as many youtubers, educaters, aspirants sug Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:26:17.176Z"),
    "question" : "How many hours of daily study is required to crack SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037512d0c817f0398fbb379"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Santosh Kumar Yadav First you should know what is syllabus of SSC CGL. Math and English - 250 marks each Reasoning and GS - 50 marks each Descriptive - 100 marks You can see from here that math and English are of 500 marks out of 700 i.e. 72℅.  Give more and more focus on English and Math. First thing you know that if you want to get selection in CGL avoid too much friendship, keep as less friend as important don’t waste time in watching movies or doing fun activity. With only 1 marks difference 1000+ candidates will cross you always remember that. This is not your school or college exam in which everyone pass this is competitive exam in which only 10,000 pass in 3 million. There is no different syllabus of pre or mains so this is ridiculous that you are preparing for pre now and mains at mains time. If you are study Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:26:37.231Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751410c817f0398fbb431"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Whose-test-series-is-the-best-for-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Mock Tests are one of the most important components of SSC CGL preparation. To see your name in the final list of selected candidates you must have strategy to attempt the mock tests properly. Talking about which test series you should rely on? Then there are hundreds of platforms but a few are irrevocable for the SSC’s point of view. I have attempted many tests from various platforms, so let me share my experience with you. But first let me clear that I am not promoting any test series here, I’m just writing my journey with various test series. If I talk about the platforms which I followed then there are Testbook, Adda24/7, Qmaths, SSC Tube Testbook: I have attempted most of my tests from this platform. I found the questions are quite relevant to that of the SSC’s pattern. But the explanat Continue Reading Mock Tests are one of the most important components of SSC CGL preparation. To see your name in the final list of selected candidates you must have strategy to attempt the mock tests properly. Talking about which test series you should rely on? Then there are hundreds of platforms but a few are irrevocable for the SSC’s point of view. I have attempted many tests from various platforms, so let me share my experience with you. But first let me clear that I am not promoting any test series here, I’m just writing my journey with various test series. If I talk about the platforms which I followed then there are Testbook, Adda24/7, Qmaths, SSC Tube Testbook: I have attempted most of my tests from this platform. I found the questions are quite relevant to that of the SSC’s pattern. But the explanat Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:26:57.240Z"),
    "question" : "Whose test series is the best for SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751540c817f0398fbb43e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "About SSC CGL Exam Exams Conducted by SSC: SSC Conducts the following exams. (a) Combined Graduate Level Examination (CGLE) for posts of Inspector in IT/Central Excise/Dept of post,SI in CBI, Assistant, Divisional Accountant, Auditor, UDC, Junior Accountant,UDC etc.(b) Combined Higher Secondary level examination(c) Sub-Inspector in CPO (BSF,CRPF,CISF, ITBP,SSB)(d) Section Officer (Audit & Commercial)(e) Junior Engineers Examination(f) SSC conducted exams for recruitment to FCI, Prasar Bharati in 2013 About Staff Selection Commission - Combined Graduate Level Exam (SSC CGLE) : Staff Selection Commission conducts Combined Graduate Level Examination (SSC – CGL) for recruitment to different Central Civil posts - Assistant / Inspector /SI / Divisional Accountant /Statistical Officer/ Auditor/Ac Continue Reading About SSC CGL Exam Exams Conducted by SSC: SSC Conducts the following exams. (a) Combined Graduate Level Examination (CGLE) for posts of Inspector in IT/Central Excise/Dept of post,SI in CBI, Assistant, Divisional Accountant, Auditor, UDC, Junior Accountant,UDC etc.(b) Combined Higher Secondary level examination(c) Sub-Inspector in CPO (BSF,CRPF,CISF, ITBP,SSB)(d) Section Officer (Audit & Commercial)(e) Junior Engineers Examination(f) SSC conducted exams for recruitment to FCI, Prasar Bharati in 2013 About Staff Selection Commission - Combined Graduate Level Exam (SSC CGLE) : Staff Selection Commission conducts Combined Graduate Level Examination (SSC – CGL) for recruitment to different Central Civil posts - Assistant / Inspector /SI / Divisional Accountant /Statistical Officer/ Auditor/Ac Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:27:16.178Z"),
    "question" : "What is SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751780c817f0398fbb500"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-highest-post-in-ssc-cgl?-",
    "answer" : "Rahul Kumar >>> These details are brutally honest tweaks i acquired over analyzing thousands of posts and websites and by first hand experience talking to people <<< [[ note - i am not even considering Assistant audit officer and Assistant Accounts Officer because - ## CLEVER STRATEGY , you would have to study too much and gain little, last year only 1 vacancy was available , giving 2 extra papers of Statistics General Studies Finance and Economics . … ### Inspector Posts Department of Post , this is a useless post in group b very very bad ]]]] LETS GO — 0A . According to you need maximum time to study or free time 1- Divisional Accountant Offices under CAG ( . Auditor Offices under C&AG Auditor Offices under CGDA these are also good but they are group c soooo……. ) 2- Assistant Other Ministries/Departments/O Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:27:52.895Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the highest post in ssc cgl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751a70c817f0398fbb51b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-tough-is-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Ankit Yadav Agyani Actually every exam need some aptitude and if one have not this he can be master of it by perseverance and practise a lot Respond to your question see SSC CGL is not that tough as some people would told you,believe me a just average student who doesn't have science background can easily crack this exam, but some of the strategy or tips you must be followed Away from friends and group studies,they only exhausted and waste your time nothing else , do friendship with only few who you think they really help in your preparationBefore any exam preparation a overview of syllabus and previous years papers helps a lot so purchase some genuine and authentic book(LIST ARE GIVEN BELOW:)QUANT : if you are so weak in quant then plss go through NCERT OF CLASS 8,9 and 10 believe me no one can teach you bettContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:28:39.312Z"),
    "question" : "How tough is SSC-CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751c00c817f0398fbb5d8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-apps-for-SSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Erudex provides online learning solution for students with High Quality Animated K12 learning videos. Erudex learning application has learning digital content for SSC and CBSE Boards. Our online learning app is driven to match the needs of every student while keeping their capabilities in mind. Besides providing access to CBSE and SSC syllabus standards through our e-learning app  Student Solutions we provide for CBSE include: Class 3 Class 4 Class 5 Class 6 Class 7 Class 8 Class 9 Class 10 Class 11 Class 12 Erudex provides a comprehensive study path for students that adheres to the NCERT Syllabus. Students have access to enriching content that includes animated videos. All chapters have additional features that make it fun and simple for students for thoroughly understanding Continue Reading Erudex provides online learning solution for students with High Quality Animated K12 learning videos. Erudex learning application has learning digital content for SSC and CBSE Boards. Our online learning app is driven to match the needs of every student while keeping their capabilities in mind. Besides providing access to CBSE and SSC syllabus standards through our e-learning app  Student Solutions we provide for CBSE include: Class 3 Class 4 Class 5 Class 6 Class 7 Class 8 Class 9 Class 10 Class 11 Class 12 Erudex provides a comprehensive study path for students that adheres to the NCERT Syllabus. Students have access to enriching content that includes animated videos. All chapters have additional features that make it fun and simple for students for thoroughly understanding Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:29:04.962Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best apps for SSC preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751d80c817f0398fbb5e3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-is-the-best-for-the-SSC-JE-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Here are 5 tips which will help a candidate crack the SSC JE exam and secure their career: 1. A candidate must strongly specialize in theory and formula-based questions so as to crack the technical part of the primary phase. To excel during this area, one needs an in-depth understanding of all the technical concepts of their respective fields (mechanical, civil, electrical, Quantity Surveying). More importantly, practice solving the preceding years’ question papers, available on the web or from any standard book; this is often a requirement . 2. to organize for the non-technical a part of this section, a candidate should mainly specialise in current affairs, particularly of the last 6 months. This includes subjects like Indian Geography (map-based questions), modern history, and important artic Continue Reading Here are 5 tips which will help a candidate crack the SSC JE exam and secure their career: 1. A candidate must strongly specialize in theory and formula-based questions so as to crack the technical part of the primary phase. To excel during this area, one needs an in-depth understanding of all the technical concepts of their respective fields (mechanical, civil, electrical, Quantity Surveying). More importantly, practice solving the preceding years’ question papers, available on the web or from any standard book; this is often a requirement . 2. to organize for the non-technical a part of this section, a candidate should mainly specialise in current affairs, particularly of the last 6 months. This includes subjects like Indian Geography (map-based questions), modern history, and important artic Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:29:28.385Z"),
    "question" : "Which book is the best for the SSC JE exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603751ee0c817f0398fbb5f5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-there-be-a-SSC-CGL-in-2018?-",
    "answer" : "RaghavAnswered 2 years agoWill there be a SSC CGL in 2018? Raghav The conduct of cgl 2018 exam depends on you. YES!!! IT TOTALLY DEPENDS ON YOU. Before enunciating my above statement, let me tell you some facts. SSC CGL EXAM holds every year in 3 stages.ALMOST 15L students appeared in 2016 and about 10,660 were selected among them.CANDIDATES who fill their application in april 2016 gave tier1 in august , tier 2 in december of the same year and tier3 in april. It comes 2018 and most of them are still waiting for their joining.CANDIDATES of 2017 have just appeared for tier2 in the last month and they are now in delhi demanding for enquiry in alleged paper leak and cheating scandal.IT is very unfortunate that these students have to suffer injustice just because of a few corrupt officers in the government itself. Ask the student who invest his 2 years and have  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:29:50.106Z"),
    "question" : "Will there be a SSC CGL in 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752020c817f0398fbb6ab"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-chance-that-the-SSC-CGL-2017-can-be-cancelled?-",
    "answer" : "Parth Misra I can't tell you with 100℅ assurance but 2 nights before while I was traveling to Uttrakhand , better to say Dev Bhumi, I met with a man who said he was a cgl officer in some department. (I don't remember name of ministry, he talked in almost perfect Hindi and there are few words , specially about government departments that are hard to understand). Coming to point, I asked him the same. He told me 4–5 things about cgl17 and cgl18. Here they are:-. exam will not be cancelled. Ssc has played well and CBI's domain doesn't include any investigation against ssc and other shift's exams. It will only focus on 21st fev exam leak and those handful of jokers. Ssc had it well planned. So re-exam won't happen.Tier 3 will be delayed by 20 around days.Those having 440+ should start preparing for tier 3.AContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:30:10.189Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any chance that the SSC CGL 2017 can be cancelled? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752170c817f0398fbb6b4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-time-table-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "With a proper study plan, limited number of good book references and determination, one can be sure enough to crack the SSC CGL examination. First and most important thing that aspirants must do while starting preparation for SSC CGL is to go thoroughly through the examination syllabus and exam pattern. It will give you a clear idea of the paper and the topics to be asked in the examination and decide the study plan accordingly for the exam. SSC CGL syllabus fundamentally comprises 4 subjects General EnglishGeneral AwarenessQuantitative AptitudeReasoning.Analyze and make a study plan after getting all the details about the Exam. Focus on the important and difficult topics first since it takes time. Also cover the topics in which you are weak. Such domains need more attention and time for pre Continue Reading With a proper study plan, limited number of good book references and determination, one can be sure enough to crack the SSC CGL examination. First and most important thing that aspirants must do while starting preparation for SSC CGL is to go thoroughly through the examination syllabus and exam pattern. It will give you a clear idea of the paper and the topics to be asked in the examination and decide the study plan accordingly for the exam. SSC CGL syllabus fundamentally comprises 4 subjects General EnglishGeneral AwarenessQuantitative AptitudeReasoning.Analyze and make a study plan after getting all the details about the Exam. Focus on the important and difficult topics first since it takes time. Also cover the topics in which you are weak. Such domains need more attention and time for pre Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:30:31.241Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my time table for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752400c817f0398fbb77a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-books-for-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are some books for SSC CGL 2018?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:31:12.869Z"),
    "question" : "What are some books for SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752570c817f0398fbb782"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-there-be-vacancy-in-2018-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "I’m afraid to tell you, but there might be no SSC CGL 2018. So 0(ZERO) vacancy. There is very less chance of this happening. But I do have some reasons to believe so. Below I will tell few reasons due to which I think there might be no vacancy for CGL 2018 and will also tell what might happen in the case.  So CGL 2017 started the application around 16 May to 19 June, with the hope of conducting Tier I from 1st to 20th of August, which changed slightly to 5th-24th August.Results came out for Tier I, and like many people I was among the lucky ones to clear it. Waiting for the Tier 2 to happen, which was supposed to happen in November, later shifted to December and after that to 18th-20th Jan 2017.Recently the date was shifted again to B. A day before the hearing which happened today on B. Now thContinue Reading I’m afraid to tell you, but there might be no SSC CGL 2018. So 0(ZERO) vacancy. There is very less chance of this happening. But I do have some reasons to believe so. Below I will tell few reasons due to which I think there might be no vacancy for CGL 2018 and will also tell what might happen in the case.  So CGL 2017 started the application around 16 May to 19 June, with the hope of conducting Tier I from 1st to 20th of August, which changed slightly to 5th-24th August.Results came out for Tier I, and like many people I was among the lucky ones to clear it. Waiting for the Tier 2 to happen, which was supposed to happen in November, later shifted to December and after that to 18th-20th Jan 2017.Recently the date was shifted again to B. A day before the hearing which happened today on B. Now thContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:31:35.064Z"),
    "question" : "Will there be vacancy in 2018 for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752980c817f0398fbb853"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1-exam-likely-to-be-held?-",
    "answer" : "Arpit Sharma, Cleared SSC CGL 2016 as AAO in CAGAnswered 2 years ago · Author has 904 answers and 8M answer viewsWhen is the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1 exam likely to be held? Arpit Sharma Hi , as you must be knowing about the Supreme Court decision about SSC CGL 2017, SSC CHSL 2017 and other SSC exams held in and around similar period, you should not expect SSC CGL 2018 any time soon. That being said, SSC CGL 2018 should be held (and not scrapped) in 2019. In my previous answers written before the verdict, I predicted January end - February for tier-1 to be conducted but now I might have to take my words back. Supreme Court in its verdict yesterday put a stay on result declaration of SSC CGL 2017 till further orders. The highlight was that SC said that the whole SSC examination process looked tainted. These were the views based on CBI report. Now , CBI has already interrogated and submitted its report and from yesterday’s verdict, it is clear that CBI report directs to mass c Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:32:40.003Z"),
    "question" : "When is the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1 exam likely to be held? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752af0c817f0398fbb914"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-crack-the-SSC-CGL-while-working?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I crack the SSC CGL while working?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:33:03.747Z"),
    "question" : "How can I crack the SSC CGL while working? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752c40c817f0398fbb927"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-coaching-necessary-to-crack-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is coaching necessary to crack SSC CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:33:24.292Z"),
    "question" : "Is coaching necessary to crack SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752db0c817f0398fbb934"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-does-one-prepare-for-current-affairs-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Harshita Gupta, Professor (2002-present)Answered October 17, 2020 · Author has 408 answers and 211.9K answer viewsHow does one prepare for current affairs for the SSC CGL? Harshita Gupta SSC CGL Current Affairs Section: Preparation Tips Read the Newspaper daily Make daily reading of newspapers a habit. Read a minimum of two of the national dailies a day. Make notes out of the important events round the world with a special specialization in India. If you don’t want to form notes, maintain a file of newspaper cuttings, and keep pertaining to it regularly. Familiarize yourself with Periodicals Magazines like Pratiyogita Darpan and Competition Success Review can go an extended way in helping you crack the overall Awareness section. These magazines won't only assist you to have access to the recent developments of India and therefore the World but also will make your job of creating notes easier. Go through Previous Years Question Papers Solving previous years' question papers is vi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:33:47.648Z"),
    "question" : "How does one prepare for current affairs for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603752f10c817f0398fbb9f0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-life-of-a-ssc-cgl-employee?-",
    "answer" : "You should not follow my routine because it was not a routine. In cgl 2017 tier 1, the most important task before me was to cover gk as much as possible. It took me around 20 days. My routine for those 20 days: Wake up time - between 11am –12pmJust after waking up, if it was weekend, I used to attempt mock test. On other days, just pick up lucent or previous year questions and solved them.Lunch - between 12pm to 3pm. Sometimes, skipped lunch if I did not feel like eating.In evening, I used to go with my friend to buy vegetables, milk and other necessary stuffs. It was my only everyday routine.Then, for one hour or something, listening to music, passing time, cursing ssc and many other things. And then have dinner before 10pm.After 10pm, again lucent and previous year questions till 12am or 1amContinue Reading You should not follow my routine because it was not a routine. In cgl 2017 tier 1, the most important task before me was to cover gk as much as possible. It took me around 20 days. My routine for those 20 days: Wake up time - between 11am –12pmJust after waking up, if it was weekend, I used to attempt mock test. On other days, just pick up lucent or previous year questions and solved them.Lunch - between 12pm to 3pm. Sometimes, skipped lunch if I did not feel like eating.In evening, I used to go with my friend to buy vegetables, milk and other necessary stuffs. It was my only everyday routine.Then, for one hour or something, listening to music, passing time, cursing ssc and many other things. And then have dinner before 10pm.After 10pm, again lucent and previous year questions till 12am or 1amContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:34:09.092Z"),
    "question" : "How is life of a ssc cgl employee? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603753140c817f0398fbba02"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-need-for-coaching-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Yes very well, provided you know what to do and what not to do. The problem is not that competition is huge, the problem is that aspirants don’t know how to approach the exam. If your approach is right then you can clear it in first attempt itself and, moreover if you preparation is right you can get top post too. As far as coaching institutes are concerned, I don’t think there is any need. coaching can be helpful in advance mathematics part if and only if you are very weak in maths otherwise there is no need. mistakes often responsible for failure are preparing banking exams with ssc. you must know that both exams are totally different. for banking you have to prepare current affairs, reasoning ( that is totally different from SSC) all this divert your attention. I am not saying that you shouContinue Reading Yes very well, provided you know what to do and what not to do. The problem is not that competition is huge, the problem is that aspirants don’t know how to approach the exam. If your approach is right then you can clear it in first attempt itself and, moreover if you preparation is right you can get top post too. As far as coaching institutes are concerned, I don’t think there is any need. coaching can be helpful in advance mathematics part if and only if you are very weak in maths otherwise there is no need. mistakes often responsible for failure are preparing banking exams with ssc. you must know that both exams are totally different. for banking you have to prepare current affairs, reasoning ( that is totally different from SSC) all this divert your attention. I am not saying that you shouContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:34:44.471Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any need for coaching for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037533d0c817f0398fbbac7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-prepare-for-Bank-PO-and-SSC-CGL-at-the-same-time?-",
    "answer" : "Sravya Km Yes. It is quite possible to Prepare for Both SSC and Bank exams.One important rule of thumb for all competitive exams is to be extremely careful about the selection of your competitive exams. Go through the following points to prepare for both the exams simultaneously. ➤Know the nature of the examWhether the exam is offline mode or online. How many questions and topics are asked. total time allotted, is there any sectional cut-off? Negative marking etc. ➤Know the syllabus Figure out the similar topics and the different ones. Make a list of the common topics that are asked in both SSC and BANKING exams. prepare for these common topics in a single slot. ➤Your current preparation level. Once you know the pattern and syllabus, you need to know where you stand in terms of preparation. This is a ve Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:35:25.565Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to prepare for Bank PO and SSC CGL at the same time? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037536a0c817f0398fbbb8e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-vocabulary-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Having strong vocabulary is very important in an exam like CGL or for any competitive exam because it covers topics like Synonyms, Antynoms, Cloze test, Spelling error, etc. These topics constitute good amount of weightage in both prelims and mains. I followed following sources: First and most important is reading of newspaper daily. I preferred The Hindu. Every day you will find so many new words in it. Have a dictionary with you to search the meaning immediately and save the word. Best part is that most of the words will keep on repeating in The Hindu and eventually it will stick in your mind. I never made notes of vocab rather i used to save them in the dictionary app. It saved a lot of time and best part was that I could revise them whenever and wherever I want. SSC is known for repeating Continue Reading Having strong vocabulary is very important in an exam like CGL or for any competitive exam because it covers topics like Synonyms, Antynoms, Cloze test, Spelling error, etc. These topics constitute good amount of weightage in both prelims and mains. I followed following sources: First and most important is reading of newspaper daily. I preferred The Hindu. Every day you will find so many new words in it. Have a dictionary with you to search the meaning immediately and save the word. Best part is that most of the words will keep on repeating in The Hindu and eventually it will stick in your mind. I never made notes of vocab rather i used to save them in the dictionary app. It saved a lot of time and best part was that I could revise them whenever and wherever I want. SSC is known for repeating Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:36:10.689Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare vocabulary for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037537d0c817f0398fbbb98"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-online-test-series-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best online test series for SSC CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:36:29.103Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best online test series for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037538f0c817f0398fbbba4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-mistakes-should-be-avoided-during-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Never start you preparation keeping previous year cutoffs in mind or keeping category cutoffs in mind. Rather try to give your best irrespective of anything.Never ignore the importance of previous year questions because ssc repeats questions and majority of the questions are based on same pattern every year.Never take sections like reasoning lightly because in recent years ssc has increased level of this section.Never be overconfident if you have command over any subject. Keep practicing for it also while devoting majority time to weak subject. Try to score good in both as merit is based on overall marks.Give fix amount of time for GS preparation never too less nor too much. GS is more of a luck based but you must know basics along with current affairs.Never get demotivated if you score 10Continue Reading Never start you preparation keeping previous year cutoffs in mind or keeping category cutoffs in mind. Rather try to give your best irrespective of anything.Never ignore the importance of previous year questions because ssc repeats questions and majority of the questions are based on same pattern every year.Never take sections like reasoning lightly because in recent years ssc has increased level of this section.Never be overconfident if you have command over any subject. Keep practicing for it also while devoting majority time to weak subject. Try to score good in both as merit is based on overall marks.Give fix amount of time for GS preparation never too less nor too much. GS is more of a luck based but you must know basics along with current affairs.Never get demotivated if you score 10Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:36:47.668Z"),
    "question" : "What mistakes should be avoided during SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603753cb0c817f0398fbbc76"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-best-SSC-CGL-tier-2-practice-book?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is best SSC CGL tier 2 practice book?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:37:47.577Z"),
    "question" : "What is best SSC CGL tier 2 practice book? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603753e00c817f0398fbbd32"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-three-months-enough-for-an-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Yes three months is enough time only if you have failed in this examination atleast one time. I am generalising this and not in favour of one particular person. There might be a genius who cracked IIT in his first attempt and completed his IIT and reasonably good at Quant (assuming English to be top notch) has 99% percent chances of clearing this exam in three months. Otherwise big no from my side. THE SUCCESS RATIO is almost 1:250. This is not exact figure but almost true. Atleast One to two lakh students work very hard for this exam. I am not counting the students who work hard. Because they are not found to clear exam anyway and that will b an experience for them. What to do : Let's say if you are asked to calculate 9.09% of 110, if you use the conventional method it is 9.09*110 / 100. What Continue Reading Yes three months is enough time only if you have failed in this examination atleast one time. I am generalising this and not in favour of one particular person. There might be a genius who cracked IIT in his first attempt and completed his IIT and reasonably good at Quant (assuming English to be top notch) has 99% percent chances of clearing this exam in three months. Otherwise big no from my side. THE SUCCESS RATIO is almost 1:250. This is not exact figure but almost true. Atleast One to two lakh students work very hard for this exam. I am not counting the students who work hard. Because they are not found to clear exam anyway and that will b an experience for them. What to do : Let's say if you are asked to calculate 9.09% of 110, if you use the conventional method it is 9.09*110 / 100. What Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:38:08.116Z"),
    "question" : "Are three months enough for an SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603753f30c817f0398fbbd3c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-exam-is-easier-to-crack-BANK-PO-or-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "One of the most commonly asked question by many students who want to prepare for competitive exams is- Which exam is easier to crack ‘Bank PO or SSC CGL’? Here i will try to answer this question in detail so that you can understand and decide the path ahead for yourself. The difficulty level of an exam is defined by several factors and we will be addressing all those factors. To begin with, you should first be aware with the exam pattern, syllabus etc of both the exams as they differ from one another still you will find many aspirants prepare for both the exam simultaneously. Exam Syllabus: The syllabus of Bank PO needs 3-4 months to cover completely but the SSC CGL syllabus is very vast and it needs atleast 5-6 months to cover the entire syllabus. Exam Pattern: One of the most important aspec Continue Reading One of the most commonly asked question by many students who want to prepare for competitive exams is- Which exam is easier to crack ‘Bank PO or SSC CGL’? Here i will try to answer this question in detail so that you can understand and decide the path ahead for yourself. The difficulty level of an exam is defined by several factors and we will be addressing all those factors. To begin with, you should first be aware with the exam pattern, syllabus etc of both the exams as they differ from one another still you will find many aspirants prepare for both the exam simultaneously. Exam Syllabus: The syllabus of Bank PO needs 3-4 months to cover completely but the SSC CGL syllabus is very vast and it needs atleast 5-6 months to cover the entire syllabus. Exam Pattern: One of the most important aspec Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:38:27.819Z"),
    "question" : "Which exam is easier to crack-BANK PO or SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754060c817f0398fbbd47"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-life-after-clearing-SSC-JE?-",
    "answer" : "Koteswararao Chappa, Junior Engineer at Central Public Works Department (2015-present)Updated January 25, 2021What is life after clearing SSC JE? Koteswararao Chappa I have cleared exam in 2015 and joined in CPWD .i am drawing salary of 44k with 5 years experience. Dont be too dreamy about JE job and please continue your preparation, try for other cadre like IES or other state services.In any department Junior Engineer (Railways/CPWD/MES) job is responsible/crucial and answerable to every body.Junior Engineer is generally posted in field for the execution of construction and maintenance work. Junior Engineer job carries high responsibility. Junior Engineer is hundred percent responsible for the quantity of work executed and accordingly payment is done for work executed.JE is section officer and to manitain some area or some buildings /construction. Basically you are at bottom line of executive cadre so they will ask/expect work from you and they will p Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:38:46.459Z"),
    "question" : "What is life after clearing SSC JE? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037541b0c817f0398fbbe03"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-there-be-SSC-CGL-in-2019?-",
    "answer" : "NO. CGL 2019 will be replaced by CET 2019. Common Entrance Test, 2019 for SSC Banking and Railway Exams Exam Details – The Common Entrance Test 2019 has been proposed to be conducted in three levels: i) Matric Level ii) Higher Secondary Level iii) Graduation level Educational Qualification CET 2019 Matric Level- 10th Standard passed from a recognized board CET 2019 Higher Secondary Level- 10+2 Intermediate/Higher Secondary or equivalent exam passed from a recognized board CET Graduate Level- Graduation in any discipline from a recognized university Important Information regarding SSC CET Recruitment 2019 i) Candidates have to register themselves at National Career Service – NCS Portal in order to apply for CET. NCS will generate an Unique ID for each candidate. ii) It is proposed that currently the CET will Continue Reading NO. CGL 2019 will be replaced by CET 2019. Common Entrance Test, 2019 for SSC Banking and Railway Exams Exam Details – The Common Entrance Test 2019 has been proposed to be conducted in three levels: i) Matric Level ii) Higher Secondary Level iii) Graduation level Educational Qualification CET 2019 Matric Level- 10th Standard passed from a recognized board CET 2019 Higher Secondary Level- 10+2 Intermediate/Higher Secondary or equivalent exam passed from a recognized board CET Graduate Level- Graduation in any discipline from a recognized university Important Information regarding SSC CET Recruitment 2019 i) Candidates have to register themselves at National Career Service – NCS Portal in order to apply for CET. NCS will generate an Unique ID for each candidate. ii) It is proposed that currently the CET will Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:39:07.585Z"),
    "question" : "Will there be SSC CGL in 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754400c817f0398fbbe20"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Have-you-cleared-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Have you cleared SSC CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:39:44.456Z"),
    "question" : "Have you cleared SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754550c817f0398fbbeda"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/In-which-posts-of-SSC-CGL-does-one-get-home-posting?-",
    "answer" : "Home posting. Your question itself is not complete. When you are asking such type of questions, describe everything what you really want. It depends on your home place. If it is in Delhi, in most of the posts, you can get home posting. For Delhi candidates, CSS assistant is the best post because of permanent posting in delhi. You will always be in delhi until govt decides to move all the ministries and sansad bhavan to some other city. The procedure of posting is like this. Based on merit (and no of vacancies), you are allotted one service e.g. income tax,excise, assistant CSS , assistant MEA, auditor,sub inspector CBI etc. Up to this point you will only know what type of post you will get.Now, you can use your common sense, if assistant CSS or assistant in any other ministries is allotted to yContinue Reading Home posting. Your question itself is not complete. When you are asking such type of questions, describe everything what you really want. It depends on your home place. If it is in Delhi, in most of the posts, you can get home posting. For Delhi candidates, CSS assistant is the best post because of permanent posting in delhi. You will always be in delhi until govt decides to move all the ministries and sansad bhavan to some other city. The procedure of posting is like this. Based on merit (and no of vacancies), you are allotted one service e.g. income tax,excise, assistant CSS , assistant MEA, auditor,sub inspector CBI etc. Up to this point you will only know what type of post you will get.Now, you can use your common sense, if assistant CSS or assistant in any other ministries is allotted to yContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:40:05.234Z"),
    "question" : "In which posts of SSC CGL does one get home posting? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754680c817f0398fbbee8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-crack-SSC-CGL-easily?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I crack SSC CGL easily?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:40:24.849Z"),
    "question" : "How can I crack SSC CGL easily? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037547a0c817f0398fbbef2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-time-is-needed-to-clear-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Time for clearing this exam depends on your preparation level and your IQ level. If you have done your schooling in English Medium school, then half of the battle is done as English section carries half of the total marks in Tier-2 of CGLE. I personally believe that this exam is all about Maths/Quant and English. If you are good at these two subjects, then 4–5 months preparation is more than sufficient. Here, i will share my own experience with you. I did my schooling from convent school and Army school, Delhi and afterwards did my Graduation and post graduation from Delhi university. English was never an issue, thanks to my father (and my school teachers too)for teaching me English grammar during my school days. I had scored 94 in 10th standard CBSE board(Mathematics) so i was overconfiden Continue Reading Time for clearing this exam depends on your preparation level and your IQ level. If you have done your schooling in English Medium school, then half of the battle is done as English section carries half of the total marks in Tier-2 of CGLE. I personally believe that this exam is all about Maths/Quant and English. If you are good at these two subjects, then 4–5 months preparation is more than sufficient. Here, i will share my own experience with you. I did my schooling from convent school and Army school, Delhi and afterwards did my Graduation and post graduation from Delhi university. English was never an issue, thanks to my father (and my school teachers too)for teaching me English grammar during my school days. I had scored 94 in 10th standard CBSE board(Mathematics) so i was overconfiden Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:40:42.922Z"),
    "question" : "How much time is needed to clear the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037548d0c817f0398fbbfae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-English-grammar-channel-on-YouTube-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Ankush KumarAnswered 2 years agoWhat are the best English grammar channel on YouTube for SSC CGL? Ankush Kumar Just search English Grammar for SSC on YouTube and you will find thousands of channels who are claiming that they will teach you English Grammar for SSC. But, the main problem of the 95% of those channels is that they just copy and paste the materials of Plinth to Paramount (by Neetu Singh), Objective English (by S.P. Bakshi), A mirror of Common errors (by Ashok K. Singh), Study material of Jamal Perwez (of Patna), MB Publication's previous year (by Ajay Kumar Singh of Patna) Then, Why do you need a YouTube channel to learn English for SSC, just learn thwm from their sources (above given) those are enough for you. BUT, If you still want to learn English Grammar from Youtube, then these two channels are two of the best: MB Books Tutorials: Ajay Kumar Singh teaches English Grammar on this YouTubContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:41:01.233Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best English grammar channel on YouTube for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037549e0c817f0398fbbfb9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-2018-be-postponed-from-the-date-mentioned-in-the-calendar?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Will the SSC CGL Tier 1 2018 be postponed from the date mentioned in the calendar?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:41:18.633Z"),
    "question" : "Will the SSC CGL Tier 1 2018 be postponed from the date mentioned in the calendar? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754d20c817f0398fbc083"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-is-suitable-for-the-SSC-JE-Civil-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hello Staff Selection Commission conducts Every year Junior Engineer Examination. This Non- Gazetted post generally for Department like CPWD Central Public Works DepartmentCentral Water CommissionMES Military Engineering Services.All Candidate who have Completed Diploma/ Degree form any recognized University/ Institute can apply for this post. Best Books for SSC JE Civil 2018 are given below: SSC Junior Engineer Civil book( CPWD/MES/CWE ) : Civil Engineering Solved Papers & Practice Sets 2017 Paperback – 10 Mar 2017″ by Hatti Aggarwal Publication “SSC CPWD – MES Civil Engineering book (Junior Engg. Recruitment Exam) Includes Solved Paper 2013 – 2015” by GKP It contain GENERAL ENGINEERING1. Building Materials, 2. Surveying 3. Soil Mechanics 4. Hydraulics 5. Environmental Engineering 6. Theory of  Continue Reading Hello Staff Selection Commission conducts Every year Junior Engineer Examination. This Non- Gazetted post generally for Department like CPWD Central Public Works DepartmentCentral Water CommissionMES Military Engineering Services.All Candidate who have Completed Diploma/ Degree form any recognized University/ Institute can apply for this post. Best Books for SSC JE Civil 2018 are given below: SSC Junior Engineer Civil book( CPWD/MES/CWE ) : Civil Engineering Solved Papers & Practice Sets 2017 Paperback – 10 Mar 2017″ by Hatti Aggarwal Publication “SSC CPWD – MES Civil Engineering book (Junior Engg. Recruitment Exam) Includes Solved Paper 2013 – 2015” by GKP It contain GENERAL ENGINEERING1. Building Materials, 2. Surveying 3. Soil Mechanics 4. Hydraulics 5. Environmental Engineering 6. Theory of  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:42:10.374Z"),
    "question" : "Which book is suitable for the SSC JE Civil exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603754f40c817f0398fbc09c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-best-books-for-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-and-2-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Staff Selection Commission (SSC) conducts an exam for Combined Graduate Level (CGL) per year. As we all know, lakhs of candidates appear during this exam for a couple of thousand vacancies that make the exam highly competitive. For this, candidates will need to plan their study in an efficient way. The foremost important thing for the preparation is to follow the simplest books.. SSC CGL Books The SSC CGL preparation will require a reference to many books. The important SSC CGL books will help the students to focus on the specific topics, and they will ultimately score well. SSC CGL Books for English Candidates must leave no stone unturned for SSC CGL English Preparation both in Paper I and Paper II. The important SSC CGL Books for English are given below: OBJECTIVE GENERAL ENGLISH BY SP BAKSHI Continue Reading Staff Selection Commission (SSC) conducts an exam for Combined Graduate Level (CGL) per year. As we all know, lakhs of candidates appear during this exam for a couple of thousand vacancies that make the exam highly competitive. For this, candidates will need to plan their study in an efficient way. The foremost important thing for the preparation is to follow the simplest books.. SSC CGL Books The SSC CGL preparation will require a reference to many books. The important SSC CGL books will help the students to focus on the specific topics, and they will ultimately score well. SSC CGL Books for English Candidates must leave no stone unturned for SSC CGL English Preparation both in Paper I and Paper II. The important SSC CGL Books for English are given below: OBJECTIVE GENERAL ENGLISH BY SP BAKSHI Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:42:44.881Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best books for SSC CGL Tier 1 and 2 preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755050c817f0398fbc156"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-SSC-a-good-career-option?-",
    "answer" : "Abhishek Chaudhary For me, yeah indeed it is. I will list down the reasons for the same:- 1.) Pride and Prestige:- My each and every effort in the Department will one or the other way contribute in building of the nation. As i will be progressing up the ladder, my grip will be expanding as vast as begining from ASSISTANT SECTION OFFICER to SECTION OFFICER SECTION OFFICER TO UNDER SECRETARY UNDER SECRETARY TO DEPUTY DIRECTOR, Deputy director to Director, DIRECTOR of a particular Ministry. Needless to say what fraction of Indian citizen I can affect at each level. I wont be seeking motivation to work from the country from elsewhere, my work alone will take care of it. 2.) HARMONY:- To be good at your life, you need to be investing your time in each and every field wherever you are linked to. Being in Central Secretar Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:43:01.909Z"),
    "question" : "Is SSC a good career option? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755190c817f0398fbc161"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-JE?-(Mechanical)-",
    "answer" : "Nikhil Ahuja, Nothing like Government Jobs!!Answered 5 years ago · Author has 99 answers and 1.3M answer viewsHow do I prepare for the SSC JE? (Mechanical) Nikhil Ahuja Thanks for A2A!! General Tips -: The first step is to go through the syllabus for the exam on the official website of SSC. This will give you a general idea of the topics you need to prepare. Once you go through the syllabus write down the topics you have absolutely no idea about and try to start preparing these topics first. This will give you more time to prepare topics that you know nothing about instead of keeping these till the end when you might be tempted to completely skip that topic!The next step is to get the appropriate books (List is mentioned in the end) to start your preparation. You need to get the SSC exam books which are designed for the purpose of the SSC exam. Make sure you buy the book for each section of the paper so you do not have to worry about its credibility.It is dContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:43:21.194Z"),
    "question" : "How do i prepare for the ssc je? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037552c0c817f0398fbc16d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-plan-to-clear-the-SSC-CGL-in-5-to-6-months?-",
    "answer" : "If you're wondering after reading the title, let me assure it's considerably possible if you systematically do your preparation, you'll crack CGL with six months of preparation, albeit you're not an engineer. Combined Graduate Level Exam is held by Staff Selection Commission per annum (if there's no Court Case involved). it's a three-stage examination. Tier-I and Tier-II are online exams by MCQ tests, and Tier-III is an offline and written test. there's also Computer-based skill/type tests also are conducted for a few of the posts. If you're new with this examination, let me first tell you that in Tier-I there'll be 100 MCQ for 200 marks, which you've got to unravel within an hour. Twenty-five questions each from capacity, General Awareness, English, and Quantitative aptitude. Tier-II has 2  Continue Reading If you're wondering after reading the title, let me assure it's considerably possible if you systematically do your preparation, you'll crack CGL with six months of preparation, albeit you're not an engineer. Combined Graduate Level Exam is held by Staff Selection Commission per annum (if there's no Court Case involved). it's a three-stage examination. Tier-I and Tier-II are online exams by MCQ tests, and Tier-III is an offline and written test. there's also Computer-based skill/type tests also are conducted for a few of the posts. If you're new with this examination, let me first tell you that in Tier-I there'll be 100 MCQ for 200 marks, which you've got to unravel within an hour. Twenty-five questions each from capacity, General Awareness, English, and Quantitative aptitude. Tier-II has 2  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:43:40.121Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best plan to clear the SSC CGL in 5 to 6 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037553d0c817f0398fbc223"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-document-are-required-for-SSC-CGL-at-the-time-of-verification?-",
    "answer" : "I have attended my document verification on March, 2016. It's been a long time.. I don't remember that much, but as far I know these are the documents I have submitted.. Admit card for Description /skill test. Keep a photocopy for reference. Last time they did document verification and skill test on the same day.They will give post preference form to you. Fill and submit it to them.2 or 3 passport photos. Not necessarily recent photographs. The photographs should match the photos you have submitted while applying for the examProof of Identity, proof of address ( Aadhar is enough for both) proof of ageAll the educational certificates in original as well as photocopies. Just in case, take two sets of photocopies10th ( Metriculation)Intermediate ( 10+2)For graduation, Mark sheets of semester wContinue Reading I have attended my document verification on March, 2016. It's been a long time.. I don't remember that much, but as far I know these are the documents I have submitted.. Admit card for Description /skill test. Keep a photocopy for reference. Last time they did document verification and skill test on the same day.They will give post preference form to you. Fill and submit it to them.2 or 3 passport photos. Not necessarily recent photographs. The photographs should match the photos you have submitted while applying for the examProof of Identity, proof of address ( Aadhar is enough for both) proof of ageAll the educational certificates in original as well as photocopies. Just in case, take two sets of photocopies10th ( Metriculation)Intermediate ( 10+2)For graduation, Mark sheets of semester wContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:43:57.209Z"),
    "question" : "Which document are required for SSC CGL at the time of verification? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037554e0c817f0398fbc232"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-get-a-good-score-in-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I get a good score in SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:44:14.681Z"),
    "question" : "How can I get a good score in SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037555f0c817f0398fbc23b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-score-in-SSC-CGL-tier-1-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers What is your score in SSC CGL tier 1 2017? My exam was on 21st August, 1st shift I attempted 95 questions out of which 9 are wrong and my total score is 167.5 Section-wise score : Reasoning : 48 GS : 26.5 Maths : 48 English : 45 There is one incorrect question in quant section which i have challenged which may increase my score with +2 marks. In my previous attempt in 2016, i had a score of 146 in prelims whereas a lot of the people were getting 165+ and even the average score was 155+ i had a mere 9 marks above the cutoff, ranking as low as 35000. Even though everyone around was telling me that it'll be okay, prepare well for tier 2 blah blah yada yada yet we all knew that it was only an assurance as i was lagging behind by a huge difference of 20 marks. Nevertheless i went ahead with my tier 2 preparation and scored 340 in mains, 179 in Ma Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:44:31.820Z"),
    "question" : "What is your score in SSC CGL tier 1 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755700c817f0398fbc24b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-your-SSC-CGL-2017-Mains?-",
    "answer" : "Subhadip Debnath My tier 1 score was 152.5 and I starting preparing for tier 2 by the end of august. My target was to get post of income tax inspector for which I needed around 345 marks in mains (on the basis of last year's result). I was always confident of achieving this target because I had scored 45.5 and 42.5 in maths and English respectively in tier 1. Also my score in testbook test series was constantly crossing 360. I had a marriage at home in November and a few other important occasions which had an impact on my studies but the continual postponement of exam took care of it as I felt like even God is conspiring to help me achieve my target. Overall my preparation was satisfactory but I couldn't revise vocabulary which I had prepared earlier. Then came the D-day. It was 18th February and I already  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:44:48.844Z"),
    "question" : "How was your SSC CGL 2017 Mains? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755920c817f0398fbc309"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-expected-SSC-CGL-Tier-2-cutoff-for-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Subhadip Debnath Hello,i have studied the cgl trends of past years and i have personally interacted with many of my fellow aspirants. Besides i have watched a hundred if not a thousand youtube videos just to find the answer to this question. So it is time to address the elephant in the room.I have reached to the following conclusion(s): Yes,the cutoffs of tier1 have an impact on tier1+2 cutoffs. It was lower than that of 2016 by 6 marks. ( Considering 150000 students only)A decrease of 25 marks in quant. Dont run behind the toppers. They dont decide the cutoffs. Average score has fallen from 150 to 125.An increase of 15 marks in English. Yes it has increased drastically. It has infact vanished the impact of quant.Mass level of cheating. Lets pray for its effect to be small. So an increment of 5 marks. It caContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:45:22.813Z"),
    "question" : "What is the expected SSC CGL Tier 2 cutoff for 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755a40c817f0398fbc315"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-both-for-SSC-CGL-and-UPSC-civil-service?-",
    "answer" : "Praveen Singh Can you prepare for both SSC CGL and CSE. It's like putting your foots in two different boats.  In today's world the government jobs are getting difficult every year. One cannot prepare for two different exams at same time like CGL and CSE. They may seem you same but they need different approach to prepare. In SSC CGL you have to prepare Quantitative aptitude, English, Reasoning and General Awareness. For tier 1 after clearing this stage you have to focus on QA and ENG for tier 2. Then tier 3 wher you have to write an essay or application. So the whole process of ssc exam is different from CSE. In CSE you have to prepare mostly general knowledge subject like history, polity, geography, environmental sciences etc. and If we talk about cset where English,Reasoning and aptitude questions asked one  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:45:40.329Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare both for SSC CGL and UPSC civil service? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755b80c817f0398fbc3d1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-your-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How was your SSC CGL 2017?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:46:00.042Z"),
    "question" : "How was your SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755cc0c817f0398fbc3dd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-exact-salary-of-an-SSC-CGL-officer?-",
    "answer" : "Partha Kansabanik 1. A successful candidate in SSCCGL Examination joins Level-7 as per VIIth CPC Pay-scale. Level-7 starts from (entry grade Basic Pay) Rs. 44,900/- p.m. 2. The candidate’s salary would vary depending upon the type of city where he/she would be posted. In metro (Class-X) cities, such employee will get maximum HRA of 24% of the Basic Pay (if he/she doesn’t take Government accommodation). In Class-Y cities, a candidate will get HRA at the rate of 16% of the Basic Pay. In Class-Z places (in rural areas), the HRA is 8% of the Basic Pay. But generally, SSCCGL-qualified candidates don’t get posted in rural areas. 3. The salary would also move upwards after the increase in DA rate. The present DA rate is 9% of the Basic Pay. DA increases twice every year. Another 3% DA has been due in January, 2019 ( Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:46:20.364Z"),
    "question" : "What is the exact salary of an SSC CGL officer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603755f40c817f0398fbc4a3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-book-of-reasoning-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "The SSC CGL selection process involves 4 tiers and only the SSC CGL Tier 1 exam tests the reasoning ability of the candidates through the General Intelligence and Reasoning section. In this section, both verbal and non-verbal reasoning are tested. The best books to prepare from for both these types of questions are as follows: #1 Modern Approach to Verbal & Non-Verbal Reasoning by Dr R.S. Aggarwal - This book is only available in English - It is ideal for practicing questions and the problems from this book are exhaustive and more than sufficient to ace the reasoning section of the SSC CGL #2 Perfect Verbal Reasoning by Ajay Chauhan - This book is just as good as R.S. Agarwal’s book. However, this book has many more questions and the problems and concepts are explained in a better and easy to gra Continue Reading The SSC CGL selection process involves 4 tiers and only the SSC CGL Tier 1 exam tests the reasoning ability of the candidates through the General Intelligence and Reasoning section. In this section, both verbal and non-verbal reasoning are tested. The best books to prepare from for both these types of questions are as follows: #1 Modern Approach to Verbal & Non-Verbal Reasoning by Dr R.S. Aggarwal - This book is only available in English - It is ideal for practicing questions and the problems from this book are exhaustive and more than sufficient to ace the reasoning section of the SSC CGL #2 Perfect Verbal Reasoning by Ajay Chauhan - This book is just as good as R.S. Agarwal’s book. However, this book has many more questions and the problems and concepts are explained in a better and easy to gra Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:47:00.902Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best book of reasoning for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756080c817f0398fbc4af"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-prepare-for-both-bank-PO-and-SSC-exams-simultaneously?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is it possible to prepare for both bank PO and SSC exams simultaneously?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:47:20.989Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to prepare for both bank PO and SSC exams simultaneously? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037561c0c817f0398fbc4bb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-SSC-CHSL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Following are my 20 commandments for SSC CHSL 2018. This exam can be easily cracked if you prepare in right way. Avoid the wrong ways of preparation. When I started my preparation in SSC CGL 2013, I did not prepare for GK much and was over-confident as my General Knowledge had always been good. I got pathetic 8–9 marks in GK which resulted in just 111 marks in Tier-1.In Tier-1, all the 4 sections are equally important.In SSC CHSL , speed matters a lot. If you have a slow speed , you will not be among toppers even if you know everything. Now the time has been reduced to 60 minutes, so speed up.If you have time, read NCERTs and prepare some notes. Some questions actually come from NCERTs, especially in History (9th –10 th class), Geography(9th - 10th class), Microeconomics(11th class) and GenContinue Reading Following are my 20 commandments for SSC CHSL 2018. This exam can be easily cracked if you prepare in right way. Avoid the wrong ways of preparation. When I started my preparation in SSC CGL 2013, I did not prepare for GK much and was over-confident as my General Knowledge had always been good. I got pathetic 8–9 marks in GK which resulted in just 111 marks in Tier-1.In Tier-1, all the 4 sections are equally important.In SSC CHSL , speed matters a lot. If you have a slow speed , you will not be among toppers even if you know everything. Now the time has been reduced to 60 minutes, so speed up.If you have time, read NCERTs and prepare some notes. Some questions actually come from NCERTs, especially in History (9th –10 th class), Geography(9th - 10th class), Microeconomics(11th class) and GenContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:47:40.552Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for SSC CHSL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756300c817f0398fbc57b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-better-RRB-JE-or-SSC-JE-and-why?-",
    "answer" : "Here my Opinion Move for SSC -JE if you got department like CPWD (Most preferable)/MES (((I am working in CPWD from last 4 years. So , I can give this answer accurately.))) And also I have 6 friends in RRB-Je. #You can compare little bit of JE Post through SSC and RRB-JE #But you can't compare Assistant engineer Post in CPWD/MES, And Senior section Engineer (SSE) in RRB because You have much benefit in AE in CPWD/MES than SSE in RRB. For Junior Engineer 1). SALARY Basic Pay of both SSC-JE and RRB JE are same 35400/- (Same grade pay-4200) So salary of both almost same. Starting Gross salary= 44k-46k (with HRA) 2) Job location (Can I live near to home town) SSC-JE (a) If you got CPWD department . Almost Posted in City of state , and Easily got posting in New Delhi (b) If you in MES 40% Chance to got posting in Continue Reading Here my Opinion Move for SSC -JE if you got department like CPWD (Most preferable)/MES (((I am working in CPWD from last 4 years. So , I can give this answer accurately.))) And also I have 6 friends in RRB-Je. #You can compare little bit of JE Post through SSC and RRB-JE #But you can't compare Assistant engineer Post in CPWD/MES, And Senior section Engineer (SSE) in RRB because You have much benefit in AE in CPWD/MES than SSE in RRB. For Junior Engineer 1). SALARY Basic Pay of both SSC-JE and RRB JE are same 35400/- (Same grade pay-4200) So salary of both almost same. Starting Gross salary= 44k-46k (with HRA) 2) Job location (Can I live near to home town) SSC-JE (a) If you got CPWD department . Almost Posted in City of state , and Easily got posting in New Delhi (b) If you in MES 40% Chance to got posting in Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:48:00.345Z"),
    "question" : "Which is better RRB JE or SSC JE and why? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756540c817f0398fbc58e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-was-your-daily-routine-in-the-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Dhiraj Sharma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:48:36.926Z"),
    "question" : "What was your daily routine in the SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756680c817f0398fbc646"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-you-crack-SSC-CGL-2016?-",
    "answer" : "If you have applied for SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination, 2016, then this post in worth reading, as in this post, we will share with you the Detailed Syllabus for SSC CGL 2016.However, if you haven't yet applied for CGL 2016 Exam, then you must first Read the Detailed SSC CGL 2016 Notification As, all of you know, that CGL is one of the highly competitive exams in India, next only to IBPS and SBI Exams. The reason for CGL to be highly competitive is that every year, 2 lakh more students are appearing for this exam. You must read our previous post, in which we have discussed the Cut off for SSC CGL 2016 Exam and you will find how the increasing no. of candidates is making an impact on the Cut off. Another reason for high Competition, is that this Exam can help you is getting Central Go Continue Reading If you have applied for SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination, 2016, then this post in worth reading, as in this post, we will share with you the Detailed Syllabus for SSC CGL 2016.However, if you haven't yet applied for CGL 2016 Exam, then you must first Read the Detailed SSC CGL 2016 Notification As, all of you know, that CGL is one of the highly competitive exams in India, next only to IBPS and SBI Exams. The reason for CGL to be highly competitive is that every year, 2 lakh more students are appearing for this exam. You must read our previous post, in which we have discussed the Cut off for SSC CGL 2016 Exam and you will find how the increasing no. of candidates is making an impact on the Cut off. Another reason for high Competition, is that this Exam can help you is getting Central Go Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:48:56.981Z"),
    "question" : "How can you crack SSC CGL 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037567e0c817f0398fbc659"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-JE?-(Civil)?-",
    "answer" : "Nikhil Ahuja, Nothing like Government Jobs!!Answered 5 years ago · Author has 99 answers and 1.3M answer viewsHow do I prepare for the SSC JE? (Mechanical) Nikhil Ahuja Thanks for A2A!! General Tips -: The first step is to go through the syllabus for the exam on the official website of SSC. This will give you a general idea of the topics you need to prepare. Once you go through the syllabus write down the topics you have absolutely no idea about and try to start preparing these topics first. This will give you more time to prepare topics that you know nothing about instead of keeping these till the end when you might be tempted to completely skip that topic!The next step is to get the appropriate books (List is mentioned in the end) to start your preparation. You need to get the SSC exam books which are designed for the purpose of the SSC exam. Make sure you buy the book for each section of the paper so you do not have to worry about its credibility.It is dContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:49:18.312Z"),
    "question" : "How do i prepare for the ssc je? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756940c817f0398fbc665"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-minimum-percentage-requirement-in-graduation-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "NO minimum marks required.. There is only one basic requirement for SSC CGL that person should complete his/her graduation before the qualifying date. SSC has mentioned 1st aug for the year of notification of Cgl as qualifying date it means you have to get your result announced on or before that day. But in coming time there is change for the qualifying age , it would be 1st Jan of the year of notification but there will be no change in the educational qualification date. ( I am saying this just because SSC has given same thing in the notification of the cgl2015). So There is no minimum marks required for any post through ssc cgl, just study hard and you will get your dream job. Best of luck.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:49:40.126Z"),
    "question" : "What is the minimum percentage requirement in graduation for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756a70c817f0398fbc721"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-test-series-for-SSC-CGL-tier-2?-",
    "answer" : "To perform well in the real exam you should take medium level as well as easy level mocks. Because you don't know what will be the level of paper so keep yourself prepared for any level. For easy mocks take gradeup. These mocks will help you to determine whether your basics are clear or not and how are you performing in the easy mocks. If you are performing good in easy mocks then go for medium level mocks. If you are not performing good in easy level mocks then don't go for medium level mocks as they can demoralize you. First fill loopholes of your preparation so that you can perform better in easy mocks then go for medium level mocks. If you are performing good in easy level mocks then go for medium level mocks like testbook and SSC TUBE. Both are good. If you need good analysis then defini Continue Reading To perform well in the real exam you should take medium level as well as easy level mocks. Because you don't know what will be the level of paper so keep yourself prepared for any level. For easy mocks take gradeup. These mocks will help you to determine whether your basics are clear or not and how are you performing in the easy mocks. If you are performing good in easy mocks then go for medium level mocks. If you are not performing good in easy level mocks then don't go for medium level mocks as they can demoralize you. First fill loopholes of your preparation so that you can perform better in easy mocks then go for medium level mocks. If you are performing good in easy level mocks then go for medium level mocks like testbook and SSC TUBE. Both are good. If you need good analysis then defini Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:49:59.857Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best test series for SSC CGL tier 2? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756bb0c817f0398fbc72d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-SSC-CGL-exam-held?-",
    "answer" : "Brajesh Goyal SSC CGL does not have specific months in which it has to be held. It all depends upon how the last exam was done. Like there are pending cases for SSC CGL 2013 but interviews are going on and they had a re exam in 2014 for 2013 candidates fur to irregularities in the exam in 2013. So you see the exam held in 2013  is stretched till  2015. Now coming to 2014 I gave SSC CGL 2014 in october but still awaiting results for the tier 1 exam. This exam is also being held again at some centers due to some problems. So it is a very uncertain exam better keep it as a option and prepare for some other good exams. Abhishek Verma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:50:19.917Z"),
    "question" : "When is the SSC CGL exam held? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756d10c817f0398fbc739"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-are-you-scoring-in-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-2-2018?-",
    "answer" : "My SSC CGL 2018 journey has been a surprising one. I am a 2014–2018 batch Engineering graduate. A full time UPSC CSE aspirant UPSC CSE 2019 prelims was on 2 nd june. After coming back from exam centre I got some coaching institutes' answer keys,matched options~~ was scoring around 93 from various keys ...so digested the fact that probably my upsc cse 2019 journey ended. CGL 2018 tier 1 exam ... scheduled on 12 th June 1 st shift. only 8 days to prepare for prelims😐 seems tough!!!! after going through some answers on quora and many ssc cgl related websites, bought testbook pass at that night. I made my mind that I would focus on test series only . During those 8 days I managed to solve around 35–40 full tests for tier 1. Daily routine was like : 3 hours for GK (lucent book was new to me 😅) 1–2 hours f Continue Reading My SSC CGL 2018 journey has been a surprising one. I am a 2014–2018 batch Engineering graduate. A full time UPSC CSE aspirant UPSC CSE 2019 prelims was on 2 nd june. After coming back from exam centre I got some coaching institutes' answer keys,matched options~~ was scoring around 93 from various keys ...so digested the fact that probably my upsc cse 2019 journey ended. CGL 2018 tier 1 exam ... scheduled on 12 th June 1 st shift. only 8 days to prepare for prelims😐 seems tough!!!! after going through some answers on quora and many ssc cgl related websites, bought testbook pass at that night. I made my mind that I would focus on test series only . During those 8 days I managed to solve around 35–40 full tests for tier 1. Daily routine was like : 3 hours for GK (lucent book was new to me 😅) 1–2 hours f Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:50:41.391Z"),
    "question" : "How much are you scoring in the SSC CGL Tier 2 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756e40c817f0398fbc7f5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-expected-cut-off-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-2016?-",
    "answer" : "Major constraint in earlier CGL (2015 and before) used to be time. But SSC has increased the time limit this year. Currently 75 minutes are provided for 100 questions, whereas, earlier it used to be 120 minutes for 200 questions. And that is half an hour more time effectively. Also since exam is now online there is no wastage of time in properly marking the bubbles on OMR sheet. Further, this year in CGL 2016 they take your biometric before the exam, earlier they used to waste atleast 2-3 minutes in taking your Left Hand thumb expressions right in middle of the exam. So, in short, time is plenty this year. In CGL 2015 I was able to read only 150 questions and attempted 135. This year I read all 100 questions and attempted 95. General Awareness was the only portion I found to be difficult, r Continue Reading Continue Reading Shailja Agrawal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:51:00.709Z"),
    "question" : "What is the expected cut off for the SSC CGL Tier 1 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603756f70c817f0398fbc800"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-could-be-the-cutoff-of-SSC-CHSL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Hello! Look in chsl 2016 pre cutoff is 127 in general category.questions are pretty tough in 2016 comparing to 2017 ssc chsl in maths,reasoning and English portion and time allotment is 75 mins but this year GS portion is too tough but rest portion is easy but time allotment is 60 mins.  This year acording to me a normal marks attained by majority of the students is :- Reasoning 40-42 Quant 38-40 Eng 34-36 GS 18-22(as this portion is unpredictable and depends on individual) Total 120-130 range. So according to me slight more than 130 is this year cutoff. Thanx!!! Good luck Chaudhary Parveen Pahel",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:51:19.282Z"),
    "question" : "What could be the cutoff of SSC CHSL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037570a0c817f0398fbc80a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-clear-the-SSC-CGL-exam-just-studying-for-two-months?-",
    "answer" : "A big Yes for your answer. You can easily crack this exam in given spitulated time given that you give your soul to the preparation. First of all, know the syllabus of the exam. Exam is divided into 2 tiers basically. Maths and English are common in both the tiers. Here is the strategy and book list that you need to refer and just stick to them religiously. No more asking around. Just stick to these. G.S :- Gs is a vast subject that is hard to cover but is of prime importance as the cut off nowadays are cleared by those who have good g.s, so it can come handy in getting handsome marks. Just stick to 2 books , Lucent Gk and Kiran Past year questions of Gs. Read lucent first and then read Kiran at least twice. You can go for Ratta-fication (learning by heart) for kiran.Maths:- First of all compContinue Reading A big Yes for your answer. You can easily crack this exam in given spitulated time given that you give your soul to the preparation. First of all, know the syllabus of the exam. Exam is divided into 2 tiers basically. Maths and English are common in both the tiers. Here is the strategy and book list that you need to refer and just stick to them religiously. No more asking around. Just stick to these. G.S :- Gs is a vast subject that is hard to cover but is of prime importance as the cut off nowadays are cleared by those who have good g.s, so it can come handy in getting handsome marks. Just stick to 2 books , Lucent Gk and Kiran Past year questions of Gs. Read lucent first and then read Kiran at least twice. You can go for Ratta-fication (learning by heart) for kiran.Maths:- First of all compContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:51:38.651Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to clear the SSC CGL exam just studying for two months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757330c817f0398fbc8d2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-best-salary-offer-in-SSC-chsl?-",
    "answer" : "Shashwat Dubey, ASO (2019-present)Answered August 27, 2020 · Author has 89 answers and 434.7K answer viewsWhat is best salary offer in SSC chsl? Shashwat Dubey SSC CHSL Salary: Post Wise Basic Salary Structure & Grade Pay The SSC CHSL posts come under Pay Level 2 and Pay Level 4. The basic Salary structure for SSC CHSL Posts has been provided in the table given below: 1. Division Clerk (LDC)/Junior Secretariat Assistant (JSA) Pay Level-2 Grade Pay- 1900 Rs. 19,900 – 63,200 In-hand Salary of LDC/JSA Approx In-Hand Salary City X- 28,000 City Y- 25,750 City Z- 23,950 2. Postal Assistant (PA)/Sorting Assistant (SA) Pay Level-4 Grade Pay- 2400 Rs. 25,500 – 81,100 In-hand Salary of PA/SA Approx In-Hand Salary City X- 36,903 City Y- 32,757 City Z- 30,717 3. Data Entry Operator (DEO) Pay Level-4 Grade Pay- 2400 Rs. 25,500 – 81,100 In-hand Salary of DEO Approx In-Hand Salary City X- 36,903 City Y- 32,757 City Z- 30,717 4. Data Entry Operator Grade “A‟ Pay Level-4 Grade Pay- 2400 Rs. 2 Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:52:19.031Z"),
    "question" : "What is best salary offer in SSC chsl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757450c817f0398fbc8dc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-strategy-for-SSC-CGL-2019?-",
    "answer" : "I'm preparing SSC and pursuing my graduation i.e. last year of my graduation . My first & last attempt will be 2019 . Most people suppose SSC CGL is hard to crack and contrary to it some consider it mind game . So don't ask strategy , Everyone know what to do but I'm gonna tell you what not to do in the time of preparation.. don't follow herd mentality i.e. Bhaiya/didi ( who are good in hard working ) can't do this , I can't ….switch on banking or group D or something like that …and last quit .Great follower of teacher , After coming Brand coaching , Most of students become fan i.e. A sir is superstar in maths and after sometimes teacher decided to move on from here to there (next brand ) and posting photos and ad something like and make on impact to do join the coaching where I'm teaching . BContinue Reading I'm preparing SSC and pursuing my graduation i.e. last year of my graduation . My first & last attempt will be 2019 . Most people suppose SSC CGL is hard to crack and contrary to it some consider it mind game . So don't ask strategy , Everyone know what to do but I'm gonna tell you what not to do in the time of preparation.. don't follow herd mentality i.e. Bhaiya/didi ( who are good in hard working ) can't do this , I can't ….switch on banking or group D or something like that …and last quit .Great follower of teacher , After coming Brand coaching , Most of students become fan i.e. A sir is superstar in maths and after sometimes teacher decided to move on from here to there (next brand ) and posting photos and ad something like and make on impact to do join the coaching where I'm teaching . BContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:52:37.208Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my strategy for SSC CGL 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757570c817f0398fbc995"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-Maths-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I prepare Maths for SSC-CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:52:55.306Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare Maths for SSC-CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037576a0c817f0398fbc9a7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-job-in-the-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best job in the SSC CHSL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:53:14.328Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best job in the SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757810c817f0398fbc9b4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-for-UPSC-and-SSC-simultaneously?-",
    "answer" : "Vishnu Gouda Staff Selection Commission - Combined Graduate Level (SSC - CGL) SSC CGL is most sought exam conducted by Staff Selection Commission. The exam is conducted in three phases- Tier-I (Preliminary)Tier-II (Main)Tier-III (Computer Proficiency Test/ Skill Test (wherever applicable)) The other classification of jobs under SSC CGL examination is based on the job profile. Under this classification, there are two types of jobs- Desk JobField Job Essential Qualifications for various posts - I) Assistant Audit Officer: a) Essential Qualifications: Bachelor's Degree from a recognized University or Institute b) Desirable Qualifications: Chartered Accountant or cost & Management Accountant or Company Secretary or Masters in Commerce or Masters in Business Studies or Masters in Business Administration (Finance Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:53:37.733Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare for UPSC and SSC simultaneously? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757970c817f0398fbca6c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-full-form-of-the-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the full form of the SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:53:59.156Z"),
    "question" : "What is the full form of the SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603757ac0c817f0398fbca7e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-an-average-student-clear-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "I think I can answer this one as I too was once an average student. Throughout my school-college days, I was just above average scoring between 70-80% in schools and 55-65% in college. Being from state board student this is just above average. I will not here share a strategy to crack SSC CGL in 100 or so many days. I am sharing something that can make you much above average or something extraordinary. When I started preparing for competitive exams, my Quant was OK OK but my English was terrible. Believe me, I couldn't attempt even 10 que in mocks of pre. Even my score in pre 2017 was 23-24/50. This was back in CGL2017 which I failed by 9 marks in the final list. But then, I started considering this subject a challenge. I knew that many Hindi medium students too have cracked this. If they can, Continue Reading I think I can answer this one as I too was once an average student. Throughout my school-college days, I was just above average scoring between 70-80% in schools and 55-65% in college. Being from state board student this is just above average. I will not here share a strategy to crack SSC CGL in 100 or so many days. I am sharing something that can make you much above average or something extraordinary. When I started preparing for competitive exams, my Quant was OK OK but my English was terrible. Believe me, I couldn't attempt even 10 que in mocks of pre. Even my score in pre 2017 was 23-24/50. This was back in CGL2017 which I failed by 9 marks in the final list. But then, I started considering this subject a challenge. I knew that many Hindi medium students too have cracked this. If they can, Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T07:54:20.660Z"),
    "question" : "How can an average student clear the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769290c817f0398fc0b45"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-expected-cutoff-of-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "A lot of candidates have request about the possibilities of the post they may get in SSC CGL 2018. Here is a brief analysis for UR category candidates. The following points have been considered while determining the expected cutoff of SSC CGL -1018. The analysis is based on trending pattern and also some new changes that have taken place recently. The actual cutoff may vary by some marks depending on various posts and actual vacancies which may vary before final result determination. 1. Normalization: This process was introduced by SSC from the year 2018. As a result of normalization the marks of most of the candidates have increased in both prelims and mains. Its repercussion can be seen in increase in final cutoff of each & every post. 2. No. of Vacancies : The total vacancies for UR categ Continue Reading A lot of candidates have request about the possibilities of the post they may get in SSC CGL 2018. Here is a brief analysis for UR category candidates. The following points have been considered while determining the expected cutoff of SSC CGL -1018. The analysis is based on trending pattern and also some new changes that have taken place recently. The actual cutoff may vary by some marks depending on various posts and actual vacancies which may vary before final result determination. 1. Normalization: This process was introduced by SSC from the year 2018. As a result of normalization the marks of most of the candidates have increased in both prelims and mains. Its repercussion can be seen in increase in final cutoff of each & every post. 2. No. of Vacancies : The total vacancies for UR categ Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:08:57.088Z"),
    "question" : "What is the expected cutoff of SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037693f0c817f0398fc0b5d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-books-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Time and again i have been asked for tips/help/strategy/book list to score well and perform good in the CGL exam. So I decided to write a blog. Here I am writing whatever i followed, see if you can relate to it or not. The things which worked for me , may not work for you. 1. make 1 source for your repeated revision, that may be your class notes or your own notes. I used to add new questions to it whenever I came across one, that may be from some book or test. 2. I focused on 3 areas which I assumed would be crucial for scoring good according to me.. concepts>accuracy>speed and I mastered them in the same order. 3. I gave mock tests..lots of them..in the month prior to exam I used to give avg around 3-4 mock tests/week. I may or may not score well in them but I used to track my performance an Continue Reading Time and again i have been asked for tips/help/strategy/book list to score well and perform good in the CGL exam. So I decided to write a blog. Here I am writing whatever i followed, see if you can relate to it or not. The things which worked for me , may not work for you. 1. make 1 source for your repeated revision, that may be your class notes or your own notes. I used to add new questions to it whenever I came across one, that may be from some book or test. 2. I focused on 3 areas which I assumed would be crucial for scoring good according to me.. concepts>accuracy>speed and I mastered them in the same order. 3. I gave mock tests..lots of them..in the month prior to exam I used to give avg around 3-4 mock tests/week. I may or may not score well in them but I used to track my performance an Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:09:19.628Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best books for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037696c0c817f0398fc0c36"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-good-online-mock-test-series-for-SSC-CGL-Tier-2-2016?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are some good online mock test series for SSC CGL Tier 2 2016?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:10:04.417Z"),
    "question" : "What are some good online mock test series for SSC CGL Tier 2 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037697e0c817f0398fc0c44"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-present-status-of-the-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Swati Gupta  SSC CGL 2018 tier-1 is highly expected to take place as per schedule, ie. 4th June onward. So, put your preparation in highest gear. Edit : Official Notification has been published by SSC. Exam on time and is starting from 4/6/2019 onward. https://ssc.nic.in/SSCFileServer/PortalManagement/UploadedFiles/Important_Notice_CGL_2018_09052019.pdf  Good Luck",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:10:22.084Z"),
    "question" : "What is the present status of the SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769920c817f0398fc0c58"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-tough-it-is-to-crack-ssc-cgl-in-first-attempt?-",
    "answer" : "No. of your attempts does not make much of a difference . Each attempt is a new journey. What matters is the depth of your preparation. So if you have been preparing dedicatedly for CGL you can clear it. I started preparing for CGL from 1 Jan 2016 . Prepared on my own by solving previous year papers and reading the Hindu religiously. On 7th July I joined a prestigious coaching institute with the target of CGL 2017. I kept preparing myself for cgl 16 and also attended coaching classes for 2017. My tier 1 paper was on 27 Aug , 3rd shift. Due to technical issues (server was not saving responses to questions asked in exam), SSC decided to take a retest. In the meantime I had started preparing for tier 2 as I was optimistic about my chances but now I had to refocus on tier 1. I switched gears accordi Continue Reading No. of your attempts does not make much of a difference . Each attempt is a new journey. What matters is the depth of your preparation. So if you have been preparing dedicatedly for CGL you can clear it. I started preparing for CGL from 1 Jan 2016 . Prepared on my own by solving previous year papers and reading the Hindu religiously. On 7th July I joined a prestigious coaching institute with the target of CGL 2017. I kept preparing myself for cgl 16 and also attended coaching classes for 2017. My tier 1 paper was on 27 Aug , 3rd shift. Due to technical issues (server was not saving responses to questions asked in exam), SSC decided to take a retest. In the meantime I had started preparing for tier 2 as I was optimistic about my chances but now I had to refocus on tier 1. I switched gears accordi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:10:42.555Z"),
    "question" : "How tough it is to crack ssc cgl in first attempt? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769a40c817f0398fc0d1b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-highest-salary-of-an-SSC-CGL-officer?-",
    "answer" : "Salary of the SSC CGL officer depends on your post group. For SSC CGL officers there are two groups: Group B - Highest salary Group C - Lower salary Highest salary post in SSC CGL is for Assistant Audit officer (AAO) which is the only gazetted post in posts offered by SSCCGL . Salary structure is : Pay band- 9300–34800 Initial salary - 30K+ Gross salary - 54,864 – 61,424 Promotions - After 6 to 10 years,(Gr. B Gazetted- GP-5400) Other Posts with lavish salary - Income tax assistantCBI Inspector - He gets salary of 13 months in a year.Junior statistical officer(JSO)Preventive inspectorCentral excise inspector.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:00.616Z"),
    "question" : "What is the highest salary of an SSC CGL officer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769b80c817f0398fc0d2d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-SSC-CGL-exam-via-self-study?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I crack the SSC CGL exam via self-study?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:20.154Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack the SSC CGL exam via self-study? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769cb0c817f0398fc0d41"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-minimum-percentage-required-to-apply-for-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "The minimum percentage that is required to appear for the SSC CHSL is described in the eligibility criteria for the SSC CHSL exam. The eligibility criteria for the SSC CHSL or the Combined Higher Secondary Level Recruitment Process, conducted by the Staff Selection Commission is mentioned below: Eligibility Criteria for the SSC CHSL Exam You should have successfully completed class 12 or its equivalent from any recognized education boardSuccessfully completion here means that you should have obtained a score that is equal to or over the minimum pass percentage which in most boards is 50% of the total score.Note: You can also apply for the SSC CHSL if you are appearing for the class 12 exams or its equivalent qualification this year. If you qualify for any job profile, your employment will b Continue Reading The minimum percentage that is required to appear for the SSC CHSL is described in the eligibility criteria for the SSC CHSL exam. The eligibility criteria for the SSC CHSL or the Combined Higher Secondary Level Recruitment Process, conducted by the Staff Selection Commission is mentioned below: Eligibility Criteria for the SSC CHSL Exam You should have successfully completed class 12 or its equivalent from any recognized education boardSuccessfully completion here means that you should have obtained a score that is equal to or over the minimum pass percentage which in most boards is 50% of the total score.Note: You can also apply for the SSC CHSL if you are appearing for the class 12 exams or its equivalent qualification this year. If you qualify for any job profile, your employment will b Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:39.963Z"),
    "question" : "What is the minimum percentage required to apply for SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603769de0c817f0398fc0dfd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-most-corrupt-job-profile-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "I'll list here most powerful jobs of SSC CGL and discuss the reason that makes them powerful and resultantly corrupt.  AAO - Assistant Auditing Officer - 4800 Grade Pay - very powerful as you will audit the government departments and policies - you will have a direct contact with Ministers - you will be hardly busy in a normal office day but raids and audits usually take a couple of days - Ministers and Government Authorities won't directly bribe you but during raids and audits, they will arrange a 5-star hotel stay for you and much more - direct contact with ministers might be a stroke of fortune  ITI - Income Tax Inspector - 4600 Grade Pay - usually a busy day in metro cities - very much respect in society - just show your ID card and business owners will be fawning over you Continue Reading I'll list here most powerful jobs of SSC CGL and discuss the reason that makes them powerful and resultantly corrupt.  AAO - Assistant Auditing Officer - 4800 Grade Pay - very powerful as you will audit the government departments and policies - you will have a direct contact with Ministers - you will be hardly busy in a normal office day but raids and audits usually take a couple of days - Ministers and Government Authorities won't directly bribe you but during raids and audits, they will arrange a 5-star hotel stay for you and much more - direct contact with ministers might be a stroke of fortune  ITI - Income Tax Inspector - 4600 Grade Pay - usually a busy day in metro cities - very much respect in society - just show your ID card and business owners will be fawning over you Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:11:58.102Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the most corrupt job profile in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a050c817f0398fc0e23"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-can-I-download-SSC-CGL-old-question-papers?-",
    "answer" : "Vishal Singh  There are many good books available in the market for CGL..If you are a beginner, start with any book that will clear all the basics and then buy a practice book in which they solve the previous year papers..For Aptitude I suggest Quantum CAT/Fast Track Arithmetic or any other as per your convenience.. For English either SP Bakshi/Plinth to Paramount.. Then Practice with Kiran's sets.. Now a days they are giving chapter wise solved papers (Advanced maths) as well and that will be very useful.. Though you can find many videos for CGL on YouTube, but I think they are of not much useful but waste of time.. Better practice from good books.. CGL is all about Speed and accuracy and you will get it by more and more practice...",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:12:37.054Z"),
    "question" : "Where can I download SSC CGL old question papers? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a1a0c817f0398fc0ee5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-syllabus-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Hello SSC CGL Exam conducted in four tiers, which are given below: Tier 1 - Preliminary Exam Tier 2 - Mains Exam Tier 3 - Descriptive Paper Tier 4 - Skill Test/ Computer Proficiency Test/ Interview/ Document Verification SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus are: SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for General Intelligence and Reasoning Syllogism, Seating Arrangement, Blood Relation, Directions, Coding-Decoding, Statements and Conclusions, Statements and Assumptions, Analogy, Ranking, Series Problems, Non-Verbal Reasoning SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for General Awareness History & Culture, Economic Scene, General Policy, Scientific Research, Biology, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Section, Current Affairs, Current GK, Books and Authors, Persons and Place in News, Abbreviation SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for Quantitative  Continue Reading Hello SSC CGL Exam conducted in four tiers, which are given below: Tier 1 - Preliminary Exam Tier 2 - Mains Exam Tier 3 - Descriptive Paper Tier 4 - Skill Test/ Computer Proficiency Test/ Interview/ Document Verification SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus are: SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for General Intelligence and Reasoning Syllogism, Seating Arrangement, Blood Relation, Directions, Coding-Decoding, Statements and Conclusions, Statements and Assumptions, Analogy, Ranking, Series Problems, Non-Verbal Reasoning SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for General Awareness History & Culture, Economic Scene, General Policy, Scientific Research, Biology, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Section, Current Affairs, Current GK, Books and Authors, Persons and Place in News, Abbreviation SSC CGL Tier 1 Syllabus 2017 for Quantitative  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:12:58.254Z"),
    "question" : "What is the syllabus for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a2c0c817f0398fc0efa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-provides-tier-2-maths-question-bank-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Tushar Sharma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:16.804Z"),
    "question" : "Which book provides tier 2 maths question bank for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a410c817f0398fc0f0f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-the-timetable-to-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-for-a-working-aspirant?-",
    "answer" : "SSC CGL is the most competitive exams right now as it welcomes aspirants from every field to get in the competition. Also it gives you a decent salary with a pay-grade between 4200–4800 at entry level (for inspector and officer post) that makes jobs from it desirable for an average student. Now before starting the preparation for CGL one must analyse the pattern thoroughly, in which for pre and mains you have Maths and English as common subjects that's makes a total of 500 out of 600 when you combine the total marks for pre and mains, and rest 100 adds up equally from GK and APTITUDE. So your main focus should be Maths and English. Maths: 1: If you are not good at maths, start with NCERT, understand the basics concepts, this will help you even if you miss the tricks for a particular question.  Continue Reading SSC CGL is the most competitive exams right now as it welcomes aspirants from every field to get in the competition. Also it gives you a decent salary with a pay-grade between 4200–4800 at entry level (for inspector and officer post) that makes jobs from it desirable for an average student. Now before starting the preparation for CGL one must analyse the pattern thoroughly, in which for pre and mains you have Maths and English as common subjects that's makes a total of 500 out of 600 when you combine the total marks for pre and mains, and rest 100 adds up equally from GK and APTITUDE. So your main focus should be Maths and English. Maths: 1: If you are not good at maths, start with NCERT, understand the basics concepts, this will help you even if you miss the tricks for a particular question.  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:37.814Z"),
    "question" : "What should be the timetable to prepare for the SSC CGL for a working aspirant? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a550c817f0398fc0fcf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-SSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "All you need to know about SSC-CHSLWho conducts it?Staff Selection Commission (SSC) (Hindi: कर्मचारीचयनआयोग) is a GOVT OF INDIA organization to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices. Exam conducted by SSC 1-SSC(CHSL) 2- SSC(CGL) 3-SSC (CPO)EligibilityA candidate must have attained the age of 18 years and must not have attained the age of 27 years as on 01-08-2015. *There are relaxations for various categories such as Defence Personnel, SC/ST, etc.Scheme of Examination The examination will consist of a Written Examination and Skill Test for the post of Data Entry Operator and Written Test and Typing Test for the post of Postal Assistant/ Sorting Assistant & Lower Division Clerk on Computer. Writ Continue Reading All you need to know about SSC-CHSLWho conducts it?Staff Selection Commission (SSC) (Hindi: कर्मचारीचयनआयोग) is a GOVT OF INDIA organization to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices. Exam conducted by SSC 1-SSC(CHSL) 2- SSC(CGL) 3-SSC (CPO)EligibilityA candidate must have attained the age of 18 years and must not have attained the age of 27 years as on 01-08-2015. *There are relaxations for various categories such as Defence Personnel, SC/ST, etc.Scheme of Examination The examination will consist of a Written Examination and Skill Test for the post of Data Entry Operator and Written Test and Typing Test for the post of Postal Assistant/ Sorting Assistant & Lower Division Clerk on Computer. Writ Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:13:57.502Z"),
    "question" : "What is the SSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a6b0c817f0398fc0fe7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-improve-my-English-for-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Arjun Singh, Inspector at Income Tax in India (2015-present)Answered 2 years ago · Author has 148 answers and 1.5M answer viewsHow can I improve my English for SSC CGL exam? Arjun Singh How to Strengthen your English? What’s the Best Approach? 1.Take English Seriously You are not able to get good marks in English simply because you are not taking it seriously. It is important for all competitive exams so take it seriously. If you don’t have any English Grammar book yet, Purchase either of the two mentioned below. Objective General English by S.P BakshiEnglish for General Competition(Plinth to Paramount)Go through the Grammar rules more than once and practice(it’s really important to practice). Once done, go through One Word Substitution, Idioms & Phrases, Phrasal Verbs & Antonyms/Synonyms. You must give at least 1-2 hour daily to English. 2.Read Newspapers Daily SSC does not ask for very high flowing words but you must be sure of the usage of the word and how it is used in sen Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:14:19.306Z"),
    "question" : "How can I improve my English for SSC CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a830c817f0398fc0ffa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-start-preparing-for-sSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Vikram Kumar Gupta",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:14:43.001Z"),
    "question" : "How do I start preparing for sSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376a960c817f0398fc10be"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-SSC-exam-tough?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is SSC exam tough?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:15:02.818Z"),
    "question" : "Is SSC exam tough? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376abb0c817f0398fc10e1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-post-in-the-SSC-CGL-for-ladies?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the best post in the SSC CGL for ladies?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:15:39.306Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best post in the SSC CGL for ladies? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ae20c817f0398fc11b3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-expected-cutoffs-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-in-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Last year cutoff was 137 Level was easy. Let us compare cgl 2016 prelims and cgl 2017 prelims Reasoning- more or less ,same level. Maths- in 2016 it was much simpler,less calculative,DI part was giving you free marks but totally opposite this year,exam is calculative tricky and DI part wont give you brownie points anymore.Also,time factor.last year we got 15 extra minutes. English- again last year it was a scoring section because of reading comprehension. An easy story followed by candy questions. Rest more or less,is the same G.S- almost same as last year. So overall this year, paper was calculative,tricky and lengthy, compared last year with 15 less minutes. So logically keeping reasoning and gs as constants and maths,english as variables with less time Cutoff would be around 118 (+-5) for unres Continue Reading Last year cutoff was 137 Level was easy. Let us compare cgl 2016 prelims and cgl 2017 prelims Reasoning- more or less ,same level. Maths- in 2016 it was much simpler,less calculative,DI part was giving you free marks but totally opposite this year,exam is calculative tricky and DI part wont give you brownie points anymore.Also,time factor.last year we got 15 extra minutes. English- again last year it was a scoring section because of reading comprehension. An easy story followed by candy questions. Rest more or less,is the same G.S- almost same as last year. So overall this year, paper was calculative,tricky and lengthy, compared last year with 15 less minutes. So logically keeping reasoning and gs as constants and maths,english as variables with less time Cutoff would be around 118 (+-5) for unres Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:16:18.572Z"),
    "question" : "What are the expected cutoffs for the SSC CGL Tier 1 in 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376af60c817f0398fc11c3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-Tier-3-result-of-SSC-CGL-2017-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:16:38.733Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for SSC CGL tier 3? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b0c0c817f0398fc1289"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-mock-tests-are-good-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "This answer would be purely a personal opinion and i won’t generalise things. so i have joined two test series-top rankers in collaboration with paramount and the other one is of career power ssc adda.I found both of them of the same difficulty level and my marks in both of them hover around 150. the actual benefit i get from these two test series is to curb my overconfidence.i am always overconfident of my prep and get lax that i have read everything and cgl is easy but only after i give the tests i realise my actual preperation .so tests which are easy such as of ssctube and testbook won’t help u if ssc prepares difficult sets and a panic situation might arrive in the exam hall. where as the test series should not be so tough that it just breaks ur confidence and brings ur score to 110–120.  Continue Reading This answer would be purely a personal opinion and i won’t generalise things. so i have joined two test series-top rankers in collaboration with paramount and the other one is of career power ssc adda.I found both of them of the same difficulty level and my marks in both of them hover around 150. the actual benefit i get from these two test series is to curb my overconfidence.i am always overconfident of my prep and get lax that i have read everything and cgl is easy but only after i give the tests i realise my actual preperation .so tests which are easy such as of ssctube and testbook won’t help u if ssc prepares difficult sets and a panic situation might arrive in the exam hall. where as the test series should not be so tough that it just breaks ur confidence and brings ur score to 110–120.  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:17:00.333Z"),
    "question" : "Which mock tests are good for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b460c817f0398fc1369"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-SSC-CGL-2019-going-to-be-conducted?-",
    "answer" : "Mahi, Counselor at Study Sector (2015-present)Answered 1 year ago · Author has 267 answers and 275.8K answer viewsWhen is the SSC CGL 2019 going to be conducted? Mahi SSC CGL is considered to be one of the biggest examinations to be conducted for graduate students in India. SSC conducts SSC CGL every year to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in its Subordinate Offices. As per the calendar of SSC Exams 2019-20, SSC CGL 2019 Recruitment Notification has been released on 22nd October 2019. SSC CGL 2019-20 Recruitment Process has started with the release of its official notification. Lets take a look at the SSC Calendar 2019-20 to get a brief on the upcoming SSC CGL 2019 Exam. SSC CGL 2019 Notification Release Date 22nd October 2019 SSC CGL 2019 Online Application Starts on 22nd October 2019 and  if you want all important information about ssc cgl so dont forget to wa Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:17:58.971Z"),
    "question" : "When is the SSC CGL 2019 going to be conducted? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b5a0c817f0398fc1381"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Who-can-I-learn-English-better-from-on-YouTube-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Yamini Gupta English in SSC is easier as compared to other competitive exams like CAT. They just check your basic understanding of the language. On the other hand, you cannot neglect it as weightage of English is about 40% (250/600) 250 marks (50 pre +200 mains). My advice would be to avoid YouTube channels for preparing English. English needs practice and revision. Read grammar rules. Once. Twice. Make short notes of the rules you often forget. Learn rules of active-passive, direct - indirect. Read newspaper. Work on your speed of reading and understanding. Read books. Highlight new words. Observe there usage. For vocab- Learn few words daily and maintain a copy to revise. Learn Idioms and try to use them in day to day life. Give mocks and analyse which part of it needs to be improve. Go through the previous ye Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:18:18.944Z"),
    "question" : "Who can I learn English better from on YouTube for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376b730c817f0398fc1398"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-study-for-the-General-Awareness-section-of-the-SSC-CGL-2017-from-a-beginner-level?-",
    "answer" : "Anurag Chaudhary, Cleared SSC CGL 2014Answered 4 years ago · Author has 114 answers and 1.6M answer viewsHow do I study for the General Awareness section of the SSC CGL 2017 from a beginner level? Anurag Chaudhary This is one of the most frequent query, I keep getting from aspirants. SSC CGL Tier 1 has 4 sections i.e Reasoning, General Awareness, Quantitative Aptitude and English. Let’s discuss about General Awareness section: This is the most vague section and all questions are of factual nature with very diverse background. Question which are asked in this section are of very useless nature. How to prepare for this section: My advice to aspirants is “Please don’t waste your time and energy for preparing this section”. First, get hold of Quantitative (Maths) and English to perfection (it will help you in Tier II also). If your ultimate goal is Civil Services, then Please go through NCERTs of Social Studies and Science (from 6th to 10th standard) while preapring for SSC. It will be very helpful to you in  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:18:43.187Z"),
    "question" : "How do I study for the General Awareness section of the SSC CGL 2017 from a beginner level? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ba00c817f0398fc146d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-for-SSC-CGL-in-Jaipur?-",
    "answer" : "Coaching For SSC CGL I Study Center Academy(Daily Test Series for practice) II MOTHERS (Batch) Lots of students searching \"Best Coaching For ssc cgl\" \"I would like to suggest all coaching searching students you have follow this steps before searching coaching\" Your basics Who wants to prepare for ssc je like exam and wants join \"ssc cgl coaching\" first check about your basics, what does it means? Basic concepts required to qualify this exam. It should be so clear that you can. How to clear basics? Step-1 Self Study- We think that most powerful method to prepare is Self study. All successful students are good in self study. Step-2 Under the Guidance of Experienced person- You can start your preparation under any of your qualified relative or Friends so that you can get proper idea about the exam. you  Continue Reading Coaching For SSC CGL I Study Center Academy(Daily Test Series for practice) II MOTHERS (Batch) Lots of students searching \"Best Coaching For ssc cgl\" \"I would like to suggest all coaching searching students you have follow this steps before searching coaching\" Your basics Who wants to prepare for ssc je like exam and wants join \"ssc cgl coaching\" first check about your basics, what does it means? Basic concepts required to qualify this exam. It should be so clear that you can. How to clear basics? Step-1 Self Study- We think that most powerful method to prepare is Self study. All successful students are good in self study. Step-2 Under the Guidance of Experienced person- You can start your preparation under any of your qualified relative or Friends so that you can get proper idea about the exam. you  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:19:28.760Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching for SSC-CGL in Jaipur? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bb50c817f0398fc1487"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-most-respectful-and-powerful-post-after-clearing-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Rahul Pratap Singh, DA in U.P. via CGL13.Answered 4 years ago · Author has 71 answers and 822.4K answer viewsWhich is the most respectful and powerful post after clearing SSC CGL? Rahul Pratap Singh This is staff level commission afterall , so abnormally high expectations will be futile ! So coming down to some most talked about posts of CGL is terms of respect ( inside and outside office ) , authority (not power as power is a negative term) , social recognition and ability to make an impact on society…. 1. Examiners in CBEC: They enjoy fair amount of authority in the ports as they are highest level examining official on field. They enjoy good amount of discretion. Promotion is very fast and work is adventure filled. Only minus is coastal posting lifetime. 2. CBI SI: Needless to say anything to anyone when you say you work in CBI. Work is adventure filled and lot if challenges . Training is rigorous and promotion is fast. 3. ITI : Most sought after post in CGL as because of its social rec Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:19:49.373Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the most respectful and powerful post after clearing SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bdb0c817f0398fc1555"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-starting-salary-of-SSC-stenographer-grade-C?-",
    "answer" : "Vikram Kumar Gupta In short and transparent way… SSC Steno exam offers grade C(Group B) called PA & grade D(Group C) called stenographer Grade and group r two different words..some new person due to lack of knowledge speak ssc stenographer group c and stenographer group d instead of ssc stenographer grade c and stenographer Grade d that is absolutely wrong.,.see from SSC notification  1:Grade C is Group B post with grade pay 4200/4600********”Salary 4600gp —…basic pay( 44900)+HRA+TA+DA+DA on TA+others…..after all allowance and deductions salary in hand will be 57300 in x city@ revised DA 9% to start with 4200gp___basic pay (35400) +HRA+ TA+DA+DA on TA+others ….after all allowance and deductions salary in hand will be 46.5k in X city to start with Your salary will be increased by 3% every year . and also Dearness a Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:20:27.712Z"),
    "question" : "What is the starting salary of SSC stenographer grade C? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376bf10c817f0398fc156d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-the-preference-of-posts-in-ssc-cgl?-",
    "answer" : "What should be the preference of post in SSC CGL? Well, this is a million dollar question. Choosing a post is even more difficult then choosing a life partner these days. Anyways. Based on my personal experience and interaction with large number of already serving officers, let me present a reality check. . Before answering this question, let's first list down the factors that differentiate one post from the other:- Social recognitionSalaryPromotionsPeace of mindTransfersHome stateAdditional illegal perksNow let's decode all the factors one by one. Social recognition/Status/Respect:- There are two aspects of this. First is respect inside the office, second is respect outside the office. The general rule of thumb is that almost all the entry level posts in SSC CGL has no respect inside the officeContinue Reading What should be the preference of post in SSC CGL? Well, this is a million dollar question. Choosing a post is even more difficult then choosing a life partner these days. Anyways. Based on my personal experience and interaction with large number of already serving officers, let me present a reality check. . Before answering this question, let's first list down the factors that differentiate one post from the other:- Social recognitionSalaryPromotionsPeace of mindTransfersHome stateAdditional illegal perksNow let's decode all the factors one by one. Social recognition/Status/Respect:- There are two aspects of this. First is respect inside the office, second is respect outside the office. The general rule of thumb is that almost all the entry level posts in SSC CGL has no respect inside the officeContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:20:49.912Z"),
    "question" : "What should be the preference of posts in ssc cgl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c040c817f0398fc1629"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-struggle-for-the-duration-of-preparation-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Subhadip Debnath To begin with, it wasn’t a struggle. It was an experience. An experience which had its fair share of ups and downs, but an experience nonetheless. So let’s get on with the story now. June, 2015I was just done with the final exams of my last semester of graduation and was awaiting results. Meanwhile, I had already appeared (literally just used to appear at the exam centres without any preparation whatsoever) for various management exams like CAT, XAT, MAT and CMAT, and these were the percentile scores that followed ( although I don’t remember the exact figures) :- CAT - 74XAT - 70 MAT - 98 (I still don’t know how, probably the cream already got selected through CAT and XAT so didn’t bother to appear)CMAT - 97 (again I think because of the reason mentioned above) I had already applied to a f Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:21:08.502Z"),
    "question" : "What is your struggle for the duration of preparation for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c180c817f0398fc163b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-score-170+-in-English-in-SSC-CGL-tier-2?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How did you score 170+ in English in SSC CGL tier 2?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:21:28.375Z"),
    "question" : "How did you score 170+ in English in SSC CGL tier 2? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c2c0c817f0398fc164f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-book-for-SSC-MTS?-",
    "answer" : "Rajesh Kumar See.. hard work and study with the help of right resources can definitely help you to crack out any exam. I can share a good study plan with you. Just follow that in a right way and be consistent with your study. Never loose hope. Just be focused upon your goal or dream whichever you want to accomplish. Topics to focus :- Number Systems, Computation of Whole Numbers, Decimals and Fractions and relationship between Numbers, Fundamental arithmetical operations, Percentages, Ratio and Proportion, Averages, Interest, Profit and Loss, Discount, use of Tables and Graphs, Mensuration, Time and Distance, Ratio and Time, Time and Work, etc. SSC MTS English Language Tips: Questions on English Language will be simple, of a level that an average matriculate will be in a position to answer comfortably. In thContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:21:48.587Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best book for SSC MTS? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c400c817f0398fc1711"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-SSC-CGL-2020-be-conducted?-",
    "answer" : "Deepak Kumar Tiwary, 191.85/200 (English, T2 CGL 18)Updated 1 year ago · Author has 362 answers and 1.2M answer viewsWhen will SSC CGL 2020 be conducted? Deepak Kumar Tiwary No one can say this for now. But one can guess based on some logic. For now, SSC CGL 2017 is pending due to dependency on SC's hearing. If it is cancelled, SSC will have to conduct re-exam. Let's put aside the CGL 2017 for now. Looking at the current trends of SSC notification, CGL 2018(Tier 1) is expected to be conducted in April 2019. Tier 2 + Tier 3 may take time up to Nov 2019. Here we are considering the fact that there won't be further any delay due to unseen/unfortunate issues like cheating and all. Now there are below possibilities. Release of CGL 2019 around May 2019: This is highly impossible given the current situation. CGL 2018 is still pending, CGL 2017 re-exam may be conducted.Combination of CGL 2019 and CGL 2020: SSC can take this step. First it will try to close CGL 2017 and 20Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:22:08.613Z"),
    "question" : "When will SSC CGL 2020 be conducted? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c530c817f0398fc1723"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-top-10-coaching-centers-for-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are top 10 coaching centers for SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:22:27.536Z"),
    "question" : "What are top 10 coaching centers for SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c650c817f0398fc1736"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-clear-the-SSC-CGL-tier-1-2016-within-2-months?-",
    "answer" : "If you are interested and dedicated, and want to clear CGL, and there is only 2 months to go, and have 6-7 hours for this, this answer is for you and you only. There's not enough time to cover everything, so we'll focus on Tier 1 only.  Time - March + April Hours - 7 hours/DayTarget Score - 135-140 (General) Maths- 40-42English- 35-36Reasoning- 40-42GK- 20-25Books: SSC CGL Math, topic wise, Kiran Pub. SSC CGL Tier1 & 2 Solved Papers kiran pub. Lucent GK SSC CGL English MB/Kiran Pub. 1 March - 20 March Finish Maths. All the topic. Start from the most important one and move to least important one. Solve as many questions as you can in this periods. Learn Formulas and tricks too. You can't swallow everything so learn whatever you can. 21 March - 15 April  Now is the time to focus on GK (3 hours Continue Reading If you are interested and dedicated, and want to clear CGL, and there is only 2 months to go, and have 6-7 hours for this, this answer is for you and you only. There's not enough time to cover everything, so we'll focus on Tier 1 only.  Time - March + April Hours - 7 hours/DayTarget Score - 135-140 (General) Maths- 40-42English- 35-36Reasoning- 40-42GK- 20-25Books: SSC CGL Math, topic wise, Kiran Pub. SSC CGL Tier1 & 2 Solved Papers kiran pub. Lucent GK SSC CGL English MB/Kiran Pub. 1 March - 20 March Finish Maths. All the topic. Start from the most important one and move to least important one. Solve as many questions as you can in this periods. Learn Formulas and tricks too. You can't swallow everything so learn whatever you can. 21 March - 15 April  Now is the time to focus on GK (3 hours Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:22:45.702Z"),
    "question" : "How can I clear the SSC CGL tier-1 2016 within 2 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376c9d0c817f0398fc1818"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-test-series-is-good-for-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1?-",
    "answer" : "Swati Gupta Hello SSC has released its official notification for CGL 2018 which is scheduled to be conducted on 25th july 2018 . There are chances that the exam can get postponed but it will be conducted and you should be well prepared for it. When it comes to such examinations , first and foremost thing to score well is attempting mock tests as you can analyse your performance and get a knowledge of your weak and strong areas so that you can work on them and do the needful . Now coming to your question , for test series you should go with adda247 test series . We have launched a SSC CGL PRIME 2018 which will suffice your needs. You will be getting a detailed video solutions for each test along with the complete performance analysis to help you out with clearing the examination with good marks and gett Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:23:41.204Z"),
    "question" : "Which test series is good for the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376caf0c817f0398fc18d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-SSC-CGL-coaching-institutes-in-Bangalore?-",
    "answer" : "Take Online coaching at Vidya Guru institution. That is the best resource because their teachers are really good. Along with that their Online channel has also worked well for me. I really like their youtube lectures and most of them have to-the-point explanations and those points come in Exam as well. Vidya Guru Math and Reasoning teachers are really the best and they have more than 15 years of experience. I really liked their teaching during my preparation period. I have learned lots of shortcut tricks which helped me attempting the maximum questions for Math, Reasoning, and GK as well. Everything remained really good there. Vidya Guru teachers have the complete SSC preparation easy for me. I never ever imagined that SSC preparation would become so easy for me. They charged a reasonable  Continue Reading Take Online coaching at Vidya Guru institution. That is the best resource because their teachers are really good. Along with that their Online channel has also worked well for me. I really like their youtube lectures and most of them have to-the-point explanations and those points come in Exam as well. Vidya Guru Math and Reasoning teachers are really the best and they have more than 15 years of experience. I really liked their teaching during my preparation period. I have learned lots of shortcut tricks which helped me attempting the maximum questions for Math, Reasoning, and GK as well. Everything remained really good there. Vidya Guru teachers have the complete SSC preparation easy for me. I never ever imagined that SSC preparation would become so easy for me. They charged a reasonable  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:23:59.263Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best SSC CGL coaching institutes in Bangalore? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cc10c817f0398fc18eb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1-paper?-",
    "answer" : "Mohak Chaudhary, former Operations Executive at Infosys Limited (2016-2018)Answered 1 year agoHow was the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1 paper? Mohak Chaudhary I left my IT job 18 months ago with a sole aim of getting a post under SSC CGL . Every thing was going well until yesterday; I was able to score 105/120 in RPF SI, 172/200 CPO, 96.45% CAT(maths-98.8) and was countiously scoring 150–160 in the mocks. I had my exam on 7th June and had analysed previous shifts’ exams before appearing. In one of the mocks based on 4th June shift I was able to score 157/200. I was pretty confident of hitting a score around 150 . All youtube analysts were advising to start with English and GS sections, but I had given over 150+ mocks starting my exam with quant so I decided not to change my stratergy at the last moment and that worked like a nail in the coffin. I started my exam with maths section and the pattern was unprecedented, I could only attempt 3–4 questi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:17.573Z"),
    "question" : "How was the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1 paper? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cd30c817f0398fc18f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-YouTube-channel-for-aptitude-for-SSC-preparation-in-English?-",
    "answer" : "Sakshi Ahuja, B.Com from University of Delhi (2016)Answered October 3, 2020 · Author has 117 answers and 168.4K answer viewsWhich is the best YouTube channel for aptitude for SSC preparation in English? Sakshi Ahuja English is a language subject in SSC. In English, we need to improve our vocabulary & grammar to crack the exam. So, self study and read English newspaper to improve vocabulary is very necessary. And also the best coaching and guidance is also necessary. So I suggest you to join Vidya Guru for the best coaching of English. Their English Teacher Sonia ma’am’s videos are really good. She explains the topic in a perfect way. She has a good command of the English language. My English is not good before joined the Vidya Guru, but now I improve very much with the help of Sonia Madam. She is very friendly in nature & teaches very well. Her way of explaining is very fab. She guides us also. You must subscribe to her youtube channel for the relevant videos to learn the SSC exam relevant English sect Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:35.264Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best YouTube channel for aptitude for SSC preparation in English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ce70c817f0398fc19ba"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-you-share-your-marks-of-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Rajat Kumar Singh Hey! I hope everyone is doing well. Coming to the topic, I have scored rather poorly in CGL 18. The prime reason for my poor performance is that I am not a serious candidate for SSC. I was preparing for SSC on a part-time basis because I was studying for my MA History. Also, I am a web developer and had to constantly do my coding alongside. Hence, it is pretty evident that I lacked consistency for SSC CGL. With that being said, let’s move on to my scorecards. Tier-1  I started my preparation just a month before prelims. So, I was obviously too far behind than everyone. I had to make the most out of these 30 days. So, I studied only the concepts for the first week. From the next week onwards, I started giving mock tests. All in all, I gave around 40 full mock tests for prelims. Over the cours Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:24:55.023Z"),
    "question" : "Can you share your marks of SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376cf90c817f0398fc19d0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-exam-is-easy-SSC-vs-bank-PO?-",
    "answer" : "Shivamm Bansal Dear Friend First and foremost let's talk about the numbers. In SSC there are approximately 10,000 vacancies each year and around 15 lakh candidates appear for Tier-1 exam. In Bank PO, there approx. 8000 vacancies by IBPS and 2000 by SBI. So, again 10,000 vacancies and again about 15 lakh job seekers are there. Hence, no clear winner here. Let's look at the exam pattern then. In SSC CGL, the exam pattern is as follows: Tier-1 100 questions in 75 minutes. Tier-2 100 questions for maths and 200 for English in 4 hours Tier-3 Essay and letter writing in one hour for 100 marks. Negative marking: yes For BANK PO, the pattern​ is : Prelims: 100 questions in 1 hour Mains: 200 questions in 2 hours and 20 minutes. Interview: I believe that it is of 100 marks Negative marking: yes Again, it appears to be a tie. Let's Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:25:13.139Z"),
    "question" : "Which exam is easy SSC vs bank PO? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d0b0c817f0398fc19e0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-your-views-about-SSC-CGL-scam?-",
    "answer" : "Abhishek Chaudhary I will write each and every aspect of it:- Exam conducting Vendor:- The vendor conducting SSC exams is SIFY. It has got huge and jeopardized software and server. Many a times student face no response of the system, the machine gets hang. Seeing that even 1 mark counts, it is certainly a grave problem. SSC must look for other vendor.Paper Leak:- Definitely there is paper leak. There are solvers who solve question on the behalf of students. There is some one involved who is making all this easier.Exam Lab betrayal:- Even the labs where exams are conducted sometimes provide a helping hand to some students by allowing cheating mafias to gt the questions ready before the exams.But all these factors are not as humongous as portrayed everywhere. These factors have led to a nation wide protest again Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:25:31.860Z"),
    "question" : "What are your views about SSC CGL scam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d1e0c817f0398fc19f9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-co-relate-CAT-and-SSC-CGL-preparation-at-the-same-time?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I co relate CAT and SSC CGL preparation at the same time?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:25:50.308Z"),
    "question" : "How can I co relate CAT and SSC CGL preparation at the same time? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d410c817f0398fc1ac4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Exam-in-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I prepare for the SSC CGL Exam in 2017?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:25.502Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for the SSC CGL Exam in 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d540c817f0398fc1ad8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-score-good-marks-in-English-in-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Ritesh Kumar Everyone knows which books are the best, Everyone knows the format of exam, Still most of the candidates face trouble while preparing for english. Here I'll be explaining how to tackle English, best resources and most importantly how to study. I scored 42.5 in tier 1 and 175.75 in tier 2 in SSC CGL 2017. This is not an excellent score but considering the fact that my English was at gutter level initially, this is indeed a big achievement for me. Primarily SSC English can be categorised in 3 categories :- 1. Grammar - Error finding, sentence improvement, fill in the blanks, voice, narration. 2. Vocabulary - Synonyms, antonyms, one word substitution, idioms and phrases, fill in the blanks (but only 1-2 out of 5). 3. Comprehension - Unseen passage, Cloze test, Sentence rearrangement. My weapons (book  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:26:44.503Z"),
    "question" : "How do I score good marks in English in SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d660c817f0398fc1b9a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-SSC-chsl-in-3-months?-",
    "answer" : "Testbook The SSC CHSL recruitment process has 3 stages - tier 1, tier 2 and tier 3. Tier 1 - Online objective test (60 min | 200 marks | 100 ques - 25 per section) - Tier 1 has four sections - General Intelligence, General Awareness, Quantitative Aptitude and English Language. There is no sectional cutoff. Tier 2 - Descriptive paper-based exam (60 min | 100 marks | 2 ques) - Essay and letter/application writing Tier 3 - Typing test for LDC/JSA and PA/SA Skill test for the role of Data Entry Operator (DEO) Usually, you will have about 3-4 months for the tier 1 exam after the official notification for the exam is released by the SSC and about 2-3 months for the tier 2 exam after the tier 1 exam. So, you can focus most of your time on clearing the tier 1 exam which is qualifying in nature. The final allotme Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:27:02.951Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack SSC chsl in 3 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d790c817f0398fc1bac"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-number-of-attempts-allowed-for-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "SSC Combined Graduate preliminary exam is conducted every year by the SSC. to use for this examination a candidate should be a graduate in any discipline from a recognized university. This examination is conducted for the posts of Assistants, Inspectors, and Sub- Inspectors, Divisional Accountants, Junior Accountants, Auditors in various governmental agencies just like the Railways, Central Vigilance Commission, Central Excise, tax, CBI, Central Police Organizations, etc. The candidate will get only three attempts for the Combined Graduate preliminary exam. there's a relaxation in age is given for the reserved category candidates.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:27:21.498Z"),
    "question" : "What is the number of attempts allowed for SSC CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376d8f0c817f0398fc1bbe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Who-is-the-best-teacher-for-SSC-CGL-maths-at-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Preparing for the SSC CGL exam is quite stressful when you don’t have proper guidance and coaching. However, if you manage to get the mentor-like Mohit Goyal, then no one can stop you from achieving your goal. MOHIT GOYAL sir is certainly the most credible and best teacher for SSC CGL Maths at Delhi. I can give you a few examples which show how he is the most demanded and genuine teacher among all I have come across. His style of teaching is not complicated because he deeply comprehends topics and gives short tricks to students that are easily memorable. Whenever my fellow SSC candidates and I feel doubts about any mathematics question, then we can ask him without any hesitation. The best thing I like about MOHIT GOYAL sir is that he loves to teach students and always help them to memorize  Continue Reading Preparing for the SSC CGL exam is quite stressful when you don’t have proper guidance and coaching. However, if you manage to get the mentor-like Mohit Goyal, then no one can stop you from achieving your goal. MOHIT GOYAL sir is certainly the most credible and best teacher for SSC CGL Maths at Delhi. I can give you a few examples which show how he is the most demanded and genuine teacher among all I have come across. His style of teaching is not complicated because he deeply comprehends topics and gives short tricks to students that are easily memorable. Whenever my fellow SSC candidates and I feel doubts about any mathematics question, then we can ask him without any hesitation. The best thing I like about MOHIT GOYAL sir is that he loves to teach students and always help them to memorize  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:27:43.590Z"),
    "question" : "Who is the best teacher for SSC CGL maths at Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376da40c817f0398fc1c86"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-will-be-the-expected-cut-off-for-SSC-CHSL-2018-tier-1?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What will be the expected cut off for SSC CHSL 2018 tier 1?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:28:04.605Z"),
    "question" : "What will be the expected cut off for SSC CHSL 2018 tier 1? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376db80c817f0398fc1c9a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-book-for-ssc-cgl-previous-years-paper-practice?-",
    "answer" : "Hi Preetam, Lets get into the details of exam pattern followed by SSC in Tier 2 exam of SSC CGL - 2017. It was completely different from the papers asked earlier. Maths paper is a deciding one to the most of the candidates. So, this time SSC changed the pattern completely. On average, 50% of the questions asked based on concepts rather than formula based. Also most of them were CAT level. So, if you really want to crack CGL 2018, start your preparation with CAT book by Arun Sharma. Though, practicing previous questions paper gives you good knowledge over the pattern of the Tier -1, we may not predict what changes SSC might bring in the toughness of Tier -1 paper this time (SSC is giving one surprise each year since 2016). So, be prepared for the worst situation and try to practice as much a Continue Reading Hi Preetam, Lets get into the details of exam pattern followed by SSC in Tier 2 exam of SSC CGL - 2017. It was completely different from the papers asked earlier. Maths paper is a deciding one to the most of the candidates. So, this time SSC changed the pattern completely. On average, 50% of the questions asked based on concepts rather than formula based. Also most of them were CAT level. So, if you really want to crack CGL 2018, start your preparation with CAT book by Arun Sharma. Though, practicing previous questions paper gives you good knowledge over the pattern of the Tier -1, we may not predict what changes SSC might bring in the toughness of Tier -1 paper this time (SSC is giving one surprise each year since 2016). So, be prepared for the worst situation and try to practice as much a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:28:24.531Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best book for ssc cgl previous years paper practice? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376dcd0c817f0398fc1cae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-SSC-CGL-difficult-to-crack-for-the-general-category?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Subhadip Debnath",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:28:45.624Z"),
    "question" : "Is the SSC CGL difficult to crack for the general category? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376df20c817f0398fc1d7c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-was-your-SSC-CGL-2018-Mains-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Nitin Verma My exam was on 12 September 2019. I have scored 170 marks in PRE. I analyzed paper of 11th Sep and it seemed quite easy and scoring,( i was even wondering why all were saying that paper is calculative, as that much of calculation was expected in MAINS exam), as there was no news of NEW QUESTIONS and mostly all questions were repeated. I revised some mensuration topics which were asked majorly and all those pity calculations of percentage and SI- CI. And when my day came on 12sep, like everyone I was also nervous but controlled. After all the inspections when we entered, seats were conjusted and it was warm enough to get you sweating. When the test started it seemed quite simple, after 4 minutes I realized that I had not attempted even a single question due to those Devastating calculations, this Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:29:22.191Z"),
    "question" : "How was your SSC CGL 2018 Mains exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e190c817f0398fc1e50"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-standard-NCERT-books-I-should-read-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which standard NCERT books I should read for SSC CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:01.986Z"),
    "question" : "Which standard NCERT books I should read for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e2f0c817f0398fc1e66"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-Paramount-the-best-coaching-institute-in-Delhi-for-the-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "No. No coaching can be best. They are just befooling you. If you read previous answers you can get to know their experience. They just give you a damn impressive demo and then they start cheating you. So i would suggest you to not go to any coaching. If you have week basics and not a good academic then firat work over them. Else if you need coaching then go for some small institutions because in Paramount and other coachings there are so huge batches about 1500–3000 students in a single batches. They keep teacher in one room and he teaches from there and other students seit in other rooms and study through projector. So if you want to attend a class like this it would be better you watch YouTube videos. Online guruji is a channel on YouTube. He teaches everything for SSC. Unacademy is diff Continue Reading No. No coaching can be best. They are just befooling you. If you read previous answers you can get to know their experience. They just give you a damn impressive demo and then they start cheating you. So i would suggest you to not go to any coaching. If you have week basics and not a good academic then firat work over them. Else if you need coaching then go for some small institutions because in Paramount and other coachings there are so huge batches about 1500–3000 students in a single batches. They keep teacher in one room and he teaches from there and other students seit in other rooms and study through projector. So if you want to attend a class like this it would be better you watch YouTube videos. Online guruji is a channel on YouTube. He teaches everything for SSC. Unacademy is diff Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:23.875Z"),
    "question" : "Is Paramount the best coaching institute in Delhi for the SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e430c817f0398fc1e78"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-apply-for-SSC-MTS?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I apply for SSC MTS?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:43.935Z"),
    "question" : "How do I apply for SSC MTS? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e580c817f0398fc1f3c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-clear-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-the-final-year-of-a-degree?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Partha Kansabanik 12",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:04.004Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to clear the SSC CGL exam in the final year of a degree? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e6a0c817f0398fc1f4c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-English-for-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Before answering this question, I wanna share my score of english section in various ssc exams:- SSC cgl tier 2 2017 168.5/200. Ssc cpo tier1 2017 42.5/50. Ssc cgl tier1 2017 41.5/50. Practice of numerous questions and their continuous revision is the key to improve English for SSC CGL. So, how to improve it? Sources and strategy to prepare English to get more than 80% makes are given below: English section of ssc cgl consists of 3 sections:- Vocabulary - It includes antonym, synonym, one word substitution, spelling errors, phrasal verbs.(Don't ignore phrasal verbs because you can get 2–3 questions in tier 1 and 5–10 questions in tier2 form this chapter. This chapter can give you an edge over other candidates in exam. I regret because I didn't prepare this chapter before ssc cgl tier 1 and lost feContinue Reading Before answering this question, I wanna share my score of english section in various ssc exams:- SSC cgl tier 2 2017 168.5/200. Ssc cpo tier1 2017 42.5/50. Ssc cgl tier1 2017 41.5/50. Practice of numerous questions and their continuous revision is the key to improve English for SSC CGL. So, how to improve it? Sources and strategy to prepare English to get more than 80% makes are given below: English section of ssc cgl consists of 3 sections:- Vocabulary - It includes antonym, synonym, one word substitution, spelling errors, phrasal verbs.(Don't ignore phrasal verbs because you can get 2–3 questions in tier 1 and 5–10 questions in tier2 form this chapter. This chapter can give you an edge over other candidates in exam. I regret because I didn't prepare this chapter before ssc cgl tier 1 and lost feContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:22.132Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve English for SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e7d0c817f0398fc1f60"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-tentative-month-in-which-SSC-CGL-2018-be-held?-",
    "answer" : "This question is there in minds of many aspirants. Got many mails regarding this query. The date of SSC CGL 2018 prelims has not yet been finalized. The issue is serious as there is a lot of uncertainty in air.There are several reasons for this and I am putting them as following : One very strong reason is that there are number of judicial cases going on against SSC. These cases are on various examinations conducted by SSC.One of the most vocal matter is the case by some unsuccessful candidates against SSC CGL 2016 . This case has stopped the joining of thousands of successful candidates so it has delayed the functioning in other exams. This case has got some media attention as well. Successful candidates are the victims here as they are being stopped from their rightful joining.There is anContinue Reading This question is there in minds of many aspirants. Got many mails regarding this query. The date of SSC CGL 2018 prelims has not yet been finalized. The issue is serious as there is a lot of uncertainty in air.There are several reasons for this and I am putting them as following : One very strong reason is that there are number of judicial cases going on against SSC. These cases are on various examinations conducted by SSC.One of the most vocal matter is the case by some unsuccessful candidates against SSC CGL 2016 . This case has stopped the joining of thousands of successful candidates so it has delayed the functioning in other exams. This case has got some media attention as well. Successful candidates are the victims here as they are being stopped from their rightful joining.There is anContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:41.211Z"),
    "question" : "What is the tentative month in which SSC CGL 2018 be held? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e920c817f0398fc2024"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-did-you-score-in-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1?-",
    "answer" : "After filling the form a year back, I had almost thought of not appearing for SSC CGL this year. My examination Centre was Noida, while my hometown is Jammu. That is because when I had filled the form, I was still in Delhi and I didn’t expect CGL to get delayed by almost 1 year. I was almost sure that my parents wouldn’t suggest me to appear in the exam.However, it didn’t happen. I prepared for CGL for just 2 weeks before the exam. Moreover, since I had to travel from Jammu to Noida for the exam, I stopped preparing two days before the exam. So, I attempted around 75 questions out of 100. My shift was 11th june , 3rd shift. And I had expected to get not more than 10 questions wrong. After getting answer key,my score goes like this : Reasoning : Attempted : 24/25Correct: 18General Knowledge:Continue Reading After filling the form a year back, I had almost thought of not appearing for SSC CGL this year. My examination Centre was Noida, while my hometown is Jammu. That is because when I had filled the form, I was still in Delhi and I didn’t expect CGL to get delayed by almost 1 year. I was almost sure that my parents wouldn’t suggest me to appear in the exam.However, it didn’t happen. I prepared for CGL for just 2 weeks before the exam. Moreover, since I had to travel from Jammu to Noida for the exam, I stopped preparing two days before the exam. So, I attempted around 75 questions out of 100. My shift was 11th june , 3rd shift. And I had expected to get not more than 10 questions wrong. After getting answer key,my score goes like this : Reasoning : Attempted : 24/25Correct: 18General Knowledge:Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:02.773Z"),
    "question" : "How much did you score in the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376eb70c817f0398fc2045"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-materials-should-an-SSC-CGL-aspirant-follow?-",
    "answer" : "Prasad Bagauli, former Career Counselor  at Triumphant Institute of Management Education (2018)Answered 4 years agoWhat materials should an SSC CGL aspirant follow? Prasad Bagauli Well..study material is one thing that people have a lot of confusion about. Striking the right resources and putting in the right amount of time is very important. I personally followed this strategy: For quant -  go through basics of all topics from RS Aggarwal. IF YOU do have good time, go through Arun sharma’s book for CAT as well. That’s because, once you solve quant book of his, you will find quant questions in all areas of any comp exam, a cakewalk. So prefer this. Rest is all about practise…practise.. For Logical - Best way is to go through some good youtube channels. I will list out those that I found extremely good. Meritshine, Unacademy, Endeavor careers, Gaurav Bakliwal and Study smart. Keep practising..coz logical is damn interesting and keeps you wanting. English - Read The Hind Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:39.344Z"),
    "question" : "What materials should an SSC CGL aspirant follow? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ec90c817f0398fc2107"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-myself-for-SSC-exam-at-home?-",
    "answer" : "Akshay અક્ષય ಅಕ್ಷಯ್ अक्षय, A Teacher by Passion ; A student by choiceAnswered 1 year ago · Author has 171 answers and 241K answer viewsHow can I prepare myself for SSC exam at home? Akshay અક્ષય ಅಕ್ಷಯ್ अक्षय The following steps may be helpful if followed. 1- Analyse the syllabus, previous year’s question papers to understand what is asked and what is not asked in the exam. 2 - Analyse the pattern of the examination, duration taken, selection process, etc. to know the amount of resources in terms of financial backup, opportunity cost involved in the process. The joining may take a couple of years. 3 - After completing points 1 and 2, when you are sure that you are going to prepare for it, make a time table spreading over a period of time, both at the macro and micro level, setting goals to achieve by the time your at the exam door. Figure out the books, study material, internet sources. Talk to your seniors, anyone who has already cleared this examination for guidance if possible. Things are easy  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:57.861Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare myself for SSC exam at home? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376edd0c817f0398fc211f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-rank-in-SSC-CGL-to-get-ASO-in-MEA?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What should be my rank in SSC CGL to get ASO in MEA?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:17.990Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my rank in SSC CGL to get ASO in MEA? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ef50c817f0398fc2133"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-all-test-are-done-in-medical-test-for-SSC-cgl?-",
    "answer" : "SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination - Physical Standards A. Physical standard for the posts of Inspector (Central Excise) and Inspector (Preventive Officer), Inspector (Examiner): Candidates will have to satisfy the following minimum physical standards, failing which, they will not be eligible for appointment. (a) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Male Candidates) (i) Physical Standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test: Walking: 1600 metres in 15 minutes. Cycling: 8 Kms. In 30 minutes. (b) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Female Candidates) (i) Physical standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test Walking: 1 Km. in 20 minutes. Cycling: 3 Kms. in 25 minutes. The Physical Test for candidates will be conducted by the Ce Continue Reading SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination - Physical Standards A. Physical standard for the posts of Inspector (Central Excise) and Inspector (Preventive Officer), Inspector (Examiner): Candidates will have to satisfy the following minimum physical standards, failing which, they will not be eligible for appointment. (a) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Male Candidates) (i) Physical Standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test: Walking: 1600 metres in 15 minutes. Cycling: 8 Kms. In 30 minutes. (b) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Female Candidates) (i) Physical standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test Walking: 1 Km. in 20 minutes. Cycling: 3 Kms. in 25 minutes. The Physical Test for candidates will be conducted by the Ce Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:41.089Z"),
    "question" : "What all test are done in medical test for SSC cgl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f0b0c817f0398fc21f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-SSC-coaching-in-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Sara Dwivedi My recommendation is for Mesorise Academy, Malviya Nagar for students who are serious and sincere about their SSC Prep. I have completed my Pol. Science Hons. from Aurvindo College of DU. I am just waiting for my graduation result to come. I decided to join SSC-CGL coaching institute in South Delhi. I called many institutes to get the knowledge of what they offer for ON-LINE-PREP. Some of them did not agree for Demo - Classes before getting admission , but a few institutes agreed to give free Demo - Classes, I also attended some of classes but I was not satisfied by the way they were teaching on Internet- Big group and no explanation for Individual queries. Some wants me to go through videos of erstwhile recorded classes to know the quality of teaching. It was more mechanical without cleari Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:03.573Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best SSC coaching in Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f1f0c817f0398fc220c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-site-to-learn-English-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Pushkar Bhatia There are so many teachers like Rini Ma’am in Subhash Nagar teaches good English for SSC CGL exams. If you are looking for 1 subject only. Then you must watch Vidya Guru youtube channel. There is a lady who posts amazing english videos. You can simply search with ‘Vidya Guru English’ in youtube search and Vidya Guru English lectures will appear there. Her presenting style is really good. I am very impressed with her lectures. I have also watched many of her lectures as I took their Online course. Due to some physical issue I don’t travel much. I decided my study to pursue from home only. I read good reviews of Vidya Guru online course and their videos are really great. Whole content is available there. VIdya Guru english video will really help you for enhancing English vocab. Sunidhi Trehan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:23.972Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best site to learn English for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f460c817f0398fc22ea"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-there-any-sectional-cutoffs-in-SSC-CGL-Tier-I?-",
    "answer" : "NO sectional cut off as all said. There is only one threshold you need to be over i.e, cut off which is total minimum score out of all the sections all together so there is only final cut off. It dosen't matter if you are weak in 1 or 2 portion or partially weak ever you can't clear it . you can clear it as in general overall cut of of tier 1 lies between100 - 110 at max.  But just scoring cut off marks would let you on backfoot in tier 2 as in final selection total marks are counted. Try to score approx 35 marks in every section than vary this section to section according to your strength but avg. Should come 35 for each, atleast make this a target. Rest is upon your strength. Best of Luck !",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:02.211Z"),
    "question" : "Are there any sectional cutoffs in SSC CGL Tier I? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f5a0c817f0398fc22fa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-SSC-CGL-2018-be-held-or-not?-",
    "answer" : "Commission was supposed to release the official notification regarding the SSC CGL 2018 exam on 21st April 2018 but now the SSC has extended the date of notification for the SSC CGL 2018 exam. The Staff Selection Commission will now release the SSC CGL Exam 2018 notification on 5th May 2018. The commission delayed the notification. This is because the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 exam was delayed. The SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 exam was scheduled to be held on March 31 but due to some reasons. The Tier 3 exam of SSC CGL 2017 will be held in the month of May. So,heat up yourself for the exam,don't give yourself excuse of delaying. Break a leg !!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:22.336Z"),
    "question" : "Will the SSC CGL 2018 be held or not? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f6e0c817f0398fc2310"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-you-share-your-final-Marks-of-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Depressed very much depressed… I (OBC) scored 643.5 including AAO exam.. And hopefully trying to see the result as per my expectation of AAO but…Some nuisance created on 15th Nov 19 , answer key revision…. I didn't get AAO but one friend low having score 642 got the AAO post……. I have scored 121.5 in Economic and Accounts exam, Unable to think, what had happened!? Why me?? In the last I get D06 post, knows nothing about this post….Donot know will join or not!!! Working in private industry with salary of 50K INR… I am hopeless, dejected.. If anyone have reasons to convince/guide me they are most welcome!!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:42.173Z"),
    "question" : "Can you share your final Marks of SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f950c817f0398fc23e4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-score-in-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-2019?-",
    "answer" : "My exam was on 7 march 1st shift. One of the easiest shift. I hated the fact i got a easy shift bcoz i hv prepared very hard for almost 1 year nd i know unless i get a hard shift i m sure gonna lose about 10 marks bcoz increment will vary from 10 - 40 and and i can score easily 145+ however hard the shift is. So i know if i get easy shift i can score 140+ out of 150 in other 3 sections and i can max it up to 160 only bcoz my GS is weak and getting 180+ will be a very hard task. But if i did the same in hard shift 130+/150 and even 14–15 in GS with a raw of 140–145 i can jump to 180+ easily relating to the normalisation in 2018 tier 1. My raw marks are Reasoning - 42.5 GS - 22.5 Maths -50 English - 50 Total - 165/200. It happend exactly as i hv dreaded. Final marks came and as i was opening the ss Continue Reading My exam was on 7 march 1st shift. One of the easiest shift. I hated the fact i got a easy shift bcoz i hv prepared very hard for almost 1 year nd i know unless i get a hard shift i m sure gonna lose about 10 marks bcoz increment will vary from 10 - 40 and and i can score easily 145+ however hard the shift is. So i know if i get easy shift i can score 140+ out of 150 in other 3 sections and i can max it up to 160 only bcoz my GS is weak and getting 180+ will be a very hard task. But if i did the same in hard shift 130+/150 and even 14–15 in GS with a raw of 140–145 i can jump to 180+ easily relating to the normalisation in 2018 tier 1. My raw marks are Reasoning - 42.5 GS - 22.5 Maths -50 English - 50 Total - 165/200. It happend exactly as i hv dreaded. Final marks came and as i was opening the ss Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:21.404Z"),
    "question" : "What is your score in the SSC CGL Tier 1 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fb70c817f0398fc24ae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-SSC-coaching-in-Allahabad?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best SSC coaching in Allahabad?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:55.962Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best SSC coaching in Allahabad? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fca0c817f0398fc24c4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-2?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How did you prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 2?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:14.208Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 2? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fdf0c817f0398fc24d8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-lecture-on-math-for-the-SSC-CGL-on-YouTube?-",
    "answer" : "There are multiple teachers teaching online saying one is best would be a disrespect to the other. All are great in there own unique way From Rakesh Yadav sir to Abhinay sharma sir. You can also visit my channel, I know I don't have all the fancy stuff like digital board but what I have is a will and creativity to teach in best manner possible. Recently I have uploaded a listen in which Complete boat and stream topic has been taught. You check it out. Every year at least one question is definitely asked from **Boat and stream ** in various government job exams you can confirm your 2 marks after watching this lesson completely. Timeline of concepts : 1. Basics of boat and stream 1:06 2. Question based on Downstream and Upstream speed 5:55 3. Concept of finding speed of boat and stream from Upstrea Continue Reading There are multiple teachers teaching online saying one is best would be a disrespect to the other. All are great in there own unique way From Rakesh Yadav sir to Abhinay sharma sir. You can also visit my channel, I know I don't have all the fancy stuff like digital board but what I have is a will and creativity to teach in best manner possible. Recently I have uploaded a listen in which Complete boat and stream topic has been taught. You check it out. Every year at least one question is definitely asked from **Boat and stream ** in various government job exams you can confirm your 2 marks after watching this lesson completely. Timeline of concepts : 1. Basics of boat and stream 1:06 2. Question based on Downstream and Upstream speed 5:55 3. Concept of finding speed of boat and stream from Upstrea Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:35.848Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best lecture on math for the SSC CGL on YouTube? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ff20c817f0398fc25a4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-eligibility-criteria-for-the-SSC-CGL-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "Maitery Mahajan For better preparation from your home itself, i would recommend you to join any good online SSC classes which cater to all your needs to crack the exam in first attempt. I myself have enrolled sometime back in Takshila Learning’s Brilliant 50 batch 8800999280 where i am getting personalised coaching for 1 year with updated video lectures, online test series, eBooks and faculty support via Whatsapp group and call facility (individual) and monthly webinars. You can also be part of this batch. If you are planning to appear for SSC CGL 2020-21, it is important that you go through the complete eligibility criteria thoroughly to avoid getting disqualified for the exam at a later stage. SSC CGL Eligibility: Age Limit The SSC CGL age criteria varies according to the different posts. Given in the tabl Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:54.800Z"),
    "question" : "What are the eligibility criteria for the SSC CGL Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770040c817f0398fc25bd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-experience-with-the-SSC-CHSL-typing-test?-",
    "answer" : "In short it was exhausting but fairly good in the end. My DEST for DEO post and typing test for LDC/PA&SA was scheduled on the same day i.e. on 26th August, 2019 in Allahabad city of central region. The reporting time of the exam was 9:00 AM. I left the hotel room at 7:30 as the centre was in the outskirts of the city and I had never been to city before. I reached the centre around 8:00 and waited for more than an hour before the entry started. Everyone had to submit their bags and other belongings, and their was fairly good arrangement for that. After submitting the bag I had to wait for another hour before the main entry which started around 10 AM. There were around 100 candidates and we were divided into 7 groups of 25 candidates in each and sent to another building for the document verif Continue Reading In short it was exhausting but fairly good in the end. My DEST for DEO post and typing test for LDC/PA&SA was scheduled on the same day i.e. on 26th August, 2019 in Allahabad city of central region. The reporting time of the exam was 9:00 AM. I left the hotel room at 7:30 as the centre was in the outskirts of the city and I had never been to city before. I reached the centre around 8:00 and waited for more than an hour before the entry started. Everyone had to submit their bags and other belongings, and their was fairly good arrangement for that. After submitting the bag I had to wait for another hour before the main entry which started around 10 AM. There were around 100 candidates and we were divided into 7 groups of 25 candidates in each and sent to another building for the document verif Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:12.243Z"),
    "question" : "What is your experience with the SSC CHSL typing test? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770180c817f0398fc25ce"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-SSC-CGL-Tier-2-in-English?-",
    "answer" : "Many students believe that it is very cumbersome to score well in English section. On the other hand, it can be one of the easiest and scoring subjects if you prepare well and with right strategy. In tier 2 exam, you have to face 200 questions of English language carrying a weightage of 1 mark each with a penalty of .25 marks for each wrong answer. Let’s have a look on the topics and the number of questions asked in previous year exam in English section:  Clearly, paper of English section is divided in three broad categories: Reading Comprehension Grammar Vocabulary So, strengthening each topic is the master key to score good marks in English Section. Remember, castle is not build in a day but if you spend time consistently, you can perform well in relatively less time. Strategy to Approach the to Continue Reading Many students believe that it is very cumbersome to score well in English section. On the other hand, it can be one of the easiest and scoring subjects if you prepare well and with right strategy. In tier 2 exam, you have to face 200 questions of English language carrying a weightage of 1 mark each with a penalty of .25 marks for each wrong answer. Let’s have a look on the topics and the number of questions asked in previous year exam in English section:  Clearly, paper of English section is divided in three broad categories: Reading Comprehension Grammar Vocabulary So, strengthening each topic is the master key to score good marks in English Section. Remember, castle is not build in a day but if you spend time consistently, you can perform well in relatively less time. Strategy to Approach the to Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:32.775Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for SSC CGL Tier 2 in English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037703f0c817f0398fc26a9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-centre-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-Chennai?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best coaching centre for the SSC CGL exam in Chennai?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:11.361Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching centre for the SSC CGL exam in Chennai? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770670c817f0398fc26d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-score-150+-in-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "9 important points to score better in ssc 2017. Many people apply for SSC CGL Exam without having any knowledge which reduces their chances of clearing the exam. So we have come across many important points which they might not be aware of but should be kept in the mind of the aspirants to score well in SSC Exam. Here is the list of such points which the aspirants should go through to excel in the upcoming SSC Exam. 1. SSC Repeats questions year after year The biggest truth with SSC is that SSC do repeat questions and that too in all sections (Reasoning, Maths, English and General Awareness). Have a look at the last 4-5 year question papers of SSC CGL Exams and you will find out that, there are around 2-3 questions in each section which are repeated every time. It is therefore necessary to sol Continue Reading 9 important points to score better in ssc 2017. Many people apply for SSC CGL Exam without having any knowledge which reduces their chances of clearing the exam. So we have come across many important points which they might not be aware of but should be kept in the mind of the aspirants to score well in SSC Exam. Here is the list of such points which the aspirants should go through to excel in the upcoming SSC Exam. 1. SSC Repeats questions year after year The biggest truth with SSC is that SSC do repeat questions and that too in all sections (Reasoning, Maths, English and General Awareness). Have a look at the last 4-5 year question papers of SSC CGL Exams and you will find out that, there are around 2-3 questions in each section which are repeated every time. It is therefore necessary to sol Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:51.256Z"),
    "question" : "How do I score 150+ in SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037709b0c817f0398fc27af"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-normalization-happen-in-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Does normalization happen in SSC-CGL exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:40:43.035Z"),
    "question" : "Does normalization happen in SSC-CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770b80c817f0398fc287b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-months-of-current-affairs-do-I-have-to-read-for-the-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Roohi Jaiswal, B.Com from Bachelor of Commerce Degrees (2016)Answered January 20, 2021 · Author has 104 answers and 73.3K answer viewsHow many months of current affairs do I have to read for the SSC CGL 2018? Roohi Jaiswal Atleast 6–7 months of current affairs are required to study in order to get full marks in current affairs portion of SSC exam. I have a better idea for you to prepare for the Current Affairs for the SSC Exams. Just go with the online videos of Vidya Guru’s Current Affairs. Their current affairs videos are just superb. You can get the best help by these videos. By these videos, you will get latest videos and all past time current affairs as well. You can watch these videos for the explanation of each event and then just make the notes by these videos. This is the free youtube session. You will get all the information about the events happening in the Country and World. Reading the magazine and newspaper is just a waste of time. Because you need atleast 2 hours to go through the newspaper or ma Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:41:12.690Z"),
    "question" : "How many months of current affairs do I have to read for the SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770d50c817f0398fc2894"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-institute-for-SSC-CGL-preparation-in-Kolkata?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best coaching institute for SSC CGL preparation in Kolkata?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:41:41.125Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching institute for SSC CGL preparation in Kolkata? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770ec0c817f0398fc295b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-YouTube-channel-for-the-best-advanced-maths-videos-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Hello In SSC CGL maths is very important subject. It carries 50 marks in tier 1 and 200 marks in tier 2. If you want to prepare for Quantitative aptitude through videos then this is the best way to gain knowledge quickly. but firstly, you should know the complete information of SSC CGL Recruitment. Here below i am providing you some best advance maths videos for SSC CGL. TrigonometryGeometryAlgebraQuadrilateral Geometry",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:42:04.554Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best YouTube channel for the best advanced maths videos for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771030c817f0398fc2970"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-will-happen-now-as-the-supreme-court-has-put-stay-on-the-result-of-the-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Samar Pratap Till this point of time, I was extremely optimistic that everything will work out fine in the end. I was not that much perturbed with delays as I was getting enough time to pursue my hobbies. Today when I was going through the article regarding stay on exam, one line particularly caught my attention and literally petrified me Delivering its verdict, the court said that it can’t permit people benefitting from SSC examination scam to get into service, Reading this line again and again gave this slight hint that exam might get cancelled. Oh God, did I just write the most dreaded statement ? I sincerely hope that nothing like this happens. Just like everyone else, I am nowhere close to what I was during tier 2. I scored 331 in tier 2 which is not a great score but not bad either. If I feel this s Continue Reading Till this point of time, I was extremely optimistic that everything will work out fine in the end. I was not that much perturbed with delays as I was getting enough time to pursue my hobbies. Today when I was going through the article regarding stay on exam, one line particularly caught my attention and literally petrified me Delivering its verdict, the court said that it can’t permit people benefitting from SSC examination scam to get into service, Reading this line again and again gave this slight hint that exam might get cancelled. Oh God, did I just write the most dreaded statement ? I sincerely hope that nothing like this happens. Just like everyone else, I am nowhere close to what I was during tier 2. I scored 331 in tier 2 which is not a great score but not bad either. If I feel this s Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:42:27.530Z"),
    "question" : "What will happen now as the supreme court has put stay on the result of the SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771400c817f0398fc2a5b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-good-institutes-in-Chandigarh-for-SSC-CGL-coaching?-",
    "answer" : "Mukesh Kapoor, lives in Chandigarh, India (2008-present)Updated 1 year ago · Author has 96 answers and 172.1K answer viewsWhat are good institutes in Chandigarh for SSC CGL coaching? Mukesh Kapoor Dear Candidate, If you are looking for an institute that provides structured and targeted SSC CGL coaching in Chandigarh, there is only one name i.e The IBS Institute. The Institute has been a frontrunner in the provider of coaching of all the SSC examinations for more than a decade. The reasons that make the institute as the leader in the niche are manifold. Institute has been delivering quality education in the field for approximately a decade. The institute’s one of a kind study material is complete in all aspects and the candidate doesn’t have to refer to anything else. The faculty is extremely talented and some of them have actually cleared the exam in the past and thus can provide the students with a better exam perspective. The test series is exhaustive which provides the candidates w Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:43:28.770Z"),
    "question" : "What are good institutes in Chandigarh for SSC CGL coaching? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771600c817f0398fc2b2d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-a-GS-for-the-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Let us first understand what is mostly asked in ssc gs section that is what are the favourite topics of ssc. If you are a science background student than you get an extra edge as approx 10 questions of physics, chemistry and biology are asked and you need to work only on bio section if you are an engineer or so. So prepare science first simply by going through the concept and than revising regularly. Go for previous year question papers of gs so that you can get an insight of how the questions are asked. Prepare science first I will tell you the strategy for others in another answer. This is my first answer guys regarding SSC. As I also have cracked SSC CGL pre and mains 2017 and have written descriptive of SSC chsl 2017. Hope this will help.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:00.914Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare a GS for the SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037718c0c817f0398fc2b56"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-book-lists-for-the-SSC-CGL-2020-if-I-am-starting-from-scratch?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the book lists for the SSC CGL 2020 if I am starting from scratch?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:44.675Z"),
    "question" : "What are the book lists for the SSC CGL 2020 if I am starting from scratch? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771a60c817f0398fc2c1f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-in-3-months?-",
    "answer" : "Harshit Shukla If CGL 2018 is Your first attempt then 3 months is not enough but yes it's not very hard to crack pre exam in first attempt. You have to follow some best books and online sources. MATHS— KIRAN chapterwise 8900+ is best book.Watch UNACADEMY videos and learn tricks. Some best Educators on that platform are HARSHIT SHUKLA, CHETAN MEENA, BINEESH.WATCH ABHINAY MATHS YOUTUBE CHANNEL.Try to attempt mocks regular. It will boost up your preparation slowly. And yes shuru me marks km aynge to sad mt ho jana. Dheere dheere hoga increase.English — MIRROR OF COMMONS ERROR BY A.K.SINGHSP BAKSHI GENERAL ENGLISHMB PUBLICATION PREVIOUS YEAR SET PAPERSDOWNLOAD IDIOMS AND ONE WORD SUBSTITUTION PDF From Qmaths websites. ( Just Google)GENERAL STUDY - This part is most uncertain for securing marks. But also it will c Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:10.480Z"),
    "question" : "How can one prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 1 in 3 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771bd0c817f0398fc2c32"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Staff Selection Commission (SSC) is an organization under Government of India to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices.Career in SSC Staff Selection Commission conducts a lot of exams every year. It is a right platform for the people who are eager to set their career in Government jobs. It provides a variety of jobs on the basis of different educational backgrounds. The pay scale for the job gets varied on the type of job selected. Jobs offered by SSC 1. Inspector of Income Tax 2. Inspector (Central Excise) 3. Inspector (Preventive Officer) 4. Inspector (Examiner) 5. Inspector of Posts 6. Assistant Enforcement Officer 7. Compiler 8. Divisional Accountant 9. Auditors 10. UDC’s 11. Tax Assistants 12. A Continue Reading Staff Selection Commission (SSC) is an organization under Government of India to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices.Career in SSC Staff Selection Commission conducts a lot of exams every year. It is a right platform for the people who are eager to set their career in Government jobs. It provides a variety of jobs on the basis of different educational backgrounds. The pay scale for the job gets varied on the type of job selected. Jobs offered by SSC 1. Inspector of Income Tax 2. Inspector (Central Excise) 3. Inspector (Preventive Officer) 4. Inspector (Examiner) 5. Inspector of Posts 6. Assistant Enforcement Officer 7. Compiler 8. Divisional Accountant 9. Auditors 10. UDC’s 11. Tax Assistants 12. A Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:33.373Z"),
    "question" : "What is SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771e70c817f0398fc2d0c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-is-the-best-scopes-between-banking-jobs-and-SSC-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, Well if i have to be honest i believe that choosing SSC would be a good idea, there are many reasons for that, First, mode of exam- see if you are good with maths concepts and your knowledge about english is also good, you can do fairly well in CGl or any other SSC exam, but for banking there are alot of different points that you have to keep in mind, banking syllabus consists maths(calculative), english(lengthy), reasoning ( hard level) and GK( vast area), so all in all syllabus of Bank is way too hard, then in mains also you have to study for all the section adding computer awarness to it too, but in SSC There are only 2 papers in mains, english and maths. There is interview in bank PO, which is absent in SSC. What we get- well after all the hard work you put, what you get is a job w Continue Reading Hello, Well if i have to be honest i believe that choosing SSC would be a good idea, there are many reasons for that, First, mode of exam- see if you are good with maths concepts and your knowledge about english is also good, you can do fairly well in CGl or any other SSC exam, but for banking there are alot of different points that you have to keep in mind, banking syllabus consists maths(calculative), english(lengthy), reasoning ( hard level) and GK( vast area), so all in all syllabus of Bank is way too hard, then in mains also you have to study for all the section adding computer awarness to it too, but in SSC There are only 2 papers in mains, english and maths. There is interview in bank PO, which is absent in SSC. What we get- well after all the hard work you put, what you get is a job w Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:15.258Z"),
    "question" : "Where is the best scopes between banking jobs and SSC jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771fb0c817f0398fc2d1a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-coaching-center-in-Patna-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Well staying in Patna people always do think that no one would be able to crack any exam and they would be left with both the legs on two boats at the same time but this is the Up-trending Apocryphal!! Patna and taking Bihar as a whole has ever since been introducing the maximum numbers of IPS officers through UPSC every year!! So it doesn't mean that we are not having the talent… Of course we are blessed with that talent of workin hard and forcing to contemplate the entire country about our labour and our innate talents!! However Staff Selection Commission(SSC) is one of the easiest exams to crack for Under Graduate aspirants or applicants, Unlike JEE, CLAT, NDA, SCRA etc. The biggest flaw that the question paper has in SSC is the repetition of the same pattern of questions every Second Yea Continue Reading Well staying in Patna people always do think that no one would be able to crack any exam and they would be left with both the legs on two boats at the same time but this is the Up-trending Apocryphal!! Patna and taking Bihar as a whole has ever since been introducing the maximum numbers of IPS officers through UPSC every year!! So it doesn't mean that we are not having the talent… Of course we are blessed with that talent of workin hard and forcing to contemplate the entire country about our labour and our innate talents!! However Staff Selection Commission(SSC) is one of the easiest exams to crack for Under Graduate aspirants or applicants, Unlike JEE, CLAT, NDA, SCRA etc. The biggest flaw that the question paper has in SSC is the repetition of the same pattern of questions every Second Yea Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:35.295Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best coaching center in Patna for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772100c817f0398fc2dde"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-revise-maths-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Prashant Singh This happens with everyone, all tends to forget the previous questions especially the tough one or which are a bit different from other questions. Dont worry just check how it is solved and do it again. Things to remember while doing any chapter is write down all important points separately while solving, especially formula's or any important aspect of a question. Do not solve 10 books once, solve one or two books many times. Here everyone will give you a list of many books which for every subject say 6–7 books for maths, 3–4 for english, 3–4 for reasoning and for gs there may be much more. Is it practical to cover all those books comprehensively. This only will waste your time. Take two books i would suggest one for advance maths portion and one for the remaining portion. If any aspect is b Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:56.078Z"),
    "question" : "How do I revise maths SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772260c817f0398fc2df9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-we-publish-the-SSC-results-for-2018?-",
    "answer" : "This is fantastic work for Students. Who are going to complete their SSC level. As my thinking upcoming 6th May going to publish “SSC result 2018” from education ministry of Bangladesh. Though, Students will get the results from online, sms as well as their organization. so, don’t worry to check everywhere. I am suggested your SSC Exam result 2018 via SMS method below:-  As you know, the official education board result going to publish result on Education Board Bangladesh or WEB BASED RESULT PUBLICATION I hope you would be happy to see this news. I wish very best you all students of SSC Exam 2018. Thanks. Continue Reading This is fantastic work for Students. Who are going to complete their SSC level. As my thinking upcoming 6th May going to publish “SSC result 2018” from education ministry of Bangladesh. Though, Students will get the results from online, sms as well as their organization. so, don’t worry to check everywhere. I am suggested your SSC Exam result 2018 via SMS method below:-  As you know, the official education board result going to publish result on Education Board Bangladesh or WEB BASED RESULT PUBLICATION I hope you would be happy to see this news. I wish very best you all students of SSC Exam 2018. Thanks. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:18.072Z"),
    "question" : "When will we publish the SSC results for 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772400c817f0398fc2e14"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-best-books-for-the-SSC-CHSL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "As I Cracked SSC CHSL 2016 (tier 1) in first attempt so may I'll be able to answer your question So..... According to me... When you gone through previous year question papers It seems the ssc chsl is too much competative exam bt the questions asked are not too tough as compared to SSC CGL... So if you build your concepts from below mention books and practice allot of previous year questions and mock tests you surely crack ssc chsl 2018... So... The Tier 1 Consist of four sections.... 1) Reasoning... The reasoning section is too easy section where you score 50/50 easily by practicing allot previous year question papers.. For reasoning this two books are more than sufficient.. * Verbal and Non verbal Reasoning by R. S Agarwal. *Kiran's previous year que Papers R. 7500 2) English... This section Continue Reading As I Cracked SSC CHSL 2016 (tier 1) in first attempt so may I'll be able to answer your question So..... According to me... When you gone through previous year question papers It seems the ssc chsl is too much competative exam bt the questions asked are not too tough as compared to SSC CGL... So if you build your concepts from below mention books and practice allot of previous year questions and mock tests you surely crack ssc chsl 2018... So... The Tier 1 Consist of four sections.... 1) Reasoning... The reasoning section is too easy section where you score 50/50 easily by practicing allot previous year question papers.. For reasoning this two books are more than sufficient.. * Verbal and Non verbal Reasoning by R. S Agarwal. *Kiran's previous year que Papers R. 7500 2) English... This section Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:44.466Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best books for the SSC CHSL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772580c817f0398fc2ee0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-SSC-CGL-2017-Tier-2-results-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "If everything goes on smoothly . We can expect answer key by 10 March and objections will be raised by say 20 March. Add one month for final result. So final result will be declared some where around 10–15 Apr. Now I know most of you say tier 3 is fixed on 31 March. Let me tell it was fixed keeping in view that tier 2 was supposed to be conducted in January. Now it look like tier will be conducted in April last or may 1 st week , unless ssc decide to conduct tier 3 for all 1.9 lakh.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:48:08.513Z"),
    "question" : "When will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 2 results be declared? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772800c817f0398fc2f04"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-marks-are-required-in-SSC-CGL-to-get-placed-in-the-income-tax-department-in-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How many marks are required in SSC CGL to get placed in the income tax department in Delhi?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:48:48.528Z"),
    "question" : "How many marks are required in SSC CGL to get placed in the income tax department in Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037729a0c817f0398fc2fcd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-should-I-refer-for-SSC-English?-",
    "answer" : "As your question is basic to advacnce so accordingly answer is Plinth to paramount - first you need to clear your concepts . This book is like mother to ssc english and does spoon feeding though students have cleared ssc english by reading only this book but that was scenario of past as level is increasing day by dayS. P. Bakshi- this is 2nd book which you need to read or i would say compulsory for ssc mains. Go through this book at least twice to clear your advance concepts of grammer , idiom phrase and other stuff.R.s Aggarwal- yes you read it right. This book of english is a bit advance than s.p. bakshi. Word meaning ,idiom phrases , one word are of advance level discussed in this book. Good thing is this book is for practice purpose mainly but don't get demoralised if you are not able tContinue Reading As your question is basic to advacnce so accordingly answer is Plinth to paramount - first you need to clear your concepts . This book is like mother to ssc english and does spoon feeding though students have cleared ssc english by reading only this book but that was scenario of past as level is increasing day by dayS. P. Bakshi- this is 2nd book which you need to read or i would say compulsory for ssc mains. Go through this book at least twice to clear your advance concepts of grammer , idiom phrase and other stuff.R.s Aggarwal- yes you read it right. This book of english is a bit advance than s.p. bakshi. Word meaning ,idiom phrases , one word are of advance level discussed in this book. Good thing is this book is for practice purpose mainly but don't get demoralised if you are not able tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:14.793Z"),
    "question" : "Which book should I refer for SSC-English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772b70c817f0398fc2fe9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-best-online-test-series-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "I may not be the right person to answer this question as I scored just 135 marks in Tier 1,2016. But still I am writing the answer because I had taken all these tests before my Tier 1 exam.So,here goes my review… 1)Pinnacle SSC CGL- I wrote their free/challenge tests. Challenge tests are of high level whereas other tests are of the same level as actual paper,sometimes i found it lengthy.2) Career power-I don’t know how they are designing the test series this year,but last year the paper was around 50% similar to bank exams.So,I personally found it good for familiarizing with online exam environment.But if you are taking mocks seriously,then think twice before buying it.3)SSC Tube-I had purchased this one. Some papers were easy,some were tough…the level of exam was similar to actual paper. Continue Reading I may not be the right person to answer this question as I scored just 135 marks in Tier 1,2016. But still I am writing the answer because I had taken all these tests before my Tier 1 exam.So,here goes my review… 1)Pinnacle SSC CGL- I wrote their free/challenge tests. Challenge tests are of high level whereas other tests are of the same level as actual paper,sometimes i found it lengthy.2) Career power-I don’t know how they are designing the test series this year,but last year the paper was around 50% similar to bank exams.So,I personally found it good for familiarizing with online exam environment.But if you are taking mocks seriously,then think twice before buying it.3)SSC Tube-I had purchased this one. Some papers were easy,some were tough…the level of exam was similar to actual paper. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:43.734Z"),
    "question" : "Which is best online test series for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772e90c817f0398fc30c5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-questions-in-SSC-CGL-repeat?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for R2A. If you had asked this question before Tier 2 of CGL 17, my answer would have been different. Well, Yes, Questions are repeated in SSC CGL but the number of such questions are very less. What exactly repeated is the type of questions and approach to solve them by candidates. So, better go through each type of questions rather than getting in such things. All the best Harsh Mangla",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:50:33.005Z"),
    "question" : "Do questions in SSC CGL repeat? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037731a0c817f0398fc31a7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-geometry-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "A2A I would suggest start with ncert, If you struggle with basic concepts begin from class 6- then 7, 8, 9 & 10. Next, jump to RD Sharma maths for class 9–10 (Chapters concerned with Geometry). If you think that you have a basic hold on geometry, then watch Advance Maths video lectures of Abhinay Maths on you tube and take notes of geometry topics. He has explained basics and how to approach questions particularly relevant for SSC exams. For practice you can use any compilation of previous year papers (atleast 10 years) and mock tests available on various websites. These mock tests will take care of time management. Once you are done, Take up CAT books, try solving questions up to level 2, this will give you an extra edge. If you find this step difficult Watch Amiya Maths channel on you tube, i Continue Reading A2A I would suggest start with ncert, If you struggle with basic concepts begin from class 6- then 7, 8, 9 & 10. Next, jump to RD Sharma maths for class 9–10 (Chapters concerned with Geometry). If you think that you have a basic hold on geometry, then watch Advance Maths video lectures of Abhinay Maths on you tube and take notes of geometry topics. He has explained basics and how to approach questions particularly relevant for SSC exams. For practice you can use any compilation of previous year papers (atleast 10 years) and mock tests available on various websites. These mock tests will take care of time management. Once you are done, Take up CAT books, try solving questions up to level 2, this will give you an extra edge. If you find this step difficult Watch Amiya Maths channel on you tube, i Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:51:22.941Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for geometry in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773540c817f0398fc328a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-SSC-CGL-tier-3?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How did you prepare for SSC CGL tier 3?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:52:20.164Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for SSC CGL tier 3? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773880c817f0398fc3371"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-one-month?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, Questions like this, “how should i prepare for cgl2019 or cgl 18 in 5 months or 3 months or 2 months and now this,one month” keep coming in my feed. I will keep answering these until the very day of actual examination :-) If you know abcd of warfare,ssc cgl,unlike upsc which is like traditional warfare, is more like a Blitzkrieg or swift action. In Blitzkrieg type of warfare,you have some strong points and coordination. You just bypass the enemy strongholds and encirle them to be exploited later. The point i want to make out is,you can crack tier1 in one month provided: Your base is strong and coordinated,You are good in mathematics, are scoring 110+ in any of the mocks. Following things you can skip: Antonyms and synonyms (i skipped them and still scored 43/50 in tier1 English)Level 2 anContinue Reading Hello, Questions like this, “how should i prepare for cgl2019 or cgl 18 in 5 months or 3 months or 2 months and now this,one month” keep coming in my feed. I will keep answering these until the very day of actual examination :-) If you know abcd of warfare,ssc cgl,unlike upsc which is like traditional warfare, is more like a Blitzkrieg or swift action. In Blitzkrieg type of warfare,you have some strong points and coordination. You just bypass the enemy strongholds and encirle them to be exploited later. The point i want to make out is,you can crack tier1 in one month provided: Your base is strong and coordinated,You are good in mathematics, are scoring 110+ in any of the mocks. Following things you can skip: Antonyms and synonyms (i skipped them and still scored 43/50 in tier1 English)Level 2 anContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:12.201Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the SSC CGL exam in one month? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773a20c817f0398fc338a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-institute-is-better-for-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which institute is better for SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:38.911Z"),
    "question" : "Which institute is better for SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773df0c817f0398fc3472"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-SSC-CGL-2017-Tier-3-results-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "Simarpreet Singh, An Aspirant  146/200 in tier 1 CGL2019 4 March S2Answered 9 months ago · Author has 58 answers and 20.4K answer viewsWhen will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 results be declared? Simarpreet Singh Thanks for A2A. When will the result of tier 3 will come? This is the question which is hovering around everyone's mind. You know what only SSC and Govt can tell us when this result will come. And no one like you me can tell. Havent you seen, there is no vedio by any youtuber guessing about the result date. Everyone is confounded by the present situation. The aspirant who was very optimistic about his future and was expecting result on 8 th may is seeing future as a bleak as no event is occuring. Every exam has been postponed. This is very bad phase for all aspirants who were thinking of job in this year. 2017 aspirant to 2018,19,20 be like... Humne Bhugta hai Ab tum Bhugto.. This is because Ssc is very slow commision. It always make some issues so that process may get delayed. In 2017 there Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:54:39.603Z"),
    "question" : "When will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 results be declared? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e190c817f0398fc1e50"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-standard-NCERT-books-I-should-read-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which standard NCERT books I should read for SSC CGL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:01.986Z"),
    "question" : "Which standard NCERT books I should read for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e2f0c817f0398fc1e66"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-Paramount-the-best-coaching-institute-in-Delhi-for-the-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "No. No coaching can be best. They are just befooling you. If you read previous answers you can get to know their experience. They just give you a damn impressive demo and then they start cheating you. So i would suggest you to not go to any coaching. If you have week basics and not a good academic then firat work over them. Else if you need coaching then go for some small institutions because in Paramount and other coachings there are so huge batches about 1500–3000 students in a single batches. They keep teacher in one room and he teaches from there and other students seit in other rooms and study through projector. So if you want to attend a class like this it would be better you watch YouTube videos. Online guruji is a channel on YouTube. He teaches everything for SSC. Unacademy is diff Continue Reading No. No coaching can be best. They are just befooling you. If you read previous answers you can get to know their experience. They just give you a damn impressive demo and then they start cheating you. So i would suggest you to not go to any coaching. If you have week basics and not a good academic then firat work over them. Else if you need coaching then go for some small institutions because in Paramount and other coachings there are so huge batches about 1500–3000 students in a single batches. They keep teacher in one room and he teaches from there and other students seit in other rooms and study through projector. So if you want to attend a class like this it would be better you watch YouTube videos. Online guruji is a channel on YouTube. He teaches everything for SSC. Unacademy is diff Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:23.875Z"),
    "question" : "Is Paramount the best coaching institute in Delhi for the SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e430c817f0398fc1e78"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-apply-for-SSC-MTS?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I apply for SSC MTS?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:30:43.935Z"),
    "question" : "How do I apply for SSC MTS? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e580c817f0398fc1f3c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-clear-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-the-final-year-of-a-degree?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Partha Kansabanik 12",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:04.004Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to clear the SSC CGL exam in the final year of a degree? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e6a0c817f0398fc1f4c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-English-for-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Before answering this question, I wanna share my score of english section in various ssc exams:- SSC cgl tier 2 2017 168.5/200. Ssc cpo tier1 2017 42.5/50. Ssc cgl tier1 2017 41.5/50. Practice of numerous questions and their continuous revision is the key to improve English for SSC CGL. So, how to improve it? Sources and strategy to prepare English to get more than 80% makes are given below: English section of ssc cgl consists of 3 sections:- Vocabulary - It includes antonym, synonym, one word substitution, spelling errors, phrasal verbs.(Don't ignore phrasal verbs because you can get 2–3 questions in tier 1 and 5–10 questions in tier2 form this chapter. This chapter can give you an edge over other candidates in exam. I regret because I didn't prepare this chapter before ssc cgl tier 1 and lost feContinue Reading Before answering this question, I wanna share my score of english section in various ssc exams:- SSC cgl tier 2 2017 168.5/200. Ssc cpo tier1 2017 42.5/50. Ssc cgl tier1 2017 41.5/50. Practice of numerous questions and their continuous revision is the key to improve English for SSC CGL. So, how to improve it? Sources and strategy to prepare English to get more than 80% makes are given below: English section of ssc cgl consists of 3 sections:- Vocabulary - It includes antonym, synonym, one word substitution, spelling errors, phrasal verbs.(Don't ignore phrasal verbs because you can get 2–3 questions in tier 1 and 5–10 questions in tier2 form this chapter. This chapter can give you an edge over other candidates in exam. I regret because I didn't prepare this chapter before ssc cgl tier 1 and lost feContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:22.132Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve English for SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e7d0c817f0398fc1f60"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-tentative-month-in-which-SSC-CGL-2018-be-held?-",
    "answer" : "This question is there in minds of many aspirants. Got many mails regarding this query. The date of SSC CGL 2018 prelims has not yet been finalized. The issue is serious as there is a lot of uncertainty in air.There are several reasons for this and I am putting them as following : One very strong reason is that there are number of judicial cases going on against SSC. These cases are on various examinations conducted by SSC.One of the most vocal matter is the case by some unsuccessful candidates against SSC CGL 2016 . This case has stopped the joining of thousands of successful candidates so it has delayed the functioning in other exams. This case has got some media attention as well. Successful candidates are the victims here as they are being stopped from their rightful joining.There is anContinue Reading This question is there in minds of many aspirants. Got many mails regarding this query. The date of SSC CGL 2018 prelims has not yet been finalized. The issue is serious as there is a lot of uncertainty in air.There are several reasons for this and I am putting them as following : One very strong reason is that there are number of judicial cases going on against SSC. These cases are on various examinations conducted by SSC.One of the most vocal matter is the case by some unsuccessful candidates against SSC CGL 2016 . This case has stopped the joining of thousands of successful candidates so it has delayed the functioning in other exams. This case has got some media attention as well. Successful candidates are the victims here as they are being stopped from their rightful joining.There is anContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:31:41.211Z"),
    "question" : "What is the tentative month in which SSC CGL 2018 be held? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376e920c817f0398fc2024"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-did-you-score-in-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1?-",
    "answer" : "After filling the form a year back, I had almost thought of not appearing for SSC CGL this year. My examination Centre was Noida, while my hometown is Jammu. That is because when I had filled the form, I was still in Delhi and I didn’t expect CGL to get delayed by almost 1 year. I was almost sure that my parents wouldn’t suggest me to appear in the exam.However, it didn’t happen. I prepared for CGL for just 2 weeks before the exam. Moreover, since I had to travel from Jammu to Noida for the exam, I stopped preparing two days before the exam. So, I attempted around 75 questions out of 100. My shift was 11th june , 3rd shift. And I had expected to get not more than 10 questions wrong. After getting answer key,my score goes like this : Reasoning : Attempted : 24/25Correct: 18General Knowledge:Continue Reading After filling the form a year back, I had almost thought of not appearing for SSC CGL this year. My examination Centre was Noida, while my hometown is Jammu. That is because when I had filled the form, I was still in Delhi and I didn’t expect CGL to get delayed by almost 1 year. I was almost sure that my parents wouldn’t suggest me to appear in the exam.However, it didn’t happen. I prepared for CGL for just 2 weeks before the exam. Moreover, since I had to travel from Jammu to Noida for the exam, I stopped preparing two days before the exam. So, I attempted around 75 questions out of 100. My shift was 11th june , 3rd shift. And I had expected to get not more than 10 questions wrong. After getting answer key,my score goes like this : Reasoning : Attempted : 24/25Correct: 18General Knowledge:Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:02.773Z"),
    "question" : "How much did you score in the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376eb70c817f0398fc2045"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-materials-should-an-SSC-CGL-aspirant-follow?-",
    "answer" : "Prasad Bagauli, former Career Counselor  at Triumphant Institute of Management Education (2018)Answered 4 years agoWhat materials should an SSC CGL aspirant follow? Prasad Bagauli Well..study material is one thing that people have a lot of confusion about. Striking the right resources and putting in the right amount of time is very important. I personally followed this strategy: For quant -  go through basics of all topics from RS Aggarwal. IF YOU do have good time, go through Arun sharma’s book for CAT as well. That’s because, once you solve quant book of his, you will find quant questions in all areas of any comp exam, a cakewalk. So prefer this. Rest is all about practise…practise.. For Logical - Best way is to go through some good youtube channels. I will list out those that I found extremely good. Meritshine, Unacademy, Endeavor careers, Gaurav Bakliwal and Study smart. Keep practising..coz logical is damn interesting and keeps you wanting. English - Read The Hind Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:39.344Z"),
    "question" : "What materials should an SSC CGL aspirant follow? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ec90c817f0398fc2107"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-myself-for-SSC-exam-at-home?-",
    "answer" : "Akshay અક્ષય ಅಕ್ಷಯ್ अक्षय, A Teacher by Passion ; A student by choiceAnswered 1 year ago · Author has 171 answers and 241K answer viewsHow can I prepare myself for SSC exam at home? Akshay અક્ષય ಅಕ್ಷಯ್ अक्षय The following steps may be helpful if followed. 1- Analyse the syllabus, previous year’s question papers to understand what is asked and what is not asked in the exam. 2 - Analyse the pattern of the examination, duration taken, selection process, etc. to know the amount of resources in terms of financial backup, opportunity cost involved in the process. The joining may take a couple of years. 3 - After completing points 1 and 2, when you are sure that you are going to prepare for it, make a time table spreading over a period of time, both at the macro and micro level, setting goals to achieve by the time your at the exam door. Figure out the books, study material, internet sources. Talk to your seniors, anyone who has already cleared this examination for guidance if possible. Things are easy  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:32:57.861Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare myself for SSC exam at home? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376edd0c817f0398fc211f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-my-rank-in-SSC-CGL-to-get-ASO-in-MEA?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What should be my rank in SSC CGL to get ASO in MEA?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:17.990Z"),
    "question" : "What should be my rank in SSC CGL to get ASO in MEA? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ef50c817f0398fc2133"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-all-test-are-done-in-medical-test-for-SSC-cgl?-",
    "answer" : "SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination - Physical Standards A. Physical standard for the posts of Inspector (Central Excise) and Inspector (Preventive Officer), Inspector (Examiner): Candidates will have to satisfy the following minimum physical standards, failing which, they will not be eligible for appointment. (a) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Male Candidates) (i) Physical Standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test: Walking: 1600 metres in 15 minutes. Cycling: 8 Kms. In 30 minutes. (b) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Female Candidates) (i) Physical standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test Walking: 1 Km. in 20 minutes. Cycling: 3 Kms. in 25 minutes. The Physical Test for candidates will be conducted by the Ce Continue Reading SSC Combined Graduate Level Examination - Physical Standards A. Physical standard for the posts of Inspector (Central Excise) and Inspector (Preventive Officer), Inspector (Examiner): Candidates will have to satisfy the following minimum physical standards, failing which, they will not be eligible for appointment. (a) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Male Candidates) (i) Physical Standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test: Walking: 1600 metres in 15 minutes. Cycling: 8 Kms. In 30 minutes. (b) Inspector (Central Excise)/Inspector (Preventive Officer)/Inspector (Examiner) (Female Candidates) (i) Physical standards (Minimum) (ii) Physical Test Walking: 1 Km. in 20 minutes. Cycling: 3 Kms. in 25 minutes. The Physical Test for candidates will be conducted by the Ce Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:33:41.089Z"),
    "question" : "What all test are done in medical test for SSC cgl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f0b0c817f0398fc21f8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-SSC-coaching-in-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Sara Dwivedi My recommendation is for Mesorise Academy, Malviya Nagar for students who are serious and sincere about their SSC Prep. I have completed my Pol. Science Hons. from Aurvindo College of DU. I am just waiting for my graduation result to come. I decided to join SSC-CGL coaching institute in South Delhi. I called many institutes to get the knowledge of what they offer for ON-LINE-PREP. Some of them did not agree for Demo - Classes before getting admission , but a few institutes agreed to give free Demo - Classes, I also attended some of classes but I was not satisfied by the way they were teaching on Internet- Big group and no explanation for Individual queries. Some wants me to go through videos of erstwhile recorded classes to know the quality of teaching. It was more mechanical without cleari Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:03.573Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best SSC coaching in Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f1f0c817f0398fc220c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-site-to-learn-English-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Pushkar Bhatia There are so many teachers like Rini Ma’am in Subhash Nagar teaches good English for SSC CGL exams. If you are looking for 1 subject only. Then you must watch Vidya Guru youtube channel. There is a lady who posts amazing english videos. You can simply search with ‘Vidya Guru English’ in youtube search and Vidya Guru English lectures will appear there. Her presenting style is really good. I am very impressed with her lectures. I have also watched many of her lectures as I took their Online course. Due to some physical issue I don’t travel much. I decided my study to pursue from home only. I read good reviews of Vidya Guru online course and their videos are really great. Whole content is available there. VIdya Guru english video will really help you for enhancing English vocab. Sunidhi Trehan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:34:23.972Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best site to learn English for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f460c817f0398fc22ea"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-there-any-sectional-cutoffs-in-SSC-CGL-Tier-I?-",
    "answer" : "NO sectional cut off as all said. There is only one threshold you need to be over i.e, cut off which is total minimum score out of all the sections all together so there is only final cut off. It dosen't matter if you are weak in 1 or 2 portion or partially weak ever you can't clear it . you can clear it as in general overall cut of of tier 1 lies between100 - 110 at max.  But just scoring cut off marks would let you on backfoot in tier 2 as in final selection total marks are counted. Try to score approx 35 marks in every section than vary this section to section according to your strength but avg. Should come 35 for each, atleast make this a target. Rest is upon your strength. Best of Luck !",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:02.211Z"),
    "question" : "Are there any sectional cutoffs in SSC CGL Tier I? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f5a0c817f0398fc22fa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-SSC-CGL-2018-be-held-or-not?-",
    "answer" : "Commission was supposed to release the official notification regarding the SSC CGL 2018 exam on 21st April 2018 but now the SSC has extended the date of notification for the SSC CGL 2018 exam. The Staff Selection Commission will now release the SSC CGL Exam 2018 notification on 5th May 2018. The commission delayed the notification. This is because the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 exam was delayed. The SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 exam was scheduled to be held on March 31 but due to some reasons. The Tier 3 exam of SSC CGL 2017 will be held in the month of May. So,heat up yourself for the exam,don't give yourself excuse of delaying. Break a leg !!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:22.336Z"),
    "question" : "Will the SSC CGL 2018 be held or not? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f6e0c817f0398fc2310"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-you-share-your-final-Marks-of-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Depressed very much depressed… I (OBC) scored 643.5 including AAO exam.. And hopefully trying to see the result as per my expectation of AAO but…Some nuisance created on 15th Nov 19 , answer key revision…. I didn't get AAO but one friend low having score 642 got the AAO post……. I have scored 121.5 in Economic and Accounts exam, Unable to think, what had happened!? Why me?? In the last I get D06 post, knows nothing about this post….Donot know will join or not!!! Working in private industry with salary of 50K INR… I am hopeless, dejected.. If anyone have reasons to convince/guide me they are most welcome!!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:35:42.173Z"),
    "question" : "Can you share your final Marks of SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376f950c817f0398fc23e4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-score-in-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-2019?-",
    "answer" : "My exam was on 7 march 1st shift. One of the easiest shift. I hated the fact i got a easy shift bcoz i hv prepared very hard for almost 1 year nd i know unless i get a hard shift i m sure gonna lose about 10 marks bcoz increment will vary from 10 - 40 and and i can score easily 145+ however hard the shift is. So i know if i get easy shift i can score 140+ out of 150 in other 3 sections and i can max it up to 160 only bcoz my GS is weak and getting 180+ will be a very hard task. But if i did the same in hard shift 130+/150 and even 14–15 in GS with a raw of 140–145 i can jump to 180+ easily relating to the normalisation in 2018 tier 1. My raw marks are Reasoning - 42.5 GS - 22.5 Maths -50 English - 50 Total - 165/200. It happend exactly as i hv dreaded. Final marks came and as i was opening the ss Continue Reading My exam was on 7 march 1st shift. One of the easiest shift. I hated the fact i got a easy shift bcoz i hv prepared very hard for almost 1 year nd i know unless i get a hard shift i m sure gonna lose about 10 marks bcoz increment will vary from 10 - 40 and and i can score easily 145+ however hard the shift is. So i know if i get easy shift i can score 140+ out of 150 in other 3 sections and i can max it up to 160 only bcoz my GS is weak and getting 180+ will be a very hard task. But if i did the same in hard shift 130+/150 and even 14–15 in GS with a raw of 140–145 i can jump to 180+ easily relating to the normalisation in 2018 tier 1. My raw marks are Reasoning - 42.5 GS - 22.5 Maths -50 English - 50 Total - 165/200. It happend exactly as i hv dreaded. Final marks came and as i was opening the ss Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:21.404Z"),
    "question" : "What is your score in the SSC CGL Tier 1 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fb70c817f0398fc24ae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-SSC-coaching-in-Allahabad?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best SSC coaching in Allahabad?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:36:55.962Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best SSC coaching in Allahabad? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fca0c817f0398fc24c4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-2?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How did you prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 2?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:14.208Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 2? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376fdf0c817f0398fc24d8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-lecture-on-math-for-the-SSC-CGL-on-YouTube?-",
    "answer" : "There are multiple teachers teaching online saying one is best would be a disrespect to the other. All are great in there own unique way From Rakesh Yadav sir to Abhinay sharma sir. You can also visit my channel, I know I don't have all the fancy stuff like digital board but what I have is a will and creativity to teach in best manner possible. Recently I have uploaded a listen in which Complete boat and stream topic has been taught. You check it out. Every year at least one question is definitely asked from **Boat and stream ** in various government job exams you can confirm your 2 marks after watching this lesson completely. Timeline of concepts : 1. Basics of boat and stream 1:06 2. Question based on Downstream and Upstream speed 5:55 3. Concept of finding speed of boat and stream from Upstrea Continue Reading There are multiple teachers teaching online saying one is best would be a disrespect to the other. All are great in there own unique way From Rakesh Yadav sir to Abhinay sharma sir. You can also visit my channel, I know I don't have all the fancy stuff like digital board but what I have is a will and creativity to teach in best manner possible. Recently I have uploaded a listen in which Complete boat and stream topic has been taught. You check it out. Every year at least one question is definitely asked from **Boat and stream ** in various government job exams you can confirm your 2 marks after watching this lesson completely. Timeline of concepts : 1. Basics of boat and stream 1:06 2. Question based on Downstream and Upstream speed 5:55 3. Concept of finding speed of boat and stream from Upstrea Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:35.848Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best lecture on math for the SSC CGL on YouTube? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60376ff20c817f0398fc25a4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-eligibility-criteria-for-the-SSC-CGL-Exam?-",
    "answer" : "Maitery Mahajan For better preparation from your home itself, i would recommend you to join any good online SSC classes which cater to all your needs to crack the exam in first attempt. I myself have enrolled sometime back in Takshila Learning’s Brilliant 50 batch 8800999280 where i am getting personalised coaching for 1 year with updated video lectures, online test series, eBooks and faculty support via Whatsapp group and call facility (individual) and monthly webinars. You can also be part of this batch. If you are planning to appear for SSC CGL 2020-21, it is important that you go through the complete eligibility criteria thoroughly to avoid getting disqualified for the exam at a later stage. SSC CGL Eligibility: Age Limit The SSC CGL age criteria varies according to the different posts. Given in the tabl Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:37:54.800Z"),
    "question" : "What are the eligibility criteria for the SSC CGL Exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770040c817f0398fc25bd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-your-experience-with-the-SSC-CHSL-typing-test?-",
    "answer" : "In short it was exhausting but fairly good in the end. My DEST for DEO post and typing test for LDC/PA&SA was scheduled on the same day i.e. on 26th August, 2019 in Allahabad city of central region. The reporting time of the exam was 9:00 AM. I left the hotel room at 7:30 as the centre was in the outskirts of the city and I had never been to city before. I reached the centre around 8:00 and waited for more than an hour before the entry started. Everyone had to submit their bags and other belongings, and their was fairly good arrangement for that. After submitting the bag I had to wait for another hour before the main entry which started around 10 AM. There were around 100 candidates and we were divided into 7 groups of 25 candidates in each and sent to another building for the document verif Continue Reading In short it was exhausting but fairly good in the end. My DEST for DEO post and typing test for LDC/PA&SA was scheduled on the same day i.e. on 26th August, 2019 in Allahabad city of central region. The reporting time of the exam was 9:00 AM. I left the hotel room at 7:30 as the centre was in the outskirts of the city and I had never been to city before. I reached the centre around 8:00 and waited for more than an hour before the entry started. Everyone had to submit their bags and other belongings, and their was fairly good arrangement for that. After submitting the bag I had to wait for another hour before the main entry which started around 10 AM. There were around 100 candidates and we were divided into 7 groups of 25 candidates in each and sent to another building for the document verif Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:12.243Z"),
    "question" : "What is your experience with the SSC CHSL typing test? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770180c817f0398fc25ce"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-SSC-CGL-Tier-2-in-English?-",
    "answer" : "Many students believe that it is very cumbersome to score well in English section. On the other hand, it can be one of the easiest and scoring subjects if you prepare well and with right strategy. In tier 2 exam, you have to face 200 questions of English language carrying a weightage of 1 mark each with a penalty of .25 marks for each wrong answer. Let’s have a look on the topics and the number of questions asked in previous year exam in English section:  Clearly, paper of English section is divided in three broad categories: Reading Comprehension Grammar Vocabulary So, strengthening each topic is the master key to score good marks in English Section. Remember, castle is not build in a day but if you spend time consistently, you can perform well in relatively less time. Strategy to Approach the to Continue Reading Many students believe that it is very cumbersome to score well in English section. On the other hand, it can be one of the easiest and scoring subjects if you prepare well and with right strategy. In tier 2 exam, you have to face 200 questions of English language carrying a weightage of 1 mark each with a penalty of .25 marks for each wrong answer. Let’s have a look on the topics and the number of questions asked in previous year exam in English section:  Clearly, paper of English section is divided in three broad categories: Reading Comprehension Grammar Vocabulary So, strengthening each topic is the master key to score good marks in English Section. Remember, castle is not build in a day but if you spend time consistently, you can perform well in relatively less time. Strategy to Approach the to Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:38:32.775Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for SSC CGL Tier 2 in English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037703f0c817f0398fc26a9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-centre-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-Chennai?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best coaching centre for the SSC CGL exam in Chennai?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:11.361Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching centre for the SSC CGL exam in Chennai? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770670c817f0398fc26d5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-score-150+-in-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "9 important points to score better in ssc 2017. Many people apply for SSC CGL Exam without having any knowledge which reduces their chances of clearing the exam. So we have come across many important points which they might not be aware of but should be kept in the mind of the aspirants to score well in SSC Exam. Here is the list of such points which the aspirants should go through to excel in the upcoming SSC Exam. 1. SSC Repeats questions year after year The biggest truth with SSC is that SSC do repeat questions and that too in all sections (Reasoning, Maths, English and General Awareness). Have a look at the last 4-5 year question papers of SSC CGL Exams and you will find out that, there are around 2-3 questions in each section which are repeated every time. It is therefore necessary to sol Continue Reading 9 important points to score better in ssc 2017. Many people apply for SSC CGL Exam without having any knowledge which reduces their chances of clearing the exam. So we have come across many important points which they might not be aware of but should be kept in the mind of the aspirants to score well in SSC Exam. Here is the list of such points which the aspirants should go through to excel in the upcoming SSC Exam. 1. SSC Repeats questions year after year The biggest truth with SSC is that SSC do repeat questions and that too in all sections (Reasoning, Maths, English and General Awareness). Have a look at the last 4-5 year question papers of SSC CGL Exams and you will find out that, there are around 2-3 questions in each section which are repeated every time. It is therefore necessary to sol Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:39:51.256Z"),
    "question" : "How do I score 150+ in SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037709b0c817f0398fc27af"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-normalization-happen-in-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Does normalization happen in SSC-CGL exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:40:43.035Z"),
    "question" : "Does normalization happen in SSC-CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770b80c817f0398fc287b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-months-of-current-affairs-do-I-have-to-read-for-the-SSC-CGL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "Roohi Jaiswal, B.Com from Bachelor of Commerce Degrees (2016)Answered January 20, 2021 · Author has 104 answers and 73.3K answer viewsHow many months of current affairs do I have to read for the SSC CGL 2018? Roohi Jaiswal Atleast 6–7 months of current affairs are required to study in order to get full marks in current affairs portion of SSC exam. I have a better idea for you to prepare for the Current Affairs for the SSC Exams. Just go with the online videos of Vidya Guru’s Current Affairs. Their current affairs videos are just superb. You can get the best help by these videos. By these videos, you will get latest videos and all past time current affairs as well. You can watch these videos for the explanation of each event and then just make the notes by these videos. This is the free youtube session. You will get all the information about the events happening in the Country and World. Reading the magazine and newspaper is just a waste of time. Because you need atleast 2 hours to go through the newspaper or ma Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:41:12.690Z"),
    "question" : "How many months of current affairs do I have to read for the SSC CGL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770d50c817f0398fc2894"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-institute-for-SSC-CGL-preparation-in-Kolkata?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best coaching institute for SSC CGL preparation in Kolkata?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:41:41.125Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching institute for SSC CGL preparation in Kolkata? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603770ec0c817f0398fc295b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-YouTube-channel-for-the-best-advanced-maths-videos-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Hello In SSC CGL maths is very important subject. It carries 50 marks in tier 1 and 200 marks in tier 2. If you want to prepare for Quantitative aptitude through videos then this is the best way to gain knowledge quickly. but firstly, you should know the complete information of SSC CGL Recruitment. Here below i am providing you some best advance maths videos for SSC CGL. TrigonometryGeometryAlgebraQuadrilateral Geometry",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:42:04.554Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best YouTube channel for the best advanced maths videos for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771030c817f0398fc2970"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-will-happen-now-as-the-supreme-court-has-put-stay-on-the-result-of-the-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Samar Pratap Till this point of time, I was extremely optimistic that everything will work out fine in the end. I was not that much perturbed with delays as I was getting enough time to pursue my hobbies. Today when I was going through the article regarding stay on exam, one line particularly caught my attention and literally petrified me Delivering its verdict, the court said that it can’t permit people benefitting from SSC examination scam to get into service, Reading this line again and again gave this slight hint that exam might get cancelled. Oh God, did I just write the most dreaded statement ? I sincerely hope that nothing like this happens. Just like everyone else, I am nowhere close to what I was during tier 2. I scored 331 in tier 2 which is not a great score but not bad either. If I feel this s Continue Reading Till this point of time, I was extremely optimistic that everything will work out fine in the end. I was not that much perturbed with delays as I was getting enough time to pursue my hobbies. Today when I was going through the article regarding stay on exam, one line particularly caught my attention and literally petrified me Delivering its verdict, the court said that it can’t permit people benefitting from SSC examination scam to get into service, Reading this line again and again gave this slight hint that exam might get cancelled. Oh God, did I just write the most dreaded statement ? I sincerely hope that nothing like this happens. Just like everyone else, I am nowhere close to what I was during tier 2. I scored 331 in tier 2 which is not a great score but not bad either. If I feel this s Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:42:27.530Z"),
    "question" : "What will happen now as the supreme court has put stay on the result of the SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771400c817f0398fc2a5b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-good-institutes-in-Chandigarh-for-SSC-CGL-coaching?-",
    "answer" : "Mukesh Kapoor, lives in Chandigarh, India (2008-present)Updated 1 year ago · Author has 96 answers and 172.1K answer viewsWhat are good institutes in Chandigarh for SSC CGL coaching? Mukesh Kapoor Dear Candidate, If you are looking for an institute that provides structured and targeted SSC CGL coaching in Chandigarh, there is only one name i.e The IBS Institute. The Institute has been a frontrunner in the provider of coaching of all the SSC examinations for more than a decade. The reasons that make the institute as the leader in the niche are manifold. Institute has been delivering quality education in the field for approximately a decade. The institute’s one of a kind study material is complete in all aspects and the candidate doesn’t have to refer to anything else. The faculty is extremely talented and some of them have actually cleared the exam in the past and thus can provide the students with a better exam perspective. The test series is exhaustive which provides the candidates w Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:43:28.770Z"),
    "question" : "What are good institutes in Chandigarh for SSC CGL coaching? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771600c817f0398fc2b2d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-a-GS-for-the-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Let us first understand what is mostly asked in ssc gs section that is what are the favourite topics of ssc. If you are a science background student than you get an extra edge as approx 10 questions of physics, chemistry and biology are asked and you need to work only on bio section if you are an engineer or so. So prepare science first simply by going through the concept and than revising regularly. Go for previous year question papers of gs so that you can get an insight of how the questions are asked. Prepare science first I will tell you the strategy for others in another answer. This is my first answer guys regarding SSC. As I also have cracked SSC CGL pre and mains 2017 and have written descriptive of SSC chsl 2017. Hope this will help.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:00.914Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare a GS for the SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037718c0c817f0398fc2b56"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-book-lists-for-the-SSC-CGL-2020-if-I-am-starting-from-scratch?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the book lists for the SSC CGL 2020 if I am starting from scratch?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:44:44.675Z"),
    "question" : "What are the book lists for the SSC CGL 2020 if I am starting from scratch? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771a60c817f0398fc2c1f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-in-3-months?-",
    "answer" : "Harshit Shukla If CGL 2018 is Your first attempt then 3 months is not enough but yes it's not very hard to crack pre exam in first attempt. You have to follow some best books and online sources. MATHS— KIRAN chapterwise 8900+ is best book.Watch UNACADEMY videos and learn tricks. Some best Educators on that platform are HARSHIT SHUKLA, CHETAN MEENA, BINEESH.WATCH ABHINAY MATHS YOUTUBE CHANNEL.Try to attempt mocks regular. It will boost up your preparation slowly. And yes shuru me marks km aynge to sad mt ho jana. Dheere dheere hoga increase.English — MIRROR OF COMMONS ERROR BY A.K.SINGHSP BAKSHI GENERAL ENGLISHMB PUBLICATION PREVIOUS YEAR SET PAPERSDOWNLOAD IDIOMS AND ONE WORD SUBSTITUTION PDF From Qmaths websites. ( Just Google)GENERAL STUDY - This part is most uncertain for securing marks. But also it will c Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:10.480Z"),
    "question" : "How can one prepare for the SSC CGL Tier 1 in 3 months? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771bd0c817f0398fc2c32"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Staff Selection Commission (SSC) is an organization under Government of India to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices.Career in SSC Staff Selection Commission conducts a lot of exams every year. It is a right platform for the people who are eager to set their career in Government jobs. It provides a variety of jobs on the basis of different educational backgrounds. The pay scale for the job gets varied on the type of job selected. Jobs offered by SSC 1. Inspector of Income Tax 2. Inspector (Central Excise) 3. Inspector (Preventive Officer) 4. Inspector (Examiner) 5. Inspector of Posts 6. Assistant Enforcement Officer 7. Compiler 8. Divisional Accountant 9. Auditors 10. UDC’s 11. Tax Assistants 12. A Continue Reading Staff Selection Commission (SSC) is an organization under Government of India to recruit staff for various posts in the various Ministries and Departments of the Government of India and in Subordinate Offices.Career in SSC Staff Selection Commission conducts a lot of exams every year. It is a right platform for the people who are eager to set their career in Government jobs. It provides a variety of jobs on the basis of different educational backgrounds. The pay scale for the job gets varied on the type of job selected. Jobs offered by SSC 1. Inspector of Income Tax 2. Inspector (Central Excise) 3. Inspector (Preventive Officer) 4. Inspector (Examiner) 5. Inspector of Posts 6. Assistant Enforcement Officer 7. Compiler 8. Divisional Accountant 9. Auditors 10. UDC’s 11. Tax Assistants 12. A Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:45:33.373Z"),
    "question" : "What is SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771e70c817f0398fc2d0c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Where-is-the-best-scopes-between-banking-jobs-and-SSC-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, Well if i have to be honest i believe that choosing SSC would be a good idea, there are many reasons for that, First, mode of exam- see if you are good with maths concepts and your knowledge about english is also good, you can do fairly well in CGl or any other SSC exam, but for banking there are alot of different points that you have to keep in mind, banking syllabus consists maths(calculative), english(lengthy), reasoning ( hard level) and GK( vast area), so all in all syllabus of Bank is way too hard, then in mains also you have to study for all the section adding computer awarness to it too, but in SSC There are only 2 papers in mains, english and maths. There is interview in bank PO, which is absent in SSC. What we get- well after all the hard work you put, what you get is a job w Continue Reading Hello, Well if i have to be honest i believe that choosing SSC would be a good idea, there are many reasons for that, First, mode of exam- see if you are good with maths concepts and your knowledge about english is also good, you can do fairly well in CGl or any other SSC exam, but for banking there are alot of different points that you have to keep in mind, banking syllabus consists maths(calculative), english(lengthy), reasoning ( hard level) and GK( vast area), so all in all syllabus of Bank is way too hard, then in mains also you have to study for all the section adding computer awarness to it too, but in SSC There are only 2 papers in mains, english and maths. There is interview in bank PO, which is absent in SSC. What we get- well after all the hard work you put, what you get is a job w Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:15.258Z"),
    "question" : "Where is the best scopes between banking jobs and SSC jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603771fb0c817f0398fc2d1a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-coaching-center-in-Patna-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Well staying in Patna people always do think that no one would be able to crack any exam and they would be left with both the legs on two boats at the same time but this is the Up-trending Apocryphal!! Patna and taking Bihar as a whole has ever since been introducing the maximum numbers of IPS officers through UPSC every year!! So it doesn't mean that we are not having the talent… Of course we are blessed with that talent of workin hard and forcing to contemplate the entire country about our labour and our innate talents!! However Staff Selection Commission(SSC) is one of the easiest exams to crack for Under Graduate aspirants or applicants, Unlike JEE, CLAT, NDA, SCRA etc. The biggest flaw that the question paper has in SSC is the repetition of the same pattern of questions every Second Yea Continue Reading Well staying in Patna people always do think that no one would be able to crack any exam and they would be left with both the legs on two boats at the same time but this is the Up-trending Apocryphal!! Patna and taking Bihar as a whole has ever since been introducing the maximum numbers of IPS officers through UPSC every year!! So it doesn't mean that we are not having the talent… Of course we are blessed with that talent of workin hard and forcing to contemplate the entire country about our labour and our innate talents!! However Staff Selection Commission(SSC) is one of the easiest exams to crack for Under Graduate aspirants or applicants, Unlike JEE, CLAT, NDA, SCRA etc. The biggest flaw that the question paper has in SSC is the repetition of the same pattern of questions every Second Yea Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:35.295Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best coaching center in Patna for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772100c817f0398fc2dde"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-revise-maths-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Prashant Singh This happens with everyone, all tends to forget the previous questions especially the tough one or which are a bit different from other questions. Dont worry just check how it is solved and do it again. Things to remember while doing any chapter is write down all important points separately while solving, especially formula's or any important aspect of a question. Do not solve 10 books once, solve one or two books many times. Here everyone will give you a list of many books which for every subject say 6–7 books for maths, 3–4 for english, 3–4 for reasoning and for gs there may be much more. Is it practical to cover all those books comprehensively. This only will waste your time. Take two books i would suggest one for advance maths portion and one for the remaining portion. If any aspect is b Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:46:56.078Z"),
    "question" : "How do I revise maths SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772260c817f0398fc2df9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-we-publish-the-SSC-results-for-2018?-",
    "answer" : "This is fantastic work for Students. Who are going to complete their SSC level. As my thinking upcoming 6th May going to publish “SSC result 2018” from education ministry of Bangladesh. Though, Students will get the results from online, sms as well as their organization. so, don’t worry to check everywhere. I am suggested your SSC Exam result 2018 via SMS method below:-  As you know, the official education board result going to publish result on Education Board Bangladesh or WEB BASED RESULT PUBLICATION I hope you would be happy to see this news. I wish very best you all students of SSC Exam 2018. Thanks. Continue Reading This is fantastic work for Students. Who are going to complete their SSC level. As my thinking upcoming 6th May going to publish “SSC result 2018” from education ministry of Bangladesh. Though, Students will get the results from online, sms as well as their organization. so, don’t worry to check everywhere. I am suggested your SSC Exam result 2018 via SMS method below:-  As you know, the official education board result going to publish result on Education Board Bangladesh or WEB BASED RESULT PUBLICATION I hope you would be happy to see this news. I wish very best you all students of SSC Exam 2018. Thanks. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:18.072Z"),
    "question" : "When will we publish the SSC results for 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772400c817f0398fc2e14"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-are-the-best-books-for-the-SSC-CHSL-2018?-",
    "answer" : "As I Cracked SSC CHSL 2016 (tier 1) in first attempt so may I'll be able to answer your question So..... According to me... When you gone through previous year question papers It seems the ssc chsl is too much competative exam bt the questions asked are not too tough as compared to SSC CGL... So if you build your concepts from below mention books and practice allot of previous year questions and mock tests you surely crack ssc chsl 2018... So... The Tier 1 Consist of four sections.... 1) Reasoning... The reasoning section is too easy section where you score 50/50 easily by practicing allot previous year question papers.. For reasoning this two books are more than sufficient.. * Verbal and Non verbal Reasoning by R. S Agarwal. *Kiran's previous year que Papers R. 7500 2) English... This section Continue Reading As I Cracked SSC CHSL 2016 (tier 1) in first attempt so may I'll be able to answer your question So..... According to me... When you gone through previous year question papers It seems the ssc chsl is too much competative exam bt the questions asked are not too tough as compared to SSC CGL... So if you build your concepts from below mention books and practice allot of previous year questions and mock tests you surely crack ssc chsl 2018... So... The Tier 1 Consist of four sections.... 1) Reasoning... The reasoning section is too easy section where you score 50/50 easily by practicing allot previous year question papers.. For reasoning this two books are more than sufficient.. * Verbal and Non verbal Reasoning by R. S Agarwal. *Kiran's previous year que Papers R. 7500 2) English... This section Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:47:44.466Z"),
    "question" : "Which are the best books for the SSC CHSL 2018? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772580c817f0398fc2ee0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-SSC-CGL-2017-Tier-2-results-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "If everything goes on smoothly . We can expect answer key by 10 March and objections will be raised by say 20 March. Add one month for final result. So final result will be declared some where around 10–15 Apr. Now I know most of you say tier 3 is fixed on 31 March. Let me tell it was fixed keeping in view that tier 2 was supposed to be conducted in January. Now it look like tier will be conducted in April last or may 1 st week , unless ssc decide to conduct tier 3 for all 1.9 lakh.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:48:08.513Z"),
    "question" : "When will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 2 results be declared? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772800c817f0398fc2f04"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-marks-are-required-in-SSC-CGL-to-get-placed-in-the-income-tax-department-in-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How many marks are required in SSC CGL to get placed in the income tax department in Delhi?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:48:48.528Z"),
    "question" : "How many marks are required in SSC CGL to get placed in the income tax department in Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037729a0c817f0398fc2fcd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-book-should-I-refer-for-SSC-English?-",
    "answer" : "As your question is basic to advacnce so accordingly answer is Plinth to paramount - first you need to clear your concepts . This book is like mother to ssc english and does spoon feeding though students have cleared ssc english by reading only this book but that was scenario of past as level is increasing day by dayS. P. Bakshi- this is 2nd book which you need to read or i would say compulsory for ssc mains. Go through this book at least twice to clear your advance concepts of grammer , idiom phrase and other stuff.R.s Aggarwal- yes you read it right. This book of english is a bit advance than s.p. bakshi. Word meaning ,idiom phrases , one word are of advance level discussed in this book. Good thing is this book is for practice purpose mainly but don't get demoralised if you are not able tContinue Reading As your question is basic to advacnce so accordingly answer is Plinth to paramount - first you need to clear your concepts . This book is like mother to ssc english and does spoon feeding though students have cleared ssc english by reading only this book but that was scenario of past as level is increasing day by dayS. P. Bakshi- this is 2nd book which you need to read or i would say compulsory for ssc mains. Go through this book at least twice to clear your advance concepts of grammer , idiom phrase and other stuff.R.s Aggarwal- yes you read it right. This book of english is a bit advance than s.p. bakshi. Word meaning ,idiom phrases , one word are of advance level discussed in this book. Good thing is this book is for practice purpose mainly but don't get demoralised if you are not able tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:14.793Z"),
    "question" : "Which book should I refer for SSC-English? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772b70c817f0398fc2fe9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-best-online-test-series-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "I may not be the right person to answer this question as I scored just 135 marks in Tier 1,2016. But still I am writing the answer because I had taken all these tests before my Tier 1 exam.So,here goes my review… 1)Pinnacle SSC CGL- I wrote their free/challenge tests. Challenge tests are of high level whereas other tests are of the same level as actual paper,sometimes i found it lengthy.2) Career power-I don’t know how they are designing the test series this year,but last year the paper was around 50% similar to bank exams.So,I personally found it good for familiarizing with online exam environment.But if you are taking mocks seriously,then think twice before buying it.3)SSC Tube-I had purchased this one. Some papers were easy,some were tough…the level of exam was similar to actual paper. Continue Reading I may not be the right person to answer this question as I scored just 135 marks in Tier 1,2016. But still I am writing the answer because I had taken all these tests before my Tier 1 exam.So,here goes my review… 1)Pinnacle SSC CGL- I wrote their free/challenge tests. Challenge tests are of high level whereas other tests are of the same level as actual paper,sometimes i found it lengthy.2) Career power-I don’t know how they are designing the test series this year,but last year the paper was around 50% similar to bank exams.So,I personally found it good for familiarizing with online exam environment.But if you are taking mocks seriously,then think twice before buying it.3)SSC Tube-I had purchased this one. Some papers were easy,some were tough…the level of exam was similar to actual paper. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:49:43.734Z"),
    "question" : "Which is best online test series for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603772e90c817f0398fc30c5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-questions-in-SSC-CGL-repeat?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for R2A. If you had asked this question before Tier 2 of CGL 17, my answer would have been different. Well, Yes, Questions are repeated in SSC CGL but the number of such questions are very less. What exactly repeated is the type of questions and approach to solve them by candidates. So, better go through each type of questions rather than getting in such things. All the best Harsh Mangla",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:50:33.005Z"),
    "question" : "Do questions in SSC CGL repeat? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037731a0c817f0398fc31a7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-geometry-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "A2A I would suggest start with ncert, If you struggle with basic concepts begin from class 6- then 7, 8, 9 & 10. Next, jump to RD Sharma maths for class 9–10 (Chapters concerned with Geometry). If you think that you have a basic hold on geometry, then watch Advance Maths video lectures of Abhinay Maths on you tube and take notes of geometry topics. He has explained basics and how to approach questions particularly relevant for SSC exams. For practice you can use any compilation of previous year papers (atleast 10 years) and mock tests available on various websites. These mock tests will take care of time management. Once you are done, Take up CAT books, try solving questions up to level 2, this will give you an extra edge. If you find this step difficult Watch Amiya Maths channel on you tube, i Continue Reading A2A I would suggest start with ncert, If you struggle with basic concepts begin from class 6- then 7, 8, 9 & 10. Next, jump to RD Sharma maths for class 9–10 (Chapters concerned with Geometry). If you think that you have a basic hold on geometry, then watch Advance Maths video lectures of Abhinay Maths on you tube and take notes of geometry topics. He has explained basics and how to approach questions particularly relevant for SSC exams. For practice you can use any compilation of previous year papers (atleast 10 years) and mock tests available on various websites. These mock tests will take care of time management. Once you are done, Take up CAT books, try solving questions up to level 2, this will give you an extra edge. If you find this step difficult Watch Amiya Maths channel on you tube, i Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:51:22.941Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for geometry in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773540c817f0398fc328a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-prepare-for-SSC-CGL-tier-3?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How did you prepare for SSC CGL tier 3?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:52:20.164Z"),
    "question" : "How did you prepare for SSC CGL tier 3? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773880c817f0398fc3371"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-exam-in-one-month?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, Questions like this, “how should i prepare for cgl2019 or cgl 18 in 5 months or 3 months or 2 months and now this,one month” keep coming in my feed. I will keep answering these until the very day of actual examination :-) If you know abcd of warfare,ssc cgl,unlike upsc which is like traditional warfare, is more like a Blitzkrieg or swift action. In Blitzkrieg type of warfare,you have some strong points and coordination. You just bypass the enemy strongholds and encirle them to be exploited later. The point i want to make out is,you can crack tier1 in one month provided: Your base is strong and coordinated,You are good in mathematics, are scoring 110+ in any of the mocks. Following things you can skip: Antonyms and synonyms (i skipped them and still scored 43/50 in tier1 English)Level 2 anContinue Reading Hello, Questions like this, “how should i prepare for cgl2019 or cgl 18 in 5 months or 3 months or 2 months and now this,one month” keep coming in my feed. I will keep answering these until the very day of actual examination :-) If you know abcd of warfare,ssc cgl,unlike upsc which is like traditional warfare, is more like a Blitzkrieg or swift action. In Blitzkrieg type of warfare,you have some strong points and coordination. You just bypass the enemy strongholds and encirle them to be exploited later. The point i want to make out is,you can crack tier1 in one month provided: Your base is strong and coordinated,You are good in mathematics, are scoring 110+ in any of the mocks. Following things you can skip: Antonyms and synonyms (i skipped them and still scored 43/50 in tier1 English)Level 2 anContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:12.201Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the SSC CGL exam in one month? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773a20c817f0398fc338a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-institute-is-better-for-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which institute is better for SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:53:38.911Z"),
    "question" : "Which institute is better for SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603773df0c817f0398fc3472"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-SSC-CGL-2017-Tier-3-results-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "Simarpreet Singh, An Aspirant  146/200 in tier 1 CGL2019 4 March S2Answered 9 months ago · Author has 58 answers and 20.4K answer viewsWhen will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 results be declared? Simarpreet Singh Thanks for A2A. When will the result of tier 3 will come? This is the question which is hovering around everyone's mind. You know what only SSC and Govt can tell us when this result will come. And no one like you me can tell. Havent you seen, there is no vedio by any youtuber guessing about the result date. Everyone is confounded by the present situation. The aspirant who was very optimistic about his future and was expecting result on 8 th may is seeing future as a bleak as no event is occuring. Every exam has been postponed. This is very bad phase for all aspirants who were thinking of job in this year. 2017 aspirant to 2018,19,20 be like... Humne Bhugta hai Ab tum Bhugto.. This is because Ssc is very slow commision. It always make some issues so that process may get delayed. In 2017 there Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T09:54:39.603Z"),
    "question" : "When will the SSC CGL 2017 Tier 3 results be declared? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a320c817f0398fc4d2a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-bitter-truths-about-the-SSC-CGL-job?-",
    "answer" : "Some of the bitter truths about SSC CGL and most other govt. jobs are - unreasonable expectations of candidates which motivates them for preparation but tears apart soon after they join office. What are these expectations and why are they unreasonable. Let us understand. Unreasonable expectations: There is severe competition among candidates to clear SSC CGL. Every year 5–10 lakh candidates apply for 2–8 thousand posts. Most candidates spend more than a year to clear these exams. Point is, clearing these exams is no less than a victory in war (at least this is what candidates feel). Those who clear it are treated like hero in locality, in their school, by their juniors. Candidates feel they are class apart just because they have cleared an exam. Truth is- from government perspective you haveContinue Reading Some of the bitter truths about SSC CGL and most other govt. jobs are - unreasonable expectations of candidates which motivates them for preparation but tears apart soon after they join office. What are these expectations and why are they unreasonable. Let us understand. Unreasonable expectations: There is severe competition among candidates to clear SSC CGL. Every year 5–10 lakh candidates apply for 2–8 thousand posts. Most candidates spend more than a year to clear these exams. Point is, clearing these exams is no less than a victory in war (at least this is what candidates feel). Those who clear it are treated like hero in locality, in their school, by their juniors. Candidates feel they are class apart just because they have cleared an exam. Truth is- from government perspective you haveContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:21:38.781Z"),
    "question" : "What are the bitter truths about the SSC CGL job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a4c0c817f0398fc4df3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-sites-for-ssc-online-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the best sites for ssc online preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:22:04.229Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best sites for ssc online preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a620c817f0398fc4e07"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-quantitative-aptitude-for-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "The SSC CGL Selection Process involves Four Tiers as indicated below: Tier I – Computer Based ExaminationTier II – Computer Based ExaminationTier III – Pen and Paper Mode (Descriptive paper)Tier IV – Computer Proficiency Test/ Skill Test (wherever applicable)/ Document Verification The pattern of the Tier-I and Tier-II exam is similar for the quantitative aptitude section. Only difficulty level shall differ.The figure given below shall reveal the weightage of various topics that the SSC CGL examines. Basic Tips: Work on the BasicsTime ManagementLearn Short-cut MethodsTips During the Exam: If candidates find a particular question difficult, it essential not to waste time trying to solve it. Rather, candidates can move to the next question and come back to it only if the time permits.Candidates mContinue Reading The SSC CGL Selection Process involves Four Tiers as indicated below: Tier I – Computer Based ExaminationTier II – Computer Based ExaminationTier III – Pen and Paper Mode (Descriptive paper)Tier IV – Computer Proficiency Test/ Skill Test (wherever applicable)/ Document Verification The pattern of the Tier-I and Tier-II exam is similar for the quantitative aptitude section. Only difficulty level shall differ.The figure given below shall reveal the weightage of various topics that the SSC CGL examines. Basic Tips: Work on the BasicsTime ManagementLearn Short-cut MethodsTips During the Exam: If candidates find a particular question difficult, it essential not to waste time trying to solve it. Rather, candidates can move to the next question and come back to it only if the time permits.Candidates mContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:22:26.343Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve quantitative aptitude for SSC CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377a770c817f0398fc4e20"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-the-GradeUp-app-for-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How is the GradeUp app for SSC CGL preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:22:47.787Z"),
    "question" : "How is the GradeUp app for SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377aa60c817f0398fc4ef7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-much-did-your-score-increase-after-normalisation-in-the-SSC-CGL-2018-Tier-1?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Ishwar Jarewal I had my exam on 4th june in 2nd shift. Despite working really hard for 10 months, I could score only 157.5 in tier 1 (as per the answer keys). I was devastated after the exam but then I got to know that exam was tougher this time. So, I was also hopeful of getting good rank in tier 1. Whomsoever I talked to after the release of answer keys, everyone said that my score was really great. I also felt the same but to slightly lesser extent. Then all of a sudden, I received a pleasant surprise from SSC. Suddenly my phone beeped yesterday evening, with a text from my friend stating that the answer keys are released. I immediately rushed to website and after many tries, I was finally able to see my score. So here it is:- English 47.5/50 Maths 44/50 Gs :- 25.5/50 Reasoning :- 40.5 Total Raw score :- 157. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:23:34.428Z"),
    "question" : "How much did your score increase after normalisation in the SSC CGL 2018 Tier 1? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377acb0c817f0398fc4fd3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-highest-mark-in-the-SSC-2017-Tier-2-so-far?-",
    "answer" : "Last night while going through my Facebook feed, I saw one post from one of my teachers who was telling us to comment our marks honestly. I commented (I scored 478 BTW) and while waiting for response from that teacher, I went through other comments just to see how others have performed. Most of the students were in this range of 430–460 while a couple of them had scored above 480. Then I spotted a comment mentioning 515 as his score. By that time I didn't know about the scores achieved by students in English, so I was mighty surprised to see these many marks. Then I saw the name and something struck me. I opened that profile and it was confirmed. He was none other than Love O Gupta. Now most of you may not have heard his name but I had seen his lectures on unacademy. He is AIR 6 in SSC CGL  Continue Reading Last night while going through my Facebook feed, I saw one post from one of my teachers who was telling us to comment our marks honestly. I commented (I scored 478 BTW) and while waiting for response from that teacher, I went through other comments just to see how others have performed. Most of the students were in this range of 430–460 while a couple of them had scored above 480. Then I spotted a comment mentioning 515 as his score. By that time I didn't know about the scores achieved by students in English, so I was mighty surprised to see these many marks. Then I saw the name and something struck me. I opened that profile and it was confirmed. He was none other than Love O Gupta. Now most of you may not have heard his name but I had seen his lectures on unacademy. He is AIR 6 in SSC CGL  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:24:11.900Z"),
    "question" : "What is the highest mark in the SSC 2017 Tier 2 so far? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ae90c817f0398fc4fec"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-result-for-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-2016-be-declared?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, With the latest notification SSC CGL Tier 1 result will be declared on 15th October 2016 (Tentative). SSC released SSC CGL answer key and response sheet on 21st September 2016. You can challenge your answer if you think that your answer will is correct (100 rps per answer). All the best for your result. Tier 2 will going to be held on last month of the year (November or december). To crack SSC CGL Tier 2 exam you need to practice more in quant and english. try to solve cgl previous year question paper more and more Stay updated and Thank you..! Bharath Sai",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:24:41.473Z"),
    "question" : "When will the result for SSC CGL Tier 1 2016 be declared? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b090c817f0398fc50bd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-will-the-SSC-CGL-2020-notification-come?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  When will the SSC CGL 2020 notification come?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:25:13.113Z"),
    "question" : "When will the SSC CGL 2020 notification come? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b1e0c817f0398fc50cd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-WhatsApp-group-for-SSC-CGL-2017-serious-aspirants?-",
    "answer" : "I have been in and out of several WhatsApp groups during my CGL 2015 preparations. I would suggest to you refrain from joining any of these WhatsApp groups, because it's simply waste of time.. All they do is spamming and abusing each other. You are more likely to get Porn videos than study material.. If you are a female, don't even think about that. Even if there are serious aspirants, there is always spoilsports to spoil the group. I suggest you to follow good blogs on Internet. Follow SSC TUBE, Neetu singh in Facebook. There are some awesome Facebook groups for SSC CGL with more than 3,00,000 members. I suggest you to join in them",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:25:34.698Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any WhatsApp group for SSC CGL 2017 serious aspirants? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b340c817f0398fc5193"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-post-in-the-SSC-CGL-has-faster-promotions?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which post in the SSC CGL has faster promotions?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:25:56.771Z"),
    "question" : "Which post in the SSC CGL has faster promotions? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b4a0c817f0398fc51aa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-maths-book-for-the-SSC-CHSL-for-the-basic-concept?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Which is the best maths book for the SSC CHSL for the basic concept?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:26:18.001Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best maths book for the SSC CHSL for the basic concept? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b5d0c817f0398fc51be"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-best-online-resources-to-preparing-for-SSC-CGL-test?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are some best online resources to preparing for SSC CGL test?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:26:37.490Z"),
    "question" : "What are some best online resources to preparing for SSC CGL test? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b6f0c817f0398fc527d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-SSC-memo-number-in-an-SSC-certificate?-",
    "answer" : "Hello, SSC MEMO Number can be understood as Memorandum of Marks of the candidate that includes the following information: Hall Ticket NumberDate of BirthYear of ExaminationStream of ExaminationThanks :) Amol P Sawant",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:26:55.103Z"),
    "question" : "What is the SSC memo number in an SSC certificate? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377b980c817f0398fc52a7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-learn-antonyms-and-synonyms-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Its a kind of task that has to be done on a daily basis, you cant just conquer this overnight. Read a lot of books( English) and if that sounds boring, then newspaper because anyway you will have to answer the general knowledge part. So, read newspapers and most importantly have your own notebook where you can write down the few new words that seemed to be new to you. That way you can develop your word stock. Please do read the notebook every morning or before bed according to your convenience. As Antonyms and Synonyms are just words and if you know the meaning of the words then you can guestimate the words form the answers. And if possible Read NORMAN LEWIS WORD POWER MADE EASY Fantastic book, super easy to read and understand and pocket-friendly too (Rs 160) So, i hope this would be enough to  Continue Reading Its a kind of task that has to be done on a daily basis, you cant just conquer this overnight. Read a lot of books( English) and if that sounds boring, then newspaper because anyway you will have to answer the general knowledge part. So, read newspapers and most importantly have your own notebook where you can write down the few new words that seemed to be new to you. That way you can develop your word stock. Please do read the notebook every morning or before bed according to your convenience. As Antonyms and Synonyms are just words and if you know the meaning of the words then you can guestimate the words form the answers. And if possible Read NORMAN LEWIS WORD POWER MADE EASY Fantastic book, super easy to read and understand and pocket-friendly too (Rs 160) So, i hope this would be enough to  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:27:36.238Z"),
    "question" : "How do I learn antonyms and synonyms for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377be10c817f0398fc53a2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-would-be-the-best-book-for-SSC-JE-general-awareness?-",
    "answer" : "Manoj Mane As ssc je exam was conducted every year , so u should prepared it before 6 month of 1 yr before, as so many aspirants waiting for this exam. As general awareness section is very important to score more marks in less time. The general awareness section contains so many section such as history, geography, polity, economy, chemistry, physics, biology , zoology and current affairs. For the static gk you should prepare from one book which is mostly used in all government exam i.e. Lucent's General Knowledge and for current affairs you should prepare one news paper daily only important points. One last tip see the previous year questions papers which clear the idea of what type of questions generally asked in exam. Best of luck. Shivanshu Srivastava",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:28:49.451Z"),
    "question" : "What would be the best book for SSC JE general awareness? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c0c0c817f0398fc5471"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-dark-truths-about-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Samar Pratap Before answering this question, let me tell you two stories in brief. . Story 1 One of my friends was in relationship with a girl since college days. The couple was madly in love and it was obvious when they approached higher authority (parents) for approval. Girl's family was a bit conservative and orthodox. My friend was in a private job earning 11 LPA (around 72k in hand) but girl's father was a bit skeptical. He wanted a government employee for his daughter. My friend being madly in love asked his future sasur (father in law) to wait for some time till he gets a government job. It was April 2017 when he started preparing for SSC CGL. He realised early that it wasn't going to be as simple as it looked initially, so to give his best possible attempt he resigned from his job. He studied  Continue Reading Before answering this question, let me tell you two stories in brief. . Story 1 One of my friends was in relationship with a girl since college days. The couple was madly in love and it was obvious when they approached higher authority (parents) for approval. Girl's family was a bit conservative and orthodox. My friend was in a private job earning 11 LPA (around 72k in hand) but girl's father was a bit skeptical. He wanted a government employee for his daughter. My friend being madly in love asked his future sasur (father in law) to wait for some time till he gets a government job. It was April 2017 when he started preparing for SSC CGL. He realised early that it wasn't going to be as simple as it looked initially, so to give his best possible attempt he resigned from his job. He studied  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:29:32.841Z"),
    "question" : "What are the dark truths about SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c210c817f0398fc5535"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-perfect-preparation-strategy-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Nothing in this world is perfect. Same is the case with Preparation Strategy for CGL. Something that worked for someone else, May not be of much help to you. But there are some things that need to be kept in mind while preparing for it. I will take the liberty to write them down. First Make up your mind about preparing for it. Don't mix it up with other exams which don't have syllabus and pattern similar to it.Only choose material that is relevant to it. I have seen people trying to fill their brains with whatever they can find with For SSC CGL written over it. Choose one or two good books for each subject.Use previous years’ question papers of all SSC Exams for understanding the pattern of questions asked from each subject. Tier 1 Question Papers for all main exams of SSC have almost same Continue Reading Nothing in this world is perfect. Same is the case with Preparation Strategy for CGL. Something that worked for someone else, May not be of much help to you. But there are some things that need to be kept in mind while preparing for it. I will take the liberty to write them down. First Make up your mind about preparing for it. Don't mix it up with other exams which don't have syllabus and pattern similar to it.Only choose material that is relevant to it. I have seen people trying to fill their brains with whatever they can find with For SSC CGL written over it. Choose one or two good books for each subject.Use previous years’ question papers of all SSC Exams for understanding the pattern of questions asked from each subject. Tier 1 Question Papers for all main exams of SSC have almost same Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:29:53.001Z"),
    "question" : "What is the perfect preparation strategy for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c350c817f0398fc554f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-SSC-CGL-good?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is SSC CGL good?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:13.074Z"),
    "question" : "Is SSC CGL good? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c490c817f0398fc555f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-improve-maths-in-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I improve maths in SSC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:33.484Z"),
    "question" : "How do I improve maths in SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c5f0c817f0398fc5625"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-SSC-CPO-better-than-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "To decide as to whether SSC CPO is better than SSC CGL, one must know about both the exams, and the recruitment process and jobs associated with both these exams conducted by the Staff Selection Commission. SSC CPO - Who Should Prefer This? The Staff Selection Commission (SSC) conducts the SSC CPO Recruitment Exam to recruit eligible applicants to the Central Police Organisation (CPO)The posts that will be filled by SSC CPO are as follows:Sub-Inspector in Delhi PoliceSub-Inspector in BSFSub-Inspector in CISFSub-Inspector in CRPFSub-Inspector in ITBPSub-Inspector in SSBAssistant Sub-Inspector in CISFThe exam is conducted in 4 stages and the applicant should possess a good academic knowledge and reasoning ability, along with physical standards and fitnessThe posts offer a good adventurous lifeContinue Reading To decide as to whether SSC CPO is better than SSC CGL, one must know about both the exams, and the recruitment process and jobs associated with both these exams conducted by the Staff Selection Commission. SSC CPO - Who Should Prefer This? The Staff Selection Commission (SSC) conducts the SSC CPO Recruitment Exam to recruit eligible applicants to the Central Police Organisation (CPO)The posts that will be filled by SSC CPO are as follows:Sub-Inspector in Delhi PoliceSub-Inspector in BSFSub-Inspector in CISFSub-Inspector in CRPFSub-Inspector in ITBPSub-Inspector in SSBAssistant Sub-Inspector in CISFThe exam is conducted in 4 stages and the applicant should possess a good academic knowledge and reasoning ability, along with physical standards and fitnessThe posts offer a good adventurous lifeContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:30:55.325Z"),
    "question" : "Is SSC CPO better than SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377c740c817f0398fc563b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-best-coaching-centre-for-SSC-CGL-exam-in-Kerala?-",
    "answer" : "Friends! Are You Looking For Good coaching Centres for SSC In Kerala???? Let me tell you There are Good Coaching Centres as well as Very Popular Coaching centres.There is a difference between best coaching Centres and Popular Coaching Centres. Popular Coaching Centres can only give you the feeling that you are in Popular Coaching centres. Those coaching Centres Only look for their infrastructure. But let me tell these Infrastructure doesn’t make any sense in giving you the Result. Also when you are looking at their results. They will have Results .I agree.But when you look at the Percentage of Students who got Government Jobs with Number students studied there, Then the percentage of result will be much lower. Undoubtedly there will be Brilliant students who don't need much coaching will be Continue Reading Friends! Are You Looking For Good coaching Centres for SSC In Kerala???? Let me tell you There are Good Coaching Centres as well as Very Popular Coaching centres.There is a difference between best coaching Centres and Popular Coaching Centres. Popular Coaching Centres can only give you the feeling that you are in Popular Coaching centres. Those coaching Centres Only look for their infrastructure. But let me tell these Infrastructure doesn’t make any sense in giving you the Result. Also when you are looking at their results. They will have Results .I agree.But when you look at the Percentage of Students who got Government Jobs with Number students studied there, Then the percentage of result will be much lower. Undoubtedly there will be Brilliant students who don't need much coaching will be Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:31:16.497Z"),
    "question" : "Which is best coaching centre for SSC CGL exam in Kerala? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377cc60c817f0398fc5738"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-SSC-exams-be-replaced-by-CET-in-2019?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, it is true. There is a proposal that preliminary recruitment exams conducted by different government agencies will be replaced by a single exam - the CET (Common Eligibility Test) from 2019 onwards. To proposal can be summarised as follows: SSC is entrusted with the task of conducting CET.Candidates will have to register themselves on a portal developed by NCS (National Career Service).There will be CETs for three levels, Matriculation level, Higher Secondary level, and Graduation level. In 2019, there will be one CET for Graduation level only in February with others being conducted in subsequent years.CET score will be valid for two years.CET will be conducted in place of the Prelims or Tier I exam (because they are more or less similar for all agencies). Subsequent Main Exams will beContinue Reading Yes, it is true. There is a proposal that preliminary recruitment exams conducted by different government agencies will be replaced by a single exam - the CET (Common Eligibility Test) from 2019 onwards. To proposal can be summarised as follows: SSC is entrusted with the task of conducting CET.Candidates will have to register themselves on a portal developed by NCS (National Career Service).There will be CETs for three levels, Matriculation level, Higher Secondary level, and Graduation level. In 2019, there will be one CET for Graduation level only in February with others being conducted in subsequent years.CET score will be valid for two years.CET will be conducted in place of the Prelims or Tier I exam (because they are more or less similar for all agencies). Subsequent Main Exams will beContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:32:38.489Z"),
    "question" : "Will SSC exams be replaced by CET in 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377cd90c817f0398fc57fe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-eligibility-for-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Applicants must satisfy the SSC CGL eligibility criteria before applying for SSC CGL exam. In case the candidate does not fulfil any of the eligibility criteria, commission will reject the candidate’s application therefore knowing the eligibility criteria is very important for candidates. An SSC CGL eligibility criterion is different for the different posts. SSC CGL Eligibility Criteria 2017: Details The CGL eligibility criteria are the conditions which is set by the staff selection commission, candidates must ensure that they fulfil all the eligibility conditions. SSC CGL eligibility criteria mention below: Educational Qualifications Candidates need to fulfil the following educational qualifications in order to be able to fill the SSC CGL application form: http://S.No Name of the Post Required E Continue Reading Applicants must satisfy the SSC CGL eligibility criteria before applying for SSC CGL exam. In case the candidate does not fulfil any of the eligibility criteria, commission will reject the candidate’s application therefore knowing the eligibility criteria is very important for candidates. An SSC CGL eligibility criterion is different for the different posts. SSC CGL Eligibility Criteria 2017: Details The CGL eligibility criteria are the conditions which is set by the staff selection commission, candidates must ensure that they fulfil all the eligibility conditions. SSC CGL eligibility criteria mention below: Educational Qualifications Candidates need to fulfil the following educational qualifications in order to be able to fill the SSC CGL application form: http://S.No Name of the Post Required E Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:32:57.569Z"),
    "question" : "What is the eligibility for SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d000c817f0398fc5825"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-coaching-institute-for-SSC-JE-in-Delhi?-",
    "answer" : "Hi Friends, I have qualified RRB JE 2018 (cbt 1 & cbt 2), document verification and medical test. I am waiting for the final result. I started my preparation for RRB JE by self-study. I studied hard and my CBT-1 exam went good. Therefore I decided to go for preparation of CBT-2 exam. I had not touched technical part for last 4 years. When I started preparation for CBT -2, I faced many problems while preparing technical part. So, I decided to join coaching. I was searching for good coaching. Then one of my friends told me about Carnot Classes in Laxmi Nagar. He had already studied there. I joined coaching just two month before the exam. They promised to complete my syllabus before the exam. When I joined coaching, I was happy to see the pace with which my syllabus was covered. Almost whole syl Continue Reading Hi Friends, I have qualified RRB JE 2018 (cbt 1 & cbt 2), document verification and medical test. I am waiting for the final result. I started my preparation for RRB JE by self-study. I studied hard and my CBT-1 exam went good. Therefore I decided to go for preparation of CBT-2 exam. I had not touched technical part for last 4 years. When I started preparation for CBT -2, I faced many problems while preparing technical part. So, I decided to join coaching. I was searching for good coaching. Then one of my friends told me about Carnot Classes in Laxmi Nagar. He had already studied there. I joined coaching just two month before the exam. They promised to complete my syllabus before the exam. When I joined coaching, I was happy to see the pace with which my syllabus was covered. Almost whole syl Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:33:36.613Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best coaching institute for SSC-JE in Delhi? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d130c817f0398fc58e5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-should-prepare-ssc-je-electrical-engineering-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Hello SSC conducts the Junior Engineer Exam for Civil, Mechanical, and Electrical Engineers. In SSC Je paper 1, General Intelligence & Reasoning, General Awareness are compulsory subjects. Give 2 hours for GK and General Intelligence & reasoning each. and 4 hours for Electrical. If you want to prepare for SSC JE 2017 then you have less to for preparation. So you should need 8–9 hours daily. First make your time table and include all the electrical syllabus. Most important clear your basic concepts related to electrical engineering. SSC JE Electrical syllabus includes Basic concepts, Circuit law, Magnetic Circuit, AC Fundamentals, Measurement and Measuring instruments, Electrical Machines, Fractional Kilowatt Motors and single phase induction Motors, Synchronous Machines, Generation, Transmission  Continue Reading Hello SSC conducts the Junior Engineer Exam for Civil, Mechanical, and Electrical Engineers. In SSC Je paper 1, General Intelligence & Reasoning, General Awareness are compulsory subjects. Give 2 hours for GK and General Intelligence & reasoning each. and 4 hours for Electrical. If you want to prepare for SSC JE 2017 then you have less to for preparation. So you should need 8–9 hours daily. First make your time table and include all the electrical syllabus. Most important clear your basic concepts related to electrical engineering. SSC JE Electrical syllabus includes Basic concepts, Circuit law, Magnetic Circuit, AC Fundamentals, Measurement and Measuring instruments, Electrical Machines, Fractional Kilowatt Motors and single phase induction Motors, Synchronous Machines, Generation, Transmission  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:33:55.776Z"),
    "question" : "How do I should prepare ssc je electrical engineering exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d290c817f0398fc58fe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-coaching-for-SSC-CGL-in-lucknow?-",
    "answer" : "To crack any government exam, preparation is the major thing that matters and the second thing is a great strategy. Vidya Guru is the best institute which provides the right environment to its student. I would suggest you t take their Online coaching. That is really the best coaching, you can join, the best service takes here only. Vidya Guru classes provide the right study material you will get the entire study material at your home. Join Vidya Guru classes for the best program. Take the classes according to the best study resource from Vidya Guru Only. As I have observed them, once you join Vidya Guru then you don’t need to go anywhere else. Just join them and your preparation will start from the first day. That is the best institute for all government exam preparation. I got improvement Continue Reading To crack any government exam, preparation is the major thing that matters and the second thing is a great strategy. Vidya Guru is the best institute which provides the right environment to its student. I would suggest you t take their Online coaching. That is really the best coaching, you can join, the best service takes here only. Vidya Guru classes provide the right study material you will get the entire study material at your home. Join Vidya Guru classes for the best program. Take the classes according to the best study resource from Vidya Guru Only. As I have observed them, once you join Vidya Guru then you don’t need to go anywhere else. Just join them and your preparation will start from the first day. That is the best institute for all government exam preparation. I got improvement Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:34:17.708Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best coaching for SSC-CGL in lucknow? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d400c817f0398fc5914"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-quantitative-book-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Hello. Thanks for asking. As per my view, Best books are those books which are comprehensible for you. What is best for me, may be worst for u. Lets assume i suggest a book and say it is the best book but u are not able to understand a single word of that book. Can it be best for u? So, for your query, i can only suggest my book list for quantitative aptitude, rest u decide whether it is best for u or not. Lets start. For Arithmetic - R.S. agrwal maths book 2. Kiran' PYQ for maths  3. MB publications' maths pyq book. 4. M Tyra's quicker maths- just for short tricks and formulae. ##. I have heard a lot about Rakesh Yadav's maths book. Though i have not personally checked this book, i cant say anything about this book. So once check this book also. Note - These books are also available in hindi medium. Continue Reading Hello. Thanks for asking. As per my view, Best books are those books which are comprehensible for you. What is best for me, may be worst for u. Lets assume i suggest a book and say it is the best book but u are not able to understand a single word of that book. Can it be best for u? So, for your query, i can only suggest my book list for quantitative aptitude, rest u decide whether it is best for u or not. Lets start. For Arithmetic - R.S. agrwal maths book 2. Kiran' PYQ for maths  3. MB publications' maths pyq book. 4. M Tyra's quicker maths- just for short tricks and formulae. ##. I have heard a lot about Rakesh Yadav's maths book. Though i have not personally checked this book, i cant say anything about this book. So once check this book also. Note - These books are also available in hindi medium. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:34:40.684Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best quantitative book for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d550c817f0398fc59db"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-syllabus-of-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What is the syllabus of SSC CHSL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:01.598Z"),
    "question" : "What is the syllabus of SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d6f0c817f0398fc59f1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-be-the-backup-plan-of-a-SSC-CGL-aspirant?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What should be the backup plan of a SSC CGL aspirant?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:27.140Z"),
    "question" : "What should be the backup plan of a SSC CGL aspirant? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d820c817f0398fc5a08"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-SSC-CGL-2017-Syllabus?-",
    "answer" : "SSC CGL Syllabus Tier 1 consists of four sections i.e. Reasoning, General Awareness, Quantitative Aptitude and English Comprehension. Tier 2 comprises Quantitative Aptitude and English Language.  Here, we take a comprehensive look at section wise Syllabus of SSC CGL 2017 General Intelligence & ReasoningAnalogies, similarities and differences, space visualization, spatial orientation, problem solving, analysis, judgment, decision making, visual memory, discrimination, observation, relationship concepts, arithmetical reasoning and figural classification, arithmetic number series, non-verbal series, coding and decoding. Quantitative AptitudeDecimals, fractions and relationships between numbers, Percentage. Ratio & Proportion, Square roots, Averages, Interest, Profit and Loss, Discount, Partnershi Continue Reading SSC CGL Syllabus Tier 1 consists of four sections i.e. Reasoning, General Awareness, Quantitative Aptitude and English Comprehension. Tier 2 comprises Quantitative Aptitude and English Language.  Here, we take a comprehensive look at section wise Syllabus of SSC CGL 2017 General Intelligence & ReasoningAnalogies, similarities and differences, space visualization, spatial orientation, problem solving, analysis, judgment, decision making, visual memory, discrimination, observation, relationship concepts, arithmetical reasoning and figural classification, arithmetic number series, non-verbal series, coding and decoding. Quantitative AptitudeDecimals, fractions and relationships between numbers, Percentage. Ratio & Proportion, Square roots, Averages, Interest, Profit and Loss, Discount, Partnershi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:35:46.279Z"),
    "question" : "What is SSC CGL 2017 Syllabus? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377d950c817f0398fc5ad6"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-necessary-to-read-all-NCERT-books-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Chirag Popat Short Answer : No Long Answer : Below is the structure of SSC CGL examination. Tier 1: 200 marks with 25 questions each from Reasoning, Mathematics, English and General Knowledge. Tier 2: 2/3/4 papers depending on your preference and educational qualifications. Two papers are of English and Maths which are compulsory for all and others are a paper each for Assistant Audit Officer and Statistical Investigator. Tier 3: Descriptive paper consists of essay, letter and precis writing. Now the only paper in which NCERT books can be remotely useful is the General Knowledge portion of Tier 1. Taking into consideration the level of question in SSC CGL Tier 1 and the vastness of topics covered in NCERT it is not worth the grind. Return on investment is low and it is better to study other subjects than to Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:36:05.626Z"),
    "question" : "Is it necessary to read all NCERT books for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377db90c817f0398fc5af7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-all-changes-can-we-expect-in-SSC-CGL-2018-pattern?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Eswara Kumar 5",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:36:41.294Z"),
    "question" : "What all changes can we expect in SSC CGL 2018 pattern? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377dcc0c817f0398fc5bbf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-mistake-we-do-while-preparing-for-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "#Silly mistakes in SSC CGL exam which everyone must avoid. This mistake is very general and very common. I had to face hell of the time due to following mistake … Read on… Don’t forget any document required for the exam. Admit card, photographs, Government ID proof in original and photocopy. I had committed this silly mistake in SSC CGL 2016 mains. Ohh… What an eventful day it was , still getting chills while I am writing this: Whenever I remember and write this incident, I get nervous memories of the day when my SSC CGL 2016 mains was scheduled. I was well prepared, reached my centre well in time, had some strong tea, sumptuous Idlis and was sure that I had all the documents with me. I keep many photographs in my wallet. Then at the time of entry in exam rooms, I was asked to show admit card Continue Reading #Silly mistakes in SSC CGL exam which everyone must avoid. This mistake is very general and very common. I had to face hell of the time due to following mistake … Read on… Don’t forget any document required for the exam. Admit card, photographs, Government ID proof in original and photocopy. I had committed this silly mistake in SSC CGL 2016 mains. Ohh… What an eventful day it was , still getting chills while I am writing this: Whenever I remember and write this incident, I get nervous memories of the day when my SSC CGL 2016 mains was scheduled. I was well prepared, reached my centre well in time, had some strong tea, sumptuous Idlis and was sure that I had all the documents with me. I keep many photographs in my wallet. Then at the time of entry in exam rooms, I was asked to show admit card Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:37:00.691Z"),
    "question" : "What are the mistake we do while preparing for SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ddf0c817f0398fc5bd1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-final-year-appearing-students-appear-in-SSC-CGL-2016?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, you are eligible for giving SSC CGL Exam. The eligibility criteria for the CGL Exam is graduation or the bachelors degree. SSC CGL age limit : For Inspector: 18 to 27 yearsStatistical Investigator: Gr-II Not exceeding 26 yearsAssistant/Sub Inspector in CBI: 20 to 27 yearsSSC CGL exam is most popular exam among the aspirants who want to see their career in government agencies. Right now CGL exam is going on now your can prepare for the next year. Here are some preparation tips: Must and the perfect strategy to crack any competitive exam is to solve last year question paper and take mock test as much as you can.Refer good books with updated syllabus and paper pattern.Solve papers with proper time management.Try to teach someone.Make small notes in your own language so that at the time of revContinue Reading Yes, you are eligible for giving SSC CGL Exam. The eligibility criteria for the CGL Exam is graduation or the bachelors degree. SSC CGL age limit : For Inspector: 18 to 27 yearsStatistical Investigator: Gr-II Not exceeding 26 yearsAssistant/Sub Inspector in CBI: 20 to 27 yearsSSC CGL exam is most popular exam among the aspirants who want to see their career in government agencies. Right now CGL exam is going on now your can prepare for the next year. Here are some preparation tips: Must and the perfect strategy to crack any competitive exam is to solve last year question paper and take mock test as much as you can.Refer good books with updated syllabus and paper pattern.Solve papers with proper time management.Try to teach someone.Make small notes in your own language so that at the time of revContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:37:19.281Z"),
    "question" : "Can final year appearing students appear in SSC CGL 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377df50c817f0398fc5be7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-final-year-student-apply-for-SSC-CGL-2017?-",
    "answer" : "Answer is a big YES. But there is a catch, u needed to have the mark sheet on or before the date mentioned by the commission. For 2017 CGL I guess that to be 1st Aug 2017. Not sure. Coming to the real situation. Forget the mark sheet tension. Apply for exam and appear. No one will ask for u r mark sheet untill tier 2 exam results are out. If u have u r results published before the stipulated date well n good. Jon the service after doc verification. If not absent yourself for verification. All that u lose is only the examination fees Rs.100. Moreover u can appear for the exam next year working in any private org managing u r expenses and parallely revise whatever u studied for the previous year exam which would be much easier and high chances of getting top rank and preferred post. Addition to it Continue Reading Answer is a big YES. But there is a catch, u needed to have the mark sheet on or before the date mentioned by the commission. For 2017 CGL I guess that to be 1st Aug 2017. Not sure. Coming to the real situation. Forget the mark sheet tension. Apply for exam and appear. No one will ask for u r mark sheet untill tier 2 exam results are out. If u have u r results published before the stipulated date well n good. Jon the service after doc verification. If not absent yourself for verification. All that u lose is only the examination fees Rs.100. Moreover u can appear for the exam next year working in any private org managing u r expenses and parallely revise whatever u studied for the previous year exam which would be much easier and high chances of getting top rank and preferred post. Addition to it Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:37:41.210Z"),
    "question" : "Can a final year student apply for SSC CGL 2017? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e0a0c817f0398fc5cb3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-a-diploma-holder-eligible-for-the-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "Do not listen to any nonsense who doesn't know anything and saying on his own that 12th and diploma is not equivalent… if u are talking about job… I have asked the ssc student helpline they said if u have completed 3 years diploma after 10th then it is equivalent to 10+2. Partha Kansabanik",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:38:02.315Z"),
    "question" : "Is a diploma holder eligible for the SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e200c817f0398fc5cc5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-SSC-CGL-selection-done?-",
    "answer" : "SSC CGL SELECTION PROCEDURE 2017 The selection procedure of ssc cgl consist of four stages- tier1, tier2, tier3 and tier4. The candidates who qualify the tier1 as per the cut of marks of ssc cgl will only be eligible for appearing in the tier2. According to the ssc cgl selection procedure 2017, marks scored by the candidates in the tier1 and tier2 will determine their selection in tier3 and tier4. According to the ssc cgl 2017 selection mode, ssc after conducting all the three tiers of ssc cgl 2017 exam will draw ALL INDIA MERIT list for each category of post on the basis of total score obtained by the candidates in tier 1 to tier 4. The tier4 is qualifying in nature as per the ssc cgl 2017 selection procedure. Candidates will be recommended for appointment in each category as per the vacan Continue Reading SSC CGL SELECTION PROCEDURE 2017 The selection procedure of ssc cgl consist of four stages- tier1, tier2, tier3 and tier4. The candidates who qualify the tier1 as per the cut of marks of ssc cgl will only be eligible for appearing in the tier2. According to the ssc cgl selection procedure 2017, marks scored by the candidates in the tier1 and tier2 will determine their selection in tier3 and tier4. According to the ssc cgl 2017 selection mode, ssc after conducting all the three tiers of ssc cgl 2017 exam will draw ALL INDIA MERIT list for each category of post on the basis of total score obtained by the candidates in tier 1 to tier 4. The tier4 is qualifying in nature as per the ssc cgl 2017 selection procedure. Candidates will be recommended for appointment in each category as per the vacan Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:38:24.402Z"),
    "question" : "How is SSC CGL selection done? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e320c817f0398fc5cd7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-job-profile-of-the-SSC-CHSL?-Is-it-advisable-to-join-SSC-CHSL-immediately-after-my-BTech?-What-is-the-right-approach-to-clear-these-type-of-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Testbook Staff Selection Commission conducts the National Level Combined High Secondary Level (10+ 2)’ exam. The SSC CHSL exam recruits eligible candidates for various posts such as Postal Assistant, Lower Divisional Clerks, Court Clerk, Sorting Assistants, Data Entry Operators, etc. in the Indian Administrative Systems. There are various duties and responsibilities associated with these posts. Here is the SSC CHSL Job Profile for the above-mentioned posts in detail. Job Profile for SSC CHSL Lower Divisional Clerk/Junior Secretariat Assistant Clerical work along with the maintenance of workflow in the office.The mails have to be registered timely.Updates and other data has to be entered onto the computer.Furthermore, they are responsible for indexing and maintaining the File Registers.Management of FContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:38:42.931Z"),
    "question" : "What is the job profile of the SSC-CHSL? Is it advisable to join SSC-CHSL immediately after my BTech? What is the right approach to clear these type of exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e450c817f0398fc5d9f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-YouTube-channel-is-the-best-for-current-affairs-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "First of all let me clarify that this exam is not of that sort in which you need to read newspaper for current affairs. This exam will ask you only to the point questions for which you will have to answer to the point and so your preparation for this indeed should be to the point. I always followed GKTODAY for current affairs. Let me tell you what should be your strategy while preparing current affairs. Follow the GKTODAY YouTube channel daily to watch video the one they upload everyday. Just watch the video, don't even try to mug up anything. Video length is generally short i.e. around 15–20 minutes. So it will hardly take 20 minutes of yours.Again they upload weekly video, where questions of previous 7 days are covered. Again just watch video don't mug up anything.Now in the month end agaiContinue Reading First of all let me clarify that this exam is not of that sort in which you need to read newspaper for current affairs. This exam will ask you only to the point questions for which you will have to answer to the point and so your preparation for this indeed should be to the point. I always followed GKTODAY for current affairs. Let me tell you what should be your strategy while preparing current affairs. Follow the GKTODAY YouTube channel daily to watch video the one they upload everyday. Just watch the video, don't even try to mug up anything. Video length is generally short i.e. around 15–20 minutes. So it will hardly take 20 minutes of yours.Again they upload weekly video, where questions of previous 7 days are covered. Again just watch video don't mug up anything.Now in the month end agaiContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:39:01.958Z"),
    "question" : "Which YouTube channel is the best for current affairs in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e590c817f0398fc5dae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-jobs-in-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Following are the Jobs Recruitment Done by SSC. 1.Combined Graduate Level Examination 2.Combined Higher Secondary (10+2) Level Examination 3.Stenographer Grade 'C' and 'D' Examination 4.Junior Engineer 5.Sub-Inspector in Delhi Police and Central Armed Police Forces Examination 6.Constable (GD) 7.Junior Hindi Translator, Junior Translator and Senior Hindi Translator Examination. 8.Constable (Executive) Male and Female in Delhi Police Examination 9.Multi Tasking (Non Technical) Staff Examination These are Jobs Being Offered by SSC. Thank You Navneet Goyal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:39:21.150Z"),
    "question" : "What are the jobs in SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e6e0c817f0398fc5dc5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-tough-is-SSC-CHSL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How tough is SSC CHSL?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:39:42.138Z"),
    "question" : "How tough is SSC CHSL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377e810c817f0398fc5e8a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-SSC-CGL-Tier-1-and-Tier-2?-",
    "answer" : "SSC CGL TIER 1 :- Number of sections:- 4 Quantitative Aptitude- 50 MarksReasoning- 50 MarksEnglish- 50 MarksGeneral Awareness- 50 MarksTotal- 200 Marks Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.25 for each wrong answer. **Note- No sectional cutoff Only those Candidates who clear Tier1 will be qualified for Tier2.   SSC CGL TIER 2 :- It comprises of three different paper subjects and depending upon the category of post applied for, the candidates required to appear either in two or in all the three papers. PAPER 1:- Arithmetical Ability- 200 Marks Number of Questions- 100Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.50 mark for each wrong answer.PAPER 2:- English Language and Comprehension- 200 Marks Number of Questions- 200Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.25 for each wrong answer.PAPER 3:- Statistics- 200 Mark Continue Reading SSC CGL TIER 1 :- Number of sections:- 4 Quantitative Aptitude- 50 MarksReasoning- 50 MarksEnglish- 50 MarksGeneral Awareness- 50 MarksTotal- 200 Marks Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.25 for each wrong answer. **Note- No sectional cutoff Only those Candidates who clear Tier1 will be qualified for Tier2.   SSC CGL TIER 2 :- It comprises of three different paper subjects and depending upon the category of post applied for, the candidates required to appear either in two or in all the three papers. PAPER 1:- Arithmetical Ability- 200 Marks Number of Questions- 100Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.50 mark for each wrong answer.PAPER 2:- English Language and Comprehension- 200 Marks Number of Questions- 200Duration- 2 hoursNegative Marks- 0.25 for each wrong answer.PAPER 3:- Statistics- 200 Mark Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:40:01.586Z"),
    "question" : "What is the difference between SSC CGL Tier 1 and Tier 2? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ea60c817f0398fc5eac"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-SSC-online?-",
    "answer" : "There are many online coaching available nowadays. English- Neetu Singh ma'am have started her live classes. These are the best for English.Maths- Abhinay Sharma (Unacademy Plus course) is a great teacher for Maths for SSC.Reasoning- KD Campus video lessons are good.GK- KD Campus video lessons are good. Also, you should cover at least one annual current affairs magazine just before tier 1.If you are short on budget, use youtube. There are many free lessons available there by many good teachers. Though coaching is not at all necessary for SSC, you should go for it if your basics are weak and you feel that you can understand concepts better if a teacher teaches you. I myself have cleared it with flying colors without any coaching. So I can say it with confidence. Thank you.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:40:38.085Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for SSC online? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ecf0c817f0398fc5f86"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-SSC-CGL-be-conducted-in-2020-as-I-am-pursuing-my-degree-at-present?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Will SSC CGL be conducted in 2020 as I am pursuing my degree at present?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:41:19.201Z"),
    "question" : "Will SSC CGL be conducted in 2020 as I am pursuing my degree at present? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ee30c817f0398fc5f9a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-do-I-do-after-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Sunil Meena After clearing SSC mostly people go for UPSC. But only few people get success in clearing UPSC. SSC includes group B and C jobs which provide social respect, decent income, less work load and officer status. Therefore only few people get over it and only few are there who are actually focussed for UPSC. But other than UPSC we can go after SSC in the departments mentioned below: CDS : The “Combined Defence Services”Examination (CDS) is conducted twice a year by the Union Public Service Commission for recruitment into the Indian Military Academy, officers Training Academy, Indian Naval Academy and Indian Air Force Academy.CAPF : The recruitment of CAPF (AC) is conducted every year by the Union Public Service Commission for selection into Border Security Force (BSF), Central Industrial Security Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:41:39.324Z"),
    "question" : "What do I do after SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377efe0c817f0398fc6063"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/When-is-the-next-hearing-of-the-SSC-CGL-2017-case-in-SC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  When is the next hearing of the SSC CGL 2017 case in SC?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:42:06.539Z"),
    "question" : "When is the next hearing of the SSC CGL 2017 case in SC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f2a0c817f0398fc6097"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-SSC-CGL-2018-prelims-happen-in-the-date-mentioned-in-the-calendar-published-by-the-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Mayank Maharaj Shaik Asif",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:42:50.604Z"),
    "question" : "Will the SSC CGL 2018 prelims happen in the date mentioned in the calendar published by the SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f410c817f0398fc615a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-SSC-CGL-exams-are-difficult-or-easy?-",
    "answer" : "Hari om, you are asking a question as to : “ Is the SSC CGL a tough exam?”. Hari om. ANSWER : Compared to your intermediate and degree exams it is tough, not because you can't pass the exam, but because there are a limited number of seats to be filled by the successful candidates. The number of contestants are many from all over the country, because it is an all India level exam. Further, any graduate from any discipline can appear for this exam. There are as many as 32 different types of jobs for the same exam, and in almost all ministries of the Central Government. Further, good salary package, good prospects, prestige, power etc. , are all attached to it. So, the competition is more. People appear in lakhs. Posts are in thousands. It is the most coveted Central Government Services after IAS,  Continue Reading Hari om, you are asking a question as to : “ Is the SSC CGL a tough exam?”. Hari om. ANSWER : Compared to your intermediate and degree exams it is tough, not because you can't pass the exam, but because there are a limited number of seats to be filled by the successful candidates. The number of contestants are many from all over the country, because it is an all India level exam. Further, any graduate from any discipline can appear for this exam. There are as many as 32 different types of jobs for the same exam, and in almost all ministries of the Central Government. Further, good salary package, good prospects, prestige, power etc. , are all attached to it. So, the competition is more. People appear in lakhs. Posts are in thousands. It is the most coveted Central Government Services after IAS,  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:13.283Z"),
    "question" : "Is SSC CGL exams are difficult or easy? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f550c817f0398fc616a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-SSC-CGL-coaching-centre-in-Dehradun?-",
    "answer" : "Best Institutes for SSC CGL coaching in Dehradun Hope IAS AcademyKaranpur, Dehradun Teaches : IAS | PCS | Civil Services | SSC CGL | IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | IBPS RRB |Success point IAS AcademyNehru Colony, Dehradun Teaches: CAT | MAT | Other MBA Entrance Exams | IBPS Clerk | SBI Bank PO | RBI | Other Banking Jobs | IAS | IFS | SSC CGL |Aim IAS AcademyRispana Pull, Dehradun Teaches : IAS | PCS | Civil Services | CSAT | Patwari | CDS | NDA | IBPS Clerk | RBI | SSC CGL |Gurukul AcademySurvey Chowk, Dehradun Teaches : IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | IBPS RRB | Other Banking Jobs | SBI Bank PO | SSC CGLVijay AcademyKaranapur, Dehradun Teaches : IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | SBI Bank PO | Other Banking Jobs | IBPS RRB | SSC CGLBefore joining the Institute, Continue Reading Best Institutes for SSC CGL coaching in Dehradun Hope IAS AcademyKaranpur, Dehradun Teaches : IAS | PCS | Civil Services | SSC CGL | IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | IBPS RRB |Success point IAS AcademyNehru Colony, Dehradun Teaches: CAT | MAT | Other MBA Entrance Exams | IBPS Clerk | SBI Bank PO | RBI | Other Banking Jobs | IAS | IFS | SSC CGL |Aim IAS AcademyRispana Pull, Dehradun Teaches : IAS | PCS | Civil Services | CSAT | Patwari | CDS | NDA | IBPS Clerk | RBI | SSC CGL |Gurukul AcademySurvey Chowk, Dehradun Teaches : IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | IBPS RRB | Other Banking Jobs | SBI Bank PO | SSC CGLVijay AcademyKaranapur, Dehradun Teaches : IBPS Clerk | RBI | Bank PO | IBPS SO | SBI Bank PO | Other Banking Jobs | IBPS RRB | SSC CGLBefore joining the Institute, Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:33.790Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best SSC CGL coaching centre in Dehradun? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f6a0c817f0398fc6232"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-prepare-for-AAO-through-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Mohua Ghosh Since this post was introduced for SSC in 2016 only, my answer is from the perspective of that first batch. Specifically for the post of AAO, the preparation required is actually quite easy if you come from a commerce background, even better if you have been a CA aspirant. A lot of in depth knowledge is not required, nor are the more complex topics covered. XI and XII std books on Accounts and Economics easily cover the entire syllabus that is notified by SSC. For CA students, your course books of Accounts and Economics from your CPT days, will completely suffice when preparing for this. Being a multiple choice question paper, nothing involving extremely long calculations is asked. In fact, with a little practice you should be able to do the 100 questions in the stipulated time of 2 hours wit Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:43:54.314Z"),
    "question" : "How should I prepare for AAO through SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f7e0c817f0398fc624a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-the-right-time-to-start-SSC-CGL-preparation-at-age-27?-",
    "answer" : "If you have read about the criterion for age limit for SSC CGL posts, you may have noticed that there are only few ( in SSC CGL 2016) posts which allow candidates older than 27 years, namely Assistant Section Officer in CSS, Assistant Audit Officer in CA&G and Sub Inspector in CBI and NIA, and Statistical Investigator. Out of these posts, ASO in CSS and SI in CBI are 4600 GP posts, SI in NIA and Statistical Investigator are 4200 GP posts, while AAO in CA&G is a 4800 GP gazetted post. So choices are limited for you in case you have expectations regarding job profile. If you are OK with any of these jobs( and you should be), you should start your preparation with immediate effect. You will have almost 3 full months before the tier 1 of CGL 2017, so it’s not too late to start. All the best.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:14.843Z"),
    "question" : "Is it the right time to start SSC CGL preparation at age 27? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377f920c817f0398fc625a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-vacancies-of-2017-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Current status of CGL vacancy is 8089 (tentative) , today a big boost in no of Vacancy As per department status vacancy will go up to 15000 Please do hard work because after that there would be less Vacancy in CGL18 So pls those who cleared T1 pls do some effort and make their future brighter    Best of luck for T2&T3 And pls CGL T2 aspirant and CGL18 do follow me for further news of SSC …I am here to help you through out your journey of this comptitive era 121",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:34.096Z"),
    "question" : "What are the vacancies of 2017 SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377fa50c817f0398fc6320"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-better-option-SSc-or-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Before going into perks salaries commanding respect who is more intelligent etc etc the sole and only difference which sets UPSC and SSC totally North and South Pole is Career Progression. I will share 2 examples of my family. My Uncle joined Customs and Central Excise as Inspector in 1988. As of now he is still a Senior Superintendent about to retire in 3yrs if he gets a promotion which is due since last 7yrs he will become Assistant Commissioner. When someone clears UPSC and gets Indian Revenue Service ( IRS ) he becomes Assistant Commissioner in his first posting. Difference of Career growth is straight 21yrs. Another example. My father joined Central Secretariat Services in 1990 as Assistant Section Officer. In 2018 he was promoted as Deputy Secretary to Govt of India Again when someone cle Continue Reading Before going into perks salaries commanding respect who is more intelligent etc etc the sole and only difference which sets UPSC and SSC totally North and South Pole is Career Progression. I will share 2 examples of my family. My Uncle joined Customs and Central Excise as Inspector in 1988. As of now he is still a Senior Superintendent about to retire in 3yrs if he gets a promotion which is due since last 7yrs he will become Assistant Commissioner. When someone clears UPSC and gets Indian Revenue Service ( IRS ) he becomes Assistant Commissioner in his first posting. Difference of Career growth is straight 21yrs. Another example. My father joined Central Secretariat Services in 1990 as Assistant Section Officer. In 2018 he was promoted as Deputy Secretary to Govt of India Again when someone cle Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:44:53.644Z"),
    "question" : "Which is better option SSc or UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377fca0c817f0398fc6343"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-benefits-of-the-SSC-CGL-exam?-",
    "answer" : "There are various benefits of CGL exam:- 1.You will be called and treated as Central Government employee. 2. After one promotion( From 4600 GP) you will become Gazetted officer. 3. You will enjoy power if you are posted in Income tax, Excise, CSS etc. 4. You will get various facilities being Central Government employee, which includes CGHS, LTC and others. 5. If you want to pursue your study you will get study leave. There are many more benefits which you will enjoy once you inducted in the system. Chetan Digal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:45:30.856Z"),
    "question" : "What are the benefits of the SSC CGL exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377fe70c817f0398fc6411"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-get-a-good-score-in-the-SSC-CGL-2018-with-only-49-days-left?-",
    "answer" : "Saumya Sinha Tier-1 is from 25. july – 20. august. so until our admit cards are out, we don’t know whether we are left with 49 days or a maximum of 75 days. Let’s just assume that, we all are going to appear for the tier 1 on 25th july ( b’coz sometimes pressure is important to perform well in exam) Everyone can have their own best-suited strategy but some things can’t be neglected or rather they are very crucial to see ourselves in the race for tier 2 . Buy the best online test series, even if you are not prepared for a particular section, don’t procrastinate the test thinking that “let me once finish the syllabus then i’ll give the exam”. just give the test, analyze which section you are weak at, solve the whole paper again and then try to cover up the part you are weak at.If you are not able to learn oContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:45:59.154Z"),
    "question" : "How can I get a good score in the SSC CGL 2018 with only 49 days left? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("60377ffb0c817f0398fc6427"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Who-is-the-best-teacher-of-SSC-CGL-Mains-mathematics?-",
    "answer" : "Pranjal Sinha Firstly, try to attempt previous years papers of 2016–2018, if you find it really difficult to score even 100–120 marks (2017 paper was exceptionally tough, take 90–100 for it), start from the scratch, make a regime which you should religiously follow till you're absolutely sure that you've completed every single topic. Many bright minds would suggest you not to buy any online/offline course, however, some of you may need a mentor, a person to look up to for your queries, so you can enroll in any of the good teacher's course, There are many good educators like Pawan Rao, Abhinay Sharma, Abhas Saini and Gagan Pratap. Just watch their free lectures first on YouTube and then decide who is the best for you. Try to watch lecture of topics which you find very difficult. Some of you might be good a Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:46:19.881Z"),
    "question" : "Who is the best teacher of SSC CGL Mains mathematics? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037800f0c817f0398fc643d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-SSC-CGL-tier-2-cut-off-for-2016?-",
    "answer" : "Though cutoffs totally depends on the level of difficulty in the tier 2 of ssc Cgl but as per the past trend I think scoring 320+ in the tier 2 ( assuming you have scored 150+) in the tier 1 will be a good score to grab a grade B post. (Perform well in tier 3 as well , 65+ will be a good score) . Overall 535+ marks (tier1+tier2+tier3) will be a safe score this time. All the best :) Suman Saurabh",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:46:39.881Z"),
    "question" : "What is the SSC CGL tier 2 cut-off for 2016? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780220c817f0398fc64ff"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-Adda247-good-for-SSC-CGL-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Suraj Arora Here are 5 reasons why SSCAdda is the best online coaching source for banking preparation- Exam info - The portal has complete information about all SSC Jobs, its latest notifications, from all state and national level jobs, and updates. These exams and jobs are regularly updated as per the official information available. Information related to Banking Admit cards is also available. Candidates get the important details that must be checked by them. Instructions are provided as per the official guidelines. Syllabus, exam pattern, important dates are all kept updated.Your Preparation guide - You can find the daily current affairs and GK updates and capsules of General Awareness. The best and the latest articles are provided for various SSC exam related topics. Paper analysis, quizzes, mock teContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:46:58.464Z"),
    "question" : "Is Adda247 good for SSC CGL preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780330c817f0398fc6512"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-ECE-students-eligible-for-SSC-JE?-",
    "answer" : "Yashvi Kasodariya  No, ECE Students can’t apply for SSC JE. JE is basically for Electrical, Mechanical & Civil.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:47:15.949Z"),
    "question" : "Are ECE students eligible for SSC JE? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780480c817f0398fc6526"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-start-preparing-for-SSC-CGL-17-if-I-start-preparing-it-from-now?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Ashish Bisht 9",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:47:36.380Z"),
    "question" : "Can I start preparing for SSC CGL 17 if I start preparing it from now? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037805a0c817f0398fc65ec"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-preparing-for-both-ssc-cgl-and-bank-exams-the-right-strategy?-",
    "answer" : "People strategize to attain . Here , your goal is in ambiguity.  If to get a govt job, then YES!!! these are the only jobs that are presented at regular basis. So,once prepared if not able to crack at the first go you always have a second chance. now, lets go for the basics. Bank Exams= IBPS or SBI- You need to prepare  Reasoning Math English Computer  And yes G.K with an inclination for the bank related news and economics. Because they gonna jolt you up with economics related questions. SSC CGL- Here you need to prepare  Math  English  Reasoning  G.K(ofcourse) But all of this only for tier1 For tier 2, maths and english would suffice. Maths , English, Reasoning and G.K common for both. No extra preparation required for that. Only computer knowledge is extra so prepare Excel, Word and all. In bank exams G Continue Reading People strategize to attain . Here , your goal is in ambiguity.  If to get a govt job, then YES!!! these are the only jobs that are presented at regular basis. So,once prepared if not able to crack at the first go you always have a second chance. now, lets go for the basics. Bank Exams= IBPS or SBI- You need to prepare  Reasoning Math English Computer  And yes G.K with an inclination for the bank related news and economics. Because they gonna jolt you up with economics related questions. SSC CGL- Here you need to prepare  Math  English  Reasoning  G.K(ofcourse) But all of this only for tier1 For tier 2, maths and english would suffice. Maths , English, Reasoning and G.K common for both. No extra preparation required for that. Only computer knowledge is extra so prepare Excel, Word and all. In bank exams G Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:47:54.769Z"),
    "question" : "Is preparing for both ssc cgl and bank exams the right strategy? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6037806d0c817f0398fc6602"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-SSC-CGL-2017-be-postponed?-",
    "answer" : "SSC CGL tier 1 2017 is scheduled from 1st August to 20th August 2017. The exam will be conducted in online mode at various centres across the country. The Admit card for SSC CGL 2017 will be released soon. If the exam gets postponed, there will be official notice for the same which can be found at Staff Selection Commission official website. Practice SSC CGL mock test here!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:13.496Z"),
    "question" : "Will SSC CGL 2017 be postponed? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780800c817f0398fc6612"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-ways-to-improve-my-general-knowledge-for-exam-like-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Best ways are something to done with consistency or else they won’t be serving the purpose of anything. Start studying and having mind map os syllabus, topic which you to have to study during your whole preparation. Some important tips for you to consider- If you are already done with traditional sources of Gk(NCERTs, Newspapers, Magazines etc). Go for detailed and quality factful knowledge topic based topics. Study IQ education, Unacademy, Byju, any of it can help you to do that. Write 2–3 pages short points for whatever you have studied because in final examination trust me the MCQ question can really confuse you with the options provided to mark so write and revise daily whatever you study. Break the structure of previous year question paper and design your own strategy while attempting t Continue Reading Best ways are something to done with consistency or else they won’t be serving the purpose of anything. Start studying and having mind map os syllabus, topic which you to have to study during your whole preparation. Some important tips for you to consider- If you are already done with traditional sources of Gk(NCERTs, Newspapers, Magazines etc). Go for detailed and quality factful knowledge topic based topics. Study IQ education, Unacademy, Byju, any of it can help you to do that. Write 2–3 pages short points for whatever you have studied because in final examination trust me the MCQ question can really confuse you with the options provided to mark so write and revise daily whatever you study. Break the structure of previous year question paper and design your own strategy while attempting t Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:32.279Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best ways to improve my general knowledge for exam like SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780940c817f0398fc66d8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-should-I-not-study-for-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Anbu Mathika Well, there are a lot of people who will give you an ’n’ number of tips on how to study for CGL. But, wait! There is also a list of things about what you should not study for CGL: Don’t keep reading random stuff from the ‘Lucent book’ for G.K. Focus on the syllabus.Don’t waste time reading the whole newspaper for current affairs. Stick to the editorial sections and the first 2 pages.Don’t have 10 books for a single subject. Have 1–3 books and be thorough with them.Don’t download 100 apps on your phone to study anything. Ditch the smartphone.Don’t go hard on those big fat books like “Quantum CAT” by Sarvesh Verma. Solving Level-1 and Level-2 questions is more than enough.Don’t watch a 1000 video tutorials on YouTube to understand the basics. DON’T WASTE TIME!For tier-1, don’t ignore reasoninContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:48:52.458Z"),
    "question" : "What should I not study for the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780bf0c817f0398fc6708"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-one-clear-the-SSC-CGL-by-practising-all-of-the-previous-years’-question-papers-only?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Tarashankar Bhattacharya",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:49:35.954Z"),
    "question" : "Can one clear the SSC CGL by practising all of the previous years’ question papers only? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603780e90c817f0398fc67e1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-SSC-CGL-2019-aspirants-doing-after-the-Tier-3-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Rajat Singla So let me go back to 22nd November. I gave my Tier-3 (I have already discussed the experience in a separate answer) in Chandigarh. I had planned to shift to a city near my hometown after the exam so as to continue the preparation for civil services. So I went to Patiala on the same day after Tier-3, looked for PGs and single rooms and finally got one. I shifted to the selected room on 27th. After that I thought to teach(earlier also I have taught for more than 2 years) some SSC subjects (preferably GS) so as to meet my daily expenses and for GS revision. Luckily I found one vacancy on 27th itself in a HelpGroup of the city on facebook. The vacancy was for a reasoning teacher in a reputed institute. I thought to give it a try. Eventually I landed up being a GS teacher (long story behind this Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:50:17.663Z"),
    "question" : "What are the SSC CGL 2019 aspirants doing after the Tier 3 exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781000c817f0398fc67f7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-many-marks-should-one-need-to-get-for-MEA-post-of-ssc-cgl?-",
    "answer" : "Gopal Anand Hello, SSC conducts CGL exam for various posts and one such prestigious post is Assistant Section Officer in Ministry of External Affairs. ASO is among the posts that has a high cutoff compared to other posts of CGL. It is a post with grade pay 4600 and other benefits including foreign posting. One aspires to be on that position and hence the cutoff is generally high for this post. Comparing the previous year cutoff, the final cutoff( general) in 2016 for ASO MEA was 558.75 out of 700. Hence, if you are giving the exam in future you need to plan accordingly. Tier 1 of cgl consists of 200 marks, tier 2 (Paper 1 + paper 2) consists of 400 marks, and tier 3 (descriptive) 100 marks. Depending on the difficulty of the exam you should score at least 20–25 marks above the cutoff (to be on a safer  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:50:40.670Z"),
    "question" : "How many marks should one need to get for MEA post of ssc cgl? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("603781140c817f0398fc68bf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-SSC-chsl-be-conducted-in-2021?-",
    "answer" : "After reading your question, it seems that you're also a SSC Aspirant like me or you're a last year college going student who is planning to prepare for upcoming SSC exams. Now coming to your question, As of now SSC CHSL 2019 Tier 1 exams is not completed due to Corona virus pandemic. It was scheduled between 16 to 27 March 2020 but due to Lockdown ssc has conducted only 3 days exam. The exam of remaining Students is scheduled to start on october 2020 if the situation comes under control, it can also be extended. Also as per the old exam calender SSC CHSL 2020 notification relase date is November 2020. As per the current scenario, SSC CHSL 2021 may be conducted between last quarter of 2021 and first quarter of 2022. Hope you all are doing well in your studies :) PS : It is my first detailed ans Continue Reading After reading your question, it seems that you're also a SSC Aspirant like me or you're a last year college going student who is planning to prepare for upcoming SSC exams. Now coming to your question, As of now SSC CHSL 2019 Tier 1 exams is not completed due to Corona virus pandemic. It was scheduled between 16 to 27 March 2020 but due to Lockdown ssc has conducted only 3 days exam. The exam of remaining Students is scheduled to start on october 2020 if the situation comes under control, it can also be extended. Also as per the old exam calender SSC CHSL 2020 notification relase date is November 2020. As per the current scenario, SSC CHSL 2021 may be conducted between last quarter of 2021 and first quarter of 2022. Hope you all are doing well in your studies :) PS : It is my first detailed ans Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-25T10:51:00.368Z"),
    "question" : "Will SSC chsl be conducted in 2021? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}